<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Code Orange Archives - Hugo&#039;s Notes</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/code-orange/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/tag/code-orange/</link>
	<description>Hugo&#039;s Notes: Design and other thoughts from a designer.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 12:28:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/cropped-favicon-32x32.webp</url>
	<title>Code Orange Archives - Hugo&#039;s Notes</title>
	<link>/tag/code-orange/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>What I learned as a designer from these album covers</title>
		<link>/what-i-learned-as-a-designer-from-these-album-covers/</link>
					<comments>/what-i-learned-as-a-designer-from-these-album-covers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hugo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 12:14:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Album cover design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Code Orange]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Color theory]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Compositon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daft Punk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Red Hot Chili Peppers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Soundgarden]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Black Keys]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Typography]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=133</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Music is great, no doubt about that, and in this article, I want to explore some of my favorite album covers and what I learned from them as a designer. I have such a huge love for music I can’t even describe it, it’s just such a huge part of who I am! So obviously [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/what-i-learned-as-a-designer-from-these-album-covers/">What I learned as a designer from these album covers</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Hugo&#039;s Notes</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Music is great, no doubt about that, and in this article, <strong>I want to explore some of my favorite album covers and what I learned from them as a designer.</strong> I have such a huge love for music I can’t even describe it, it’s just such a huge part of who I am! So obviously when looking for inspiration out there I always love to look at new and old album covers.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/oleg-ivanov-7x4ngEfelyE-unsplash-1024x683.jpg" alt="Photo of a person filliping through vinyls at a store" class="wp-image-134" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/oleg-ivanov-7x4ngEfelyE-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/oleg-ivanov-7x4ngEfelyE-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/oleg-ivanov-7x4ngEfelyE-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/oleg-ivanov-7x4ngEfelyE-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/oleg-ivanov-7x4ngEfelyE-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@olegivanovpht?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Oleg Ivanov</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/person-checking-the-file-7x4ngEfelyE?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Unsplash</a></p>



<p><strong>What kind of music do you listen to while you work? </strong>For me it’s always something kind of relaxing but with a good beat so it helps me to focus. </p>



<p>As I’m writing this I’m listening to <strong>Daft Punk</strong> albums because I’ve been having this huge nostalgia trip, and I’m such a huge fan of the robots! <strong>Please do leave your favorite albums in the comments below, I would love to find new music to listen to!</strong></p>



<p>Anyways, with this article I want to dive into some of my <strong>favorite albums,</strong> talking about their cover designs and how I’ve used them as a learning tool for stuff like composition, color combinations, layout, etc. </p>



<p><strong>There is a lot we can learn from our day-to-day activities</strong> and as designers it’s basically essential that you look at everything with an eagle eye. Sometimes I find myself analyzing a weird milk carton or something random and there’s a lot to take away from these little things. </p>



<p>So, take this article as a <strong>call for action,</strong> look at stuff around you with a designer approach and you will see what I’m talking about!</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">In a nutshell these will be the album covers I’m going to talk about:</h4>



<ul>
<li><strong>Daft Punk</strong> &#8211; Discovery</li>



<li><strong>Soundgarden </strong>&#8211; Badmotorfinger</li>



<li><strong>Code Orange</strong> &#8211; The Above</li>



<li><strong>The Black Keys</strong> &#8211; Brothers</li>



<li><strong>Red Hot Chili Peppers</strong> &#8211; By the Way</li>
</ul>



<p>Also, a quick note, if you have any albums, you would love me to talk about, please leave a comment or write me an email, always open to suggestions!</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Daft Punk &#8211; Discovery</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" width="592" height="600" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/R-2879-1236035472.jpg" alt="Discovery by Daft Punk album cover" class="wp-image-135" style="aspect-ratio:0.9866666666666667;width:750px;height:auto" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/R-2879-1236035472.jpg 592w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/R-2879-1236035472-296x300.jpg 296w" sizes="(max-width: 592px) 100vw, 592px" /></figure>



<p>Album Cover image from <a href="https://www.discogs.com/">Discogs</a></p>



<p>Released on <strong>March 12, 2001</strong> &#8211; Discovery is the second studio album by the iconic French duo<strong> Daft Punk.</strong> This album was a cornerstone for electronic music and a master class on sampling techniques. </p>



<p>It also had a movie released in 2003, serving as a visual companion for the album named <strong>“Interstella 5555: The 5tory of the 5ecret 5tar 5ystem”,</strong> this movie was animated by <strong>Toei Animation</strong>, and I would recommend you watch it and experience it.</p>



<p>To me this is <strong>one of my favorite albums of all time,</strong> it’s basically perfect and its album cover is incredibly iconic, I would even consider it a <strong>landmark</strong> of pop culture.</p>



<p>The previous album Homework also had such an interesting cover which like Discovery’s is a <strong>photograph!</strong> Yeah, I was also mind blown!</p>



<p>The Daft Punk logo which is also iconic, and the center piece of both albums was actually designed by <strong>Guy-Man</strong>, the gold robot. Although it may look 3d it actually isn’t this album cover was done using liquid metal by photographer <strong><a href="https://www.mitch.fr/">Mitch Feinberg.</a></strong></p>



<p>Unfortunately, I couldn’t really find a lot of information around about the exact process, but <strong>I sent an email to Mitch to try and figure it out.</strong> </p>



<p>If I learn anything new from him, <strong>I will write an article about it!</strong></p>



<p>There is a lot we can learn from this cover, but my <strong>main takeaway</strong> is that we should try and find ways to do our work more physically, nowadays we are bound to technology, and although it’s awesome that we have ways of doing stuff that we didn’t had 20 years ago sometimes <strong>being out there experimenting with materials and different processes of what we are used to, may translate in a very interesting result </strong>that we were not expecting.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Soundgarden &#8211; Badmotorfinger</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" width="600" height="600" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/R-2499366-1523173854-2423.jpg" alt="Badmotorfinger by Soundgarden Album Cover" class="wp-image-137" style="aspect-ratio:1;width:750px;height:auto" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/R-2499366-1523173854-2423.jpg 600w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/R-2499366-1523173854-2423-300x300.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/R-2499366-1523173854-2423-150x150.jpg 150w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></figure>



<p>Album Cover image from <a href="https://www.discogs.com/">Discogs</a></p>



<p>Badmotorfinger is such an iconic album, released on October 8, 1991, by <strong>Soundgarden</strong> it quickly became an historic part of the grunge movement.</p>



<p>What makes the cover of this album so cool is the <strong>typography and the color combinations</strong>. I absolutely love it and I think you and I can learn a lot from it. </p>



<p>Red, yellow and purple are three colors that don’t make much sense but when put together they just work.</p>



<p>The main takeaway is to<strong> experiment with color and overall composition of elements,</strong> sometimes we tend to get stuck with grids or formulas that we have learned, and we could experiment and get amazing results. </p>



<p><strong>Formulas are good but sometimes we need to explore beyond them.</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Code Orange – The above</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="599" height="546" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/R-28429588-1697995453-7695.jpg" alt="The Above by Code Orange Album Cover" class="wp-image-138" style="aspect-ratio:1.0970695970695972;width:750px;height:auto" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/R-28429588-1697995453-7695.jpg 599w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/R-28429588-1697995453-7695-300x273.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 599px) 100vw, 599px" /></figure>



<p>Album Cover image from <a href="https://www.discogs.com/">Discogs</a></p>



<p>First, let me say I love <strong>Code Orange,</strong> if you haven’t listened to their stuff check it out. I was a huge fan of their older album cover designs. </p>



<p><strong>Bold colors, bold typography it just worked.</strong></p>



<p>I think The Above was a nice <strong>improvement</strong> on their formula for album cover design and the overall vinyl set looks awesome.</p>



<p>I really think<strong> composition</strong> is a big takeaway from this cover, the focus on the image and the overall graphic treatment is also a very interesting point.</p>



<p>What I takeaway from this is that we sometimes avoid using simple compositions, but <strong>this album turns a very simple composition which is very effective and levels it up with the graphic treatmen</strong>t. So don’t be afraid of using effective more simple compositions, embrace white space and experiment with effects/digital treatment.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The Black Keys &#8211; Brothers</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="600" height="600" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/R-2284952-1626530490-7581.jpg" alt="Brothers by The Black Keys Album Cover" class="wp-image-139" style="aspect-ratio:1;width:750px;height:auto" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/R-2284952-1626530490-7581.jpg 600w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/R-2284952-1626530490-7581-300x300.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/R-2284952-1626530490-7581-150x150.jpg 150w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></figure>



<p>Album Cover image from <a href="https://www.discogs.com/">Discogs</a></p>



<p>Brothers is the sixth studio album of <strong>The Black Keys </strong>released on May 18, 2010. This album cover became an instant classic, red, black, white and Cooper Black – <strong>what more could we ask for!</strong></p>



<p>I really do think it’s perhaps one of the<strong> most iconic albums covers of the 2010s,</strong> alongside AM by <strong>Artic </strong>Monkeys. Albums that just embraced simplicity and showed that sometimes less is more.</p>



<p>If you must take any album here and use it as an example of what an iconic album cover can look like I would recommend Brothers. Again, the same points I previously mentioned apply here, composition, color, typography, embracing white space. <strong>Do I need to say more?</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Red Hot Chili Peppers – By the way</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="600" height="600" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/R-1162737-1197254678.jpg" alt="By the Way by The Red Hot Chili Peppers Album Cover" class="wp-image-140" style="aspect-ratio:1;width:750px;height:auto" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/R-1162737-1197254678.jpg 600w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/R-1162737-1197254678-300x300.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/R-1162737-1197254678-150x150.jpg 150w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></figure>



<p>Album Cover image from <a href="https://www.discogs.com/">Discogs</a></p>



<p>Arguably my favorite band, I just had to mention them. Their eighth studio album <strong>By the Way </strong>was released July 9, 2002.</p>



<p>I talked about breaking formulas before and experimentation, but I really do think the By the Way album cover is probably one of the best examples of this. <strong>It’s incredibly expressive and features a very interesting typography treatment too.</strong></p>



<p>If had to take any lesson from it, it would be the same that I took from Discovery, <strong>to experiment with materials, get away from the computer and try stuff out.</strong> I don’t really like to paint or draw but sometimes we need to get uncomfortable to create unique stuff.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">On a final note, the main takeaways here are to experiment with design elements, get uncomfortable, less is more, formulas are good and sometimes breaking them is also good.</h2>



<p>This is about it, I know this wasn’t very extensive, this was as I said in the beginning to just make the point that you should look at things differently and take lessons from them.</p>



<p>I hope you found this article useful, please if you have any suggestions leave a comment below, I will try to read and answer them all!</p>



<p>Also, you can read the previous <a href="/5-things-every-design-student-needs-to-hear/"><strong>article here!</strong></a></p>



<p>Thank you for reading, I hope you enjoyed!</p>
<p>The post <a href="/what-i-learned-as-a-designer-from-these-album-covers/">What I learned as a designer from these album covers</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Hugo&#039;s Notes</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/what-i-learned-as-a-designer-from-these-album-covers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- plugin=object-cache-pro client=phpredis metric#hits=571 metric#misses=17 metric#hit-ratio=97.1 metric#bytes=271976 metric#prefetches=0 metric#store-reads=44 metric#store-writes=3 metric#store-hits=56 metric#store-misses=11 metric#sql-queries=10 metric#ms-total=77.29 metric#ms-cache=6.13 metric#ms-cache-avg=0.1332 metric#ms-cache-ratio=7.9 -->
