<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>college Archives - Hugo&#039;s Notes</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/college/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/tag/college/</link>
	<description>Hugo&#039;s Notes: Design and other thoughts from a designer.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 11:14:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/cropped-favicon-32x32.webp</url>
	<title>college Archives - Hugo&#039;s Notes</title>
	<link>/tag/college/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>5 things every design student needs to hear</title>
		<link>/5-things-every-design-student-needs-to-hear/</link>
					<comments>/5-things-every-design-student-needs-to-hear/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hugo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 10:48:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[college]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[people]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=122</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As a recently graduated graphic designer, kick-starting my career, there are certain things that If I was starting all over again, I would tell myself, so here are 5 things that I believe every design student needs to hear. Photo by Unseen Studio on Unsplash Hello fellow readers, today I wanted to talk with those [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/5-things-every-design-student-needs-to-hear/">5 things every design student needs to hear</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Hugo&#039;s Notes</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As a <strong>recently graduated graphic designer</strong>, kick-starting my career, there are certain things that If I was starting all over again, I would tell myself, so here are <strong>5 things that I believe every design student needs to hear.</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/unseen-studio-s9CC2SKySJM-unsplash-1024x683.jpg" alt="Image of a person holding a pen related to the article name - 5 things that every design student needs to hear " class="wp-image-123" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/unseen-studio-s9CC2SKySJM-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/unseen-studio-s9CC2SKySJM-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/unseen-studio-s9CC2SKySJM-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/unseen-studio-s9CC2SKySJM-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/unseen-studio-s9CC2SKySJM-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@craftedbygc?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Unseen Studio</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/person-writing-on-brown-wooden-table-near-white-ceramic-mug-s9CC2SKySJM?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Unsplash</a></p>



<p>Hello fellow readers, today I wanted to talk with those of you that are <strong>currently in college or thinking of going to college and studying design</strong>. My studying journey was good, I was a fairly successful student, I didn’t exactly fail any classes, but <strong>there is always room for improvement.</strong> Although my learning chapter isn’t exactly done, as I intend to eventually get a master’s degree, I feel like I can share with you valuable information, so here it is, <strong>my top 5 things that you and every design student needs to hear.</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">1 – Understand what college for designers means and take the most out of it</h2>



<p>I’ve read so many articles in the past about college for designers and <strong>if it’s worth it or if it’s foolish</strong> to even go to college for design. In my opinion this is kind of a <strong>silly question.</strong> The reason being that it simply varies from person to person. <strong>I’ve met amazing designers who went to college and amazing designers who didn’t and were self-taught.</strong></p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">If you can afford it and are in this should I go or shouldn’t I go situation, I will always answer the same thing – go for it! </h4>



<p>If this is an <strong>area that you actually like,</strong> University is going to be awesome for you, mainly because you will spend countless hours<strong> with experts</strong> in their fields! That’s a lot of value. Also, in the increasingly saturated market of graphic designers, having a degree sometimes <strong>will influence</strong> a lot of recruiters to even consider you, if candidate A and B are equal in terms of portfolio, soft skills, etc… but one holds a degree and the other one doesn’t, it’s simply the <strong>deciding factor that’s going to take you out.</strong></p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">On the other hand, If you are being forced to go by your parents or If you just want to go to university studying design because you want to hold a degree – simply don’t go. </h4>



<p>Choose another option instead. I can’t really recommend you any specific course, but I guarantee you <strong>design isn’t the way,</strong> If I were in your shoes, I would just see <strong>what course</strong> translated into the job that pays the <strong>highest.</strong></p>



<p>If you are actually interested in going to university studying design because you have a passion for it, I want to help you understand <strong>what exactly you are getting out of it.</strong> As I previously mentioned professors that are experts in their fields is going to be the main advantage of taking a degree.</p>



<p>If you expect to learn software and stuff like that you are wrong, <strong>that’s going to be your homework</strong>. </p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">The main purpose of any design program in the world is to teach you the fundamentals and help you develop upon them. </h4>



<p>By the end you should expect to <strong>master the concepts</strong> you learned and how to <strong>apply them.</strong> Don’t expect classes about how to use illustrator 101, yes they exist but a lot of times they do not add any significant knowledge besides what you can see on youtube.</p>



<p>As a student I had colleagues in all the above-mentioned situations, but the main reason I became a standout student is because <strong>I understood the system and what it means to go to college for design.</strong> <strong>I needed to be able to form connections</strong> with those that were teaching me so that I could get the <strong>most value </strong>out of it. Of course, this means that you need to be an <strong>exemplary class member,</strong> don’t miss class, deliver work on time, don’t take shortcuts and <strong>be serious.</strong></p>



<p>The number of students I’ve met who wasted years of their lives and finished courses <strong>knowing nothing</strong> is genuinely <strong>hard to believe. </strong>All because they missed classes, went partying, had zero sense of responsibility and were genuinely uninterested.</p>



<p><strong>You can live your life the way you want </strong>and although I was one of top students of my class while I had two jobs and didn’t even complain <strong>I’m not saying you need to do the same.</strong> Just make sure you are happy with the options you make <strong>now and later.</strong> Everything you do eventually comes around, <strong>it’s a cycle.</strong></p>



<p>The message that I want to share with you in this point is simple, <strong>think about your decisions</strong> and how it affects you.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">2 – Be curious, make questions, solve problems and create new ones</h2>



<p>The first question that really got me extremely curious in university was <strong>“What is design?&#8221;</strong>, I was so speechless and surprised with the fact that <strong>I couldn’t find the words to explain what design is,</strong> to me it was something around the lines of making logos, talking with clients, making magazines, books and other stuff. The answer that our teacher gave us was a simple one, but it blew my mind <strong>“design is solving problems”.</strong></p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Why am I reminiscing on this? Because that moment was important to me, I learned for the first-time what design was all about and I was curious to know more.</h4>



<p>The first tip that I want to give you in this second point is a simple one –<strong> be curious.</strong> Curiosity fuels creativity, make questions, foolish questions, don’t be afraid of being curious and asking around, this is what takes your learning from good to great. I<strong>nvolving yourself is an important step,</strong> talent without curiosity, without questions is just wasted potential. I’ve met average students that became great designers because they were curious and made questions. <strong>Don’t be afraid!</strong></p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">At university you will solve problems, a lot of them, these are going to be given to you by your teachers, but are you going to be that person that sticks with just the program? </h4>



<p>University is about <strong>exploration</strong> and figuring stuff out and that ties up with curiosity, so <strong>be curious, solve problems,</strong> but also and perhaps most importantly<strong> create new problems</strong> that you can solve by yourself.</p>



<p>This isn’t as difficult as it sounds, to me I did this by <strong>finding competitions</strong> that I could be a part of, by <strong>kickstarting certain projects </strong>or by <strong>learning new software or techniques</strong> that weren’t taught to me. </p>



<p>I did all of this after-school stuff whilst having <strong>two jobs,</strong> so you do not have any possible excuse besides being lazy. <strong>Get up, do it, now!</strong></p>



<p>In an increasingly saturated market where everyone who uses canva thinks they are designers <strong>it’s difficult to stand out</strong> so if you pickup up things like web development, 3d, motion design, video editing, etc… <strong>in your free time,</strong> when you start searching for a job <strong>a door will eventually more easily open</strong> for you. I know this because<strong> only a month or two after finishing my degree</strong> I already was doing an internship, perhaps it wasn’t what I wanted to initially do, but a door was open and that’s my point.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">3 – Always carry a usb drive</h2>



<p>Okay, this is kind of just me being a little mad at some of my fellow university colleagues, but for god sakes <strong>buy a usb drive!</strong> They are cheap nowadays and you are going to need them to carry files around for a variety of purposes, even if it is to just figure out minimum dimensions for a logo. <strong>Don’t be that person that doesn’t have a usb drive </strong>or an external hard drive and just ask if someone has it, it’s foolish!</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">In my opinion if you carry around a laptop with good storage a smaller usb drive is all you need, if you use university computers then I recommend you get an external hard drive. </h4>



<p>It really <strong>depends on your use case,</strong> but always have backups of your projects. <strong>I’m serious,</strong> it’s unprofessional and very realistic the number of times I listened to someone say, <strong>“I just lost all of my work for X project because my pc broke”</strong>, don’t be like this you have zero excuse when hard drives exist, and cloud storage exist.</p>



<p>Also, to make it simple for you <strong>here are some suggestions at different price points,</strong> all the links will be <strong>affiliated </strong>– always <strong>do your own research on stuff you buy,</strong> don’t simply take mine or others recommendations as the rule.</p>



<p><strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Kingston-DataTraveler-Exodia-128GB-DTX/dp/B08JD4TBM3/ref=sr_1_4?crid=3TGO88RNB8TE1&amp;keywords=usb%252Bkingston&amp;qid=1697706811&amp;sprefix=usb%252Bkingston%252Caps%252C190&amp;sr=8-4&amp;th=1&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=a291591cfdb9ed5aa0039df482045bcd&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325">Kingston DataTraveler Exodia</a></strong> – I have a few of these, I don’t know if it’s an exclusive deal to Portugal, but I bought mine in a kit that came with two, so do research on that. <strong>They are really good for the money</strong> I use them almost every day, no complaints, Kingston hit me up, I like your products.</p>



<p><strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08GTYFC37/ref=twister_B0C6YZGJFH?_encoding=UTF8&amp;th=1&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=5b949e90b0315a238043d629b5d7c020&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325">SanDisk Portable SSD</a></strong> – A few options here in terms of what storage you get, see what fits your budget, but 2TB usb 3.2 up to 1050MB/s at $119.99 feels like a decent deal to me.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">4 – Find time to live life</h2>



<p>In a period of time that’s going to be tense,<strong> find the time to live your life.</strong> This probably would be one of the biggest tips I would give to myself looking back. </p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">I always have a very serious relationship with my work and sometimes I forget that I must live my life. </h4>



<p>For the years I was in college I had basically <strong>no personal time</strong> and this affected my <strong>mental health,</strong> but now as an older individual I have learned that you must have personal time and I really do value my moments of relaxation a lot. So, if you are starting college, <strong>work hard, but find time to chill a little,</strong> watch a movie, read a book, paint, take care of plants, work out, I don’t know what fits your mood. </p>



<p>I will say this, in the minuscule time I had for myself <strong>I always worked out </strong>because it kept my mental health in check, so if you don’t currently do any form of exercise <strong>that’s my recommendation.</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">5 – If you don’t fit in with everybody else, you’re probably in the right track</h2>



<p>There is such a need that people in general have to fit in that <strong>I personally don’t get.</strong> People are quick to try and form groups. Perhaps this is something more personal, but I never quite <strong>liked the idea of forming a group and putting people </strong>aside, even worse is when people retroactively choose to be jerks about it.</p>



<p>I always tried to be nice and helpful to others and to connect with everyone and be an open book, but these types of things <strong>make me want to just be on my shell. </strong>This is perhaps why I have very few friends and even fewer best friends.</p>



<p>On my university years I never quite fitted in with my classmates and I honestly think most of them didn’t really like me a lot, but I was not searching for their approval &#8211; so I kind of get them! I just did my own thing and if someone wanted help or to talk, I didn’t have a problem with that, I just didn’t offer shortcuts, that was my rule.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">I’m telling you this not because I want your compassion but because I want to tell you something that I never see people telling each other. You don’t need a group, you can be alone and find success, if you don’t like people’s attitudes or behaviors don’t join them. Let them be the ones to find you.</h4>



<p>On another note, people can and will be jerks there is simply no way of avoiding it, even I am not a hero, and I was a jerk a few times. It’s life, not everyone is perfect, that’s what makes us human. </p>



<p>Although there are <strong>those who apologize and those who don’t.</strong> The takeaway of this point is that you can be yourself, <strong>you don’t need others approvals, you don’t need to join people that you don’t want to be around and you definitely don’t need to agree with something you do not believe.</strong> So please fellow readers be aware of others humans!</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">On a final note, and because depression is a real thing among students, please feel free to contact me if you need someone to not judge you and just talk.</h2>



<p>I hope these five tips help you on your journey. <strong>If you have tips</strong> for others or any opinion about this article <strong>please do leave a comment bellow!</strong> I will try to read and answer them all!</p>



<p>If you are new to the blog, I recommend reading this <a href="/my-blogging-story-why-i-started-and-how-you-can-start-right-now/"><strong>article!</strong></a></p>



<p>Also, if you want more content, please do consider checking out my social media platforms!</p>



<p>Thank you for reading, I hope you enjoyed!</p>
<p>The post <a href="/5-things-every-design-student-needs-to-hear/">5 things every design student needs to hear</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Hugo&#039;s Notes</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/5-things-every-design-student-needs-to-hear/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- plugin=object-cache-pro client=phpredis metric#hits=492 metric#misses=17 metric#hit-ratio=96.7 metric#bytes=247192 metric#prefetches=0 metric#store-reads=43 metric#store-writes=3 metric#store-hits=36 metric#store-misses=11 metric#sql-queries=10 metric#ms-total=73.76 metric#ms-cache=5.82 metric#ms-cache-avg=0.1294 metric#ms-cache-ratio=7.9 -->
