<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>blender Archives - Hugo&#039;s Notes</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/blender/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/tag/blender/</link>
	<description>Hugo&#039;s Notes: Design and other thoughts from a designer.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 17:18:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/cropped-favicon-32x32.webp</url>
	<title>blender Archives - Hugo&#039;s Notes</title>
	<link>/tag/blender/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>The key skill every designer needs to learn in 2024</title>
		<link>/the-key-skill-every-designer-needs-to-learn-in-2024/</link>
					<comments>/the-key-skill-every-designer-needs-to-learn-in-2024/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hugo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 17:04:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[augmented reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blender]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[people]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[skill]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=218</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In a world of constant change, the design industry is continuously evolving, with these changes we must also evolve so in this article I will talk about the key skill every designer needs to learn in 2024. Photo by Jason Goodman on Unsplash In my last article, I talked about my vision for the future [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/the-key-skill-every-designer-needs-to-learn-in-2024/">The key skill every designer needs to learn in 2024</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Hugo&#039;s Notes</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In a world of constant change, <strong>the design industry is continuously evolving</strong>, with these changes <strong>we must also evolve </strong>so in this article I will talk about the <strong>key skill every designer needs to learn in 2024.</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/jason-goodman-Oalh2MojUuk-unsplash-1024x683.jpg" alt="Image of a group of designers working on a project" class="wp-image-220" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/jason-goodman-Oalh2MojUuk-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/jason-goodman-Oalh2MojUuk-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/jason-goodman-Oalh2MojUuk-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/jason-goodman-Oalh2MojUuk-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/jason-goodman-Oalh2MojUuk-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@jasongoodman_youxventures?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Jason Goodman</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/woman-placing-sticky-notes-on-wall-Oalh2MojUuk?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Unsplash</a></p>



<p><a href="/what-does-the-future-of-design-look-like/"><strong>In my last article,</strong></a> I talked about my vision for the future of design and <strong>how we are very close to massive changes in the industry.</strong> Out of the several things I wrapped my head around one stood out to me the most – <strong>the future is motion.</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Static is out, motion is in</h2>



<p>Over the last few years motion design undoubtedly has taken the world by storm, if we take a close look at the last 10 years, <strong>motion design has steadily, alongside UI/UX, become an increasingly important area of design.</strong></p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">From TV to smartphones to ads on the street, everything nowadays is slowly becoming less static. The new possibilities in terms of technology have been increasing the types of supports we can use motion in, to me motion will be a part of every designer’s skillset in a few years.</h4>



<p>In many ways,<strong> when we look at the world that surrounds us,</strong> more and more, <strong>we see static formats slowly disappearing. </strong>An example of this in Portugal recently has been the introduction of digital Mupis on bus stops.</p>



<p>What was once a place for a <strong>completely static poster</strong> is now basically a <strong>digital playground for motion design.</strong> This is just an example, but many more places are suffering these types of changes, from the introduction of the e-book to televisions replacing static posters in movie theaters, e<strong>verything is changing to become less static.</strong></p>



<p><strong>I challenge you to take a look around you</strong> and identify these small details in our day-to-day activities, you will most likely see different examples than the one I previously mentioned, <strong>you just need to keep your eyes wide open.</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The evolution of software and hardware</h2>



<p>Like the Mupis I was talking about technology in general has improved dramatically over the years. <strong>We are lucky to be a part of one of the most interesting generations ever.</strong></p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">If you took a look at the world 25 years ago it was a vastly different place in terms of technology, forget your high res Tv, your laptop, your smartphone, your high-speed internet connection and bring back the CRTs, the Nokia phones, the dial-up internet and all the other marvels of late 90s technology.</h4>



<p>My point is – <strong>there has been a dramatic change in technology in a very short time frame.</strong> Although nowadays its starting to slow down a bit <strong>the evolution of technology is as obvious as my name being Hugo.</strong></p>



<p>Over the last few years, a lot of these technological revolutions have turned out to be related to <strong>finding new ways of implementing screens into your life.</strong> Making them <strong>cheaper and easier to make</strong> has only translated into the <strong>propagation of screens to almost everything we use</strong> that involves some type of technology.</p>



<p>In the future Motion Design will be important as we move to an <strong>era of new supports</strong> like augmented and virtual reality, but also as we move to an era of <strong>full/increasing replacement of static media.</strong></p>



<p><strong>The world of advertising and media is already changing by the clock so we must evolve and adapt with the times. </strong>Accepting that motion is going to be a big part of your life is the first step.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The new age of social media</h2>



<p>Remember good old <strong>MSN,</strong> no? What about <strong>Hi5?</strong> Hey, do you even remember<strong> Facebook?</strong></p>



<p>It’s very strange how social media platforms have been changing over the years, but one thing that isn’t strange to me is <strong>how every single one of them started to get some type of way of showing you videos</strong>.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Instagram, X (rip Twitter), Facebook, TikTok, and others have one thing in common besides basically copying each other – the possibility of sharing videos.</h4>



<p>This fact <strong>single-handedly makes Motion Design even more important.</strong> If you want to stand out you can’t be static.</p>



<p>As we move into the future, platforms focused on video sharing seem to be slowly taking over,<strong> Motion Design in my eyes will play an essential role in the future of social media.</strong> Every brand, every product, everything really <strong>will seek to have motion attached to it.</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Animation has never been more accessible</h2>



<p>On one side we have an <strong>ever-expanding industry</strong> only increasing in the future, on the other, <strong>we have software that has become easier to use.</strong> We don’t need the mess that was Flash animation, nowadays we have <strong>After-effects,</strong> several 3d and 2d animation software, and of course the incredible <a href="http://blender.org/"><strong>Blender.</strong></a></p>



<p>Thanks to <strong>YouTube, platforms like Skillshare, and School of Motion</strong> learning Motion Design has never been <strong>cheaper and more accessible.</strong></p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">I have to say I really do like Blender, the community is incredible, and personally speaking, I see it taking over the industry standard Cinema 4D in the near future.</h4>



<p>The fact that a piece of software is so loved and remains free shows the type of people behind <strong>Blender </strong>and why it is<strong> the tool to learn </strong>if you are looking to learn 3D and animation.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="576" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/untitled-1024x576.png" alt="3d image of a credit card mockup" class="wp-image-219" style="width:750px;height:auto" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/untitled-1024x576.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/untitled-300x169.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/untitled-768x432.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/untitled-1536x864.png 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/untitled.png 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Cool Credit Card Mockup I made in Blender (I still have to figure out the whole animation thing)</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Why is motion design a key skill that every designer needs to learn in 2024?</h2>



<p>Last but not least on my to-talk list is the answer to the starting question of this article. <strong>It’s a key skill every designer should learn because motion design has never been easier and more important in our industry.</strong></p>



<p>Recently award-winning agencies such as <a href="http://studiodumbar.com/"><strong>Studio Dumbar</strong></a> and <a href="http://wolffolins.com/"><strong>Wolff Olins</strong></a> have been releasing successful project after successful project. The <strong>one key ingredient </strong>almost every project they share has in common is <strong>motion.</strong></p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">If you look at these agencies motion stands almost as a core component in every single project and its no coincidence that they have become two of the most popular agencies in the world.</h4>



<p>So, I suggest you <em>look </em><strong>around you, accept motion and work on your skillset, </strong>because believe me this will become the future.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">On a final note, here are a few suggestions if you want to get started with motion design</h2>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/@DerekElliott"><strong>Derek Elliot</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.schoolofmotion.com/"><strong>School of Motion</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/@blenderguru"><strong>Blender Guru</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/@BenMarriott"><strong>Ben Marriott</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/@SonduckFilm"><strong>SounduckFilm</strong></a></li>
</ul>



<p>Although on the shorter side, <strong>I do hope this article has at least made you interested in motion, </strong>don’t forget to leave a comment below I’m interested to read your opinions.</p>



<p>Think different. Make difference.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/the-key-skill-every-designer-needs-to-learn-in-2024/">The key skill every designer needs to learn in 2024</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Hugo&#039;s Notes</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/the-key-skill-every-designer-needs-to-learn-in-2024/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- plugin=object-cache-pro client=phpredis metric#hits=512 metric#misses=17 metric#hit-ratio=96.8 metric#bytes=245720 metric#prefetches=0 metric#store-reads=44 metric#store-writes=3 metric#store-hits=42 metric#store-misses=11 metric#sql-queries=10 metric#ms-total=76.39 metric#ms-cache=5.95 metric#ms-cache-avg=0.1293 metric#ms-cache-ratio=7.8 -->
