<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>design Archives - Hugo&#039;s Notes</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/design/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/tag/design/</link>
	<description>Hugo&#039;s Notes: Design and other thoughts from a designer.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 16:38:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/cropped-favicon-32x32.webp</url>
	<title>design Archives - Hugo&#039;s Notes</title>
	<link>/tag/design/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>MX Keys S Combo review – is it worth the hype?</title>
		<link>/mx-keys-s-combo-review-is-it-worth-the-hype/</link>
					<comments>/mx-keys-s-combo-review-is-it-worth-the-hype/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hugo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 16:38:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Typography]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=222</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I needed a new keyboard and mouse so I bought the “holy grail” of keyboard and mouse combos, in this review you will find out if the MX Keys S Combo is worth the hype and praise it gets or if you should avoid it. Photo by Marios Gkortsilas on Unsplash Hello designers, in one [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/mx-keys-s-combo-review-is-it-worth-the-hype/">MX Keys S Combo review – is it worth the hype?</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Hugo&#039;s Notes</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>I needed a new keyboard and mouse so I bought the “holy grail” of keyboard and mouse combos, in this review you will find out if the<strong> MX Keys S Combo </strong>is worth the hype and praise it gets or if you should avoid it.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1024" height="576" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/marios-gkortsilas-JCeQHpTpU24-unsplash-1024x576.png" alt="MX Keys S Combo " class="wp-image-225" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/marios-gkortsilas-JCeQHpTpU24-unsplash-1024x576.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/marios-gkortsilas-JCeQHpTpU24-unsplash-300x169.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/marios-gkortsilas-JCeQHpTpU24-unsplash-768x432.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/marios-gkortsilas-JCeQHpTpU24-unsplash-1536x864.png 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/marios-gkortsilas-JCeQHpTpU24-unsplash-2048x1152.png 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@mr_mgk?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Marios Gkortsilas</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/a-computer-mouse-and-keyboard-on-a-desk-JCeQHpTpU24?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Unsplash</a></p>



<p>Hello designers, in one of my recent articles I talked about tools <a href="/5-must-have-items-every-designer-needs-in-their-toolkit/"><strong>that every designer needs,</strong></a> I wrote in that post that I had recently bought the <strong>MX Keys S Combo</strong> and that soon I would be reviewing it. This is that review.</p>



<p>Before we start I wanted to tell you a few things, first <strong>I’m not in any way or shape sponsored by Logitech</strong> (I wish I was), second if there is a link to the product it&#8217;s going to be <strong>non-affiliated,</strong> thirdly I see a lot of articles like this in which people say that they are not biased, <strong>I’m human and I like Logitech so obviously although I’m going to try to write an unbiased review there are always small bias</strong> we cannot go around – do your own research before buying stuff.</p>



<p>On another note, let me also say that I’m going to be brutally honest,<strong> I will not sugar coat anything for you,</strong> whatever I like I like, whatever I hate I hate, period.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">I’m a Logitech fanboy</h2>



<p>I wanted to start this review by stating what I had previously mentioned, I really like Logitech. <strong>I have been using their products for years,</strong> from their entry-level products like the <strong>G203 Prodigy</strong> to their more expensive items like the<strong> MX Master 3.</strong></p>



<p>Throughout the years their product selection has stood against my abuse, which to be fair isn’t much as I’m very careful with my stuff. The most abuse any of their products saw was my MX Master 3 being thrown around in a case inside my backpack when I went to university and now my internship.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">By mentioning this I hope you understand where my slight bias may come from, I’ve been for the most part a happy customer throughout their whole lineup.</h4>



<p>Their products are in general <strong>high quality, fairly priced, and resistant</strong> – which is basically what I’m ideally looking for.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Why did I buy this combo?</h2>



<p>The main reason I decided to buy this combo is because I wanted to use my MX Master 3 at my internship and retire my 6-year-old K120 keyboard (which I’m also using at work right now).</p>



<p>This specific case put me in a very peculiar situation in which I needed to buy a new keyboard and mouse. I thought about buying a mechanical keyboard and another MX Master 3 since <strong>the experience I had with was so positive,</strong> but as I was endlessly scrolling through product pages, <strong>I ended up finding the MX Keys S Combo on Logitech’s website.</strong></p>



<p>Like many of you, <strong>the amount of hype and positive things I heard or read regarding the MX Keys </strong>was so large I thought <strong>“Wait, incredible mouse, incredible keyboard plus a wrist rest for this price? Take my money!”.</strong></p>



<p>On another note, I thought as a tech enthusiast it would be fun to review this for you,<strong> would the combo be as good as it seemed?</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The lackluster ordering process</h2>



<p>Here I am ordering my combo, Logitech’s official website looked cool, I paid with 0 problems. Got my order made, and now I only needed to receive it.</p>



<p>On Logitech’s European store they claim the delivery takes around <strong>2-3 days,</strong> mine took basically <strong>4 weeks.</strong> Between numerous tickets, they told me they had a<strong> huge number of orders</strong> which in all fairness I see as a Christmas buildup issue more than anything else.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Throughout the 4 weeks, I contacted Logitech’s customer support frequently through the chat-bot on their website, and although it took an eternity to get my order in which they sent me a free mousepad first, and later the combo it eventually came.</h4>



<p>For the most part, I have to be mad at Logitech for the delivery of my order to take so long, but on the other hand, <strong>their customer support was truly refreshing.</strong> They were always very nice to me making sure I got detailed information on why my order hadn’t been delivered.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">A quick cost breakdown</h2>



<p>At this specific point, I wanted to do a quick breakdown of how much I paid for the product. In total, I paid <strong>197.10€.</strong> This included the combo <strong>(Keyboard, Mouse, and Wrist Rest)</strong> plus a free studio series desk mat.</p>



<p>I believe this combo offers a lot of value and is in general a good product for those of you who like me need a keyboard and mouse.</p>



<p>Usually, <strong>you will find discount codes online,</strong> I found one that gave me a little bit of a discount, so stay alert for that as well. Besides this the <strong>bonus desk mat</strong> was a nice addition to the bundle although personally, <strong>I don’t find it that amazing, it’s a very basic desk mat, </strong>slightly on the smaller side but perfect for my use case – to have a desk mat at work and one at home.</p>



<p>If you are curious I use <a href="https://www.corsair.com/us/en/p/mousepads/ch-9413641-ww/mm300-pro-premium-spill-proof-cloth-gaming-mouse-pad-extended-ch-9413641-ww"><strong>this corsair deskmat on my home setup,</strong></a> which I also want to share with you on a separate article.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The good points</h2>



<p>Let’s start with the actual product review, first, <strong>the combo offers in my view a lot of value for the price that I paid.</strong> It seems to me that Logitech has a really good price/performance ratio.</p>



<p>The <strong>MX3S Mouse</strong> is a nice evolution to the standard <strong>MX3, </strong>most of the design and features remain the same with an <strong>improved sensor.</strong> Has a 3+ year user of the standard MX3 I found the MX3S a nice evolution, it features <strong>quieter button clicks</strong> which I personally really enjoy, and an improved sensor with a <strong>higher dpi number,</strong> it also uses the <strong>newer bolt 3 receiver.</strong></p>



<p>Like the MX3 the 3S features an <strong>incredibly designed scroll wheel </strong>that allows you to change between infinite scrolling and standard scrolling, it’s also the best scroll wheel I’ve ever used on any mouse ever.</p>



<p>Like the keyboard, it features a<strong> plethora of customization options through the Logi Options + software, </strong>allowing you to customize your experience. Personally, I don’t really use half of the customization options you have but I see the value in it, I believe designers will find it useful for their workflow.</p>



<p>In my use case, <strong>the feature I find the most valuable is the scroll wheel on the top and the one on the side,</strong> allowing me to do stuff like changing volume, infinite scrolling through webpages/ documents and controlling the timeline on video editing/animation projects. <strong>The improved dpi range is also really good for me </strong>as I really enjoy using a higher dpi.</p>



<p>The keyboard is very interesting to me,<strong> I really like the slim profile and the low noise it produces when typing,</strong> and features like the automatic background light are cool as well. The build construction is in general <strong>high quality with a mostly metal construction.</strong> Like the mouse, it features an extensive list of customization possibilities which is honestly perfect for those of you who use a lot of key binds. The typing experience is relatively nice with the wrist rest offering added comfort, a fixed keyboard inclination that is perfect, and keys that are designed for your fingers.</p>



<p>From the past weeks utilizing the MX Keys S, I’ve got to say, <strong>I really enjoyed the typing experience and if you game it will be good for you as well,</strong> from my time playing Tetris and other games with this keyboard it proved more than capable.</p>



<p>The keyboard also features multiple text on the ctrl/command keys for example as <strong>it’s designed for both Apple and PC.</strong></p>



<p>Last but not least I really liked the fact <strong>I could connect both the keyboard and mouse to the same receiver, </strong>well done and thought out Logitech!</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The not-so-good points</h2>



<p>I’m not going to sugarcoat it in any way or form, I don’t like some things about this combo. First, <strong>I really don’t like the fact both the keyboard and mouse don’t hold any type of internal memory,</strong> to me this is the biggest issue. If you want a certain dpi number, for example, you have to have Logi Options + installed all the time on your device. In products this expensive it’s a<strong> major design flaw.</strong></p>



<p>The keyboard has a very nice construction except for the keys,<strong> they feel very different from the rest of the product.</strong> Honestly, they disappointed me, I was expecting incredible keys but instead, they are mediocre, they feel like low-quality plastic. </p>



<p>Although useful in some scenarios and decent I feel like the <strong>top material on the wrist rest could be better, </strong>it doesn’t make me mad but it definitely feels slightly worse than the rest of the package.</p>



<p>So, the package comes with a usb-c mouse and a usb-c keyboard, both wireless, awesome! What’s the problem? <strong>It only includes a single usb-c cable for charging.</strong> Come on Logitech. The cable itself feels low quality and slightly thin for my liking.</p>



<p>Last but not least <strong>Logi options +</strong> is good but could be better, the fact it always has to be installed is a problem and I found some scenarios throughout the years in which it crashed on me (very rare). I really do like it compared to the rest of the industry, but again, could be better.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">On a final note, I consider this combo to be worth your time but I don’t believe it fits the hype it gets</h2>



<p>This combo has so much built-up hype, specifically the keyboard, which I believe is not that amazing. In general, <strong>you will get a really good product and personally, I’m really happy</strong> but take into consideration the details I’ve given you on these smaller issues. I really liked Logitech’s support and I would recommend you to get their combo <a href="https://www.logitech.com/en-eu/products/combos/mx-keys-s-combo.html"><strong>through their website.</strong></a></p>



<p>You can read my last post<strong> <a href="/the-key-skill-every-designer-needs-to-learn-in-2024/">here.</a></strong> If you own or eventually acquire this keyboard leave a comment below. I’m interested to see what you think!</p>



<p>That’s all folks, have a nice one.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/mx-keys-s-combo-review-is-it-worth-the-hype/">MX Keys S Combo review – is it worth the hype?</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Hugo&#039;s Notes</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/mx-keys-s-combo-review-is-it-worth-the-hype/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The key skill every designer needs to learn in 2024</title>
		<link>/the-key-skill-every-designer-needs-to-learn-in-2024/</link>
					<comments>/the-key-skill-every-designer-needs-to-learn-in-2024/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hugo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 17:04:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[augmented reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blender]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[people]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[skill]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=218</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In a world of constant change, the design industry is continuously evolving, with these changes we must also evolve so in this article I will talk about the key skill every designer needs to learn in 2024. Photo by Jason Goodman on Unsplash In my last article, I talked about my vision for the future [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/the-key-skill-every-designer-needs-to-learn-in-2024/">The key skill every designer needs to learn in 2024</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Hugo&#039;s Notes</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In a world of constant change, <strong>the design industry is continuously evolving</strong>, with these changes <strong>we must also evolve </strong>so in this article I will talk about the <strong>key skill every designer needs to learn in 2024.</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/jason-goodman-Oalh2MojUuk-unsplash-1024x683.jpg" alt="Image of a group of designers working on a project" class="wp-image-220" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/jason-goodman-Oalh2MojUuk-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/jason-goodman-Oalh2MojUuk-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/jason-goodman-Oalh2MojUuk-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/jason-goodman-Oalh2MojUuk-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/jason-goodman-Oalh2MojUuk-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@jasongoodman_youxventures?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Jason Goodman</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/woman-placing-sticky-notes-on-wall-Oalh2MojUuk?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Unsplash</a></p>



<p><a href="/what-does-the-future-of-design-look-like/"><strong>In my last article,</strong></a> I talked about my vision for the future of design and <strong>how we are very close to massive changes in the industry.</strong> Out of the several things I wrapped my head around one stood out to me the most – <strong>the future is motion.</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Static is out, motion is in</h2>



<p>Over the last few years motion design undoubtedly has taken the world by storm, if we take a close look at the last 10 years, <strong>motion design has steadily, alongside UI/UX, become an increasingly important area of design.</strong></p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">From TV to smartphones to ads on the street, everything nowadays is slowly becoming less static. The new possibilities in terms of technology have been increasing the types of supports we can use motion in, to me motion will be a part of every designer’s skillset in a few years.</h4>



<p>In many ways,<strong> when we look at the world that surrounds us,</strong> more and more, <strong>we see static formats slowly disappearing. </strong>An example of this in Portugal recently has been the introduction of digital Mupis on bus stops.</p>



<p>What was once a place for a <strong>completely static poster</strong> is now basically a <strong>digital playground for motion design.</strong> This is just an example, but many more places are suffering these types of changes, from the introduction of the e-book to televisions replacing static posters in movie theaters, e<strong>verything is changing to become less static.</strong></p>



<p><strong>I challenge you to take a look around you</strong> and identify these small details in our day-to-day activities, you will most likely see different examples than the one I previously mentioned, <strong>you just need to keep your eyes wide open.</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The evolution of software and hardware</h2>



<p>Like the Mupis I was talking about technology in general has improved dramatically over the years. <strong>We are lucky to be a part of one of the most interesting generations ever.</strong></p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">If you took a look at the world 25 years ago it was a vastly different place in terms of technology, forget your high res Tv, your laptop, your smartphone, your high-speed internet connection and bring back the CRTs, the Nokia phones, the dial-up internet and all the other marvels of late 90s technology.</h4>



<p>My point is – <strong>there has been a dramatic change in technology in a very short time frame.</strong> Although nowadays its starting to slow down a bit <strong>the evolution of technology is as obvious as my name being Hugo.</strong></p>



<p>Over the last few years, a lot of these technological revolutions have turned out to be related to <strong>finding new ways of implementing screens into your life.</strong> Making them <strong>cheaper and easier to make</strong> has only translated into the <strong>propagation of screens to almost everything we use</strong> that involves some type of technology.</p>



<p>In the future Motion Design will be important as we move to an <strong>era of new supports</strong> like augmented and virtual reality, but also as we move to an era of <strong>full/increasing replacement of static media.</strong></p>



<p><strong>The world of advertising and media is already changing by the clock so we must evolve and adapt with the times. </strong>Accepting that motion is going to be a big part of your life is the first step.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The new age of social media</h2>



<p>Remember good old <strong>MSN,</strong> no? What about <strong>Hi5?</strong> Hey, do you even remember<strong> Facebook?</strong></p>



<p>It’s very strange how social media platforms have been changing over the years, but one thing that isn’t strange to me is <strong>how every single one of them started to get some type of way of showing you videos</strong>.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Instagram, X (rip Twitter), Facebook, TikTok, and others have one thing in common besides basically copying each other – the possibility of sharing videos.</h4>



<p>This fact <strong>single-handedly makes Motion Design even more important.</strong> If you want to stand out you can’t be static.</p>



<p>As we move into the future, platforms focused on video sharing seem to be slowly taking over,<strong> Motion Design in my eyes will play an essential role in the future of social media.</strong> Every brand, every product, everything really <strong>will seek to have motion attached to it.</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Animation has never been more accessible</h2>



<p>On one side we have an <strong>ever-expanding industry</strong> only increasing in the future, on the other, <strong>we have software that has become easier to use.</strong> We don’t need the mess that was Flash animation, nowadays we have <strong>After-effects,</strong> several 3d and 2d animation software, and of course the incredible <a href="http://blender.org/"><strong>Blender.</strong></a></p>



<p>Thanks to <strong>YouTube, platforms like Skillshare, and School of Motion</strong> learning Motion Design has never been <strong>cheaper and more accessible.</strong></p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">I have to say I really do like Blender, the community is incredible, and personally speaking, I see it taking over the industry standard Cinema 4D in the near future.</h4>



<p>The fact that a piece of software is so loved and remains free shows the type of people behind <strong>Blender </strong>and why it is<strong> the tool to learn </strong>if you are looking to learn 3D and animation.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="576" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/untitled-1024x576.png" alt="3d image of a credit card mockup" class="wp-image-219" style="width:750px;height:auto" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/untitled-1024x576.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/untitled-300x169.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/untitled-768x432.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/untitled-1536x864.png 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/untitled.png 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Cool Credit Card Mockup I made in Blender (I still have to figure out the whole animation thing)</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Why is motion design a key skill that every designer needs to learn in 2024?</h2>



<p>Last but not least on my to-talk list is the answer to the starting question of this article. <strong>It’s a key skill every designer should learn because motion design has never been easier and more important in our industry.</strong></p>



<p>Recently award-winning agencies such as <a href="http://studiodumbar.com/"><strong>Studio Dumbar</strong></a> and <a href="http://wolffolins.com/"><strong>Wolff Olins</strong></a> have been releasing successful project after successful project. The <strong>one key ingredient </strong>almost every project they share has in common is <strong>motion.</strong></p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">If you look at these agencies motion stands almost as a core component in every single project and its no coincidence that they have become two of the most popular agencies in the world.</h4>



<p>So, I suggest you <em>look </em><strong>around you, accept motion and work on your skillset, </strong>because believe me this will become the future.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">On a final note, here are a few suggestions if you want to get started with motion design</h2>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/@DerekElliott"><strong>Derek Elliot</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.schoolofmotion.com/"><strong>School of Motion</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/@blenderguru"><strong>Blender Guru</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/@BenMarriott"><strong>Ben Marriott</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/@SonduckFilm"><strong>SounduckFilm</strong></a></li>
</ul>



<p>Although on the shorter side, <strong>I do hope this article has at least made you interested in motion, </strong>don’t forget to leave a comment below I’m interested to read your opinions.</p>



<p>Think different. Make difference.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/the-key-skill-every-designer-needs-to-learn-in-2024/">The key skill every designer needs to learn in 2024</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Hugo&#039;s Notes</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/the-key-skill-every-designer-needs-to-learn-in-2024/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What does the future of design look like?</title>
		<link>/what-does-the-future-of-design-look-like/</link>
					<comments>/what-does-the-future-of-design-look-like/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hugo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 15:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[augmented reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[designers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Future]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[people]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Typography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[virtual reality]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=215</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>What does the future of design look like? I don’t know about you but recently, this question has been on my mind. With this article, I will try to share some of my thoughts and get you to share yours hopefully. Photo by Possessed Photography on Unsplash Hello designers, how many of us think about [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/what-does-the-future-of-design-look-like/">What does the future of design look like?</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Hugo&#039;s Notes</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>What does the future of design look like?</strong> I don’t know about you but recently, <strong>this question has been on my mind.</strong> With this article, I will try to share some of my thoughts and get you to share yours hopefully.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="737" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/possessed-photography-jIBMSMs4_kA-unsplash-1-1024x737.jpg" alt="Photo of a robotic hand" class="wp-image-216" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/possessed-photography-jIBMSMs4_kA-unsplash-1-1024x737.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/possessed-photography-jIBMSMs4_kA-unsplash-1-300x216.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/possessed-photography-jIBMSMs4_kA-unsplash-1-768x553.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/possessed-photography-jIBMSMs4_kA-unsplash-1-1536x1106.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/possessed-photography-jIBMSMs4_kA-unsplash-1-2048x1474.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@possessedphotography?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Possessed Photography</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/closeup-photo-of-white-robot-arm-jIBMSMs4_kA?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Unsplash</a></p>



<p>Hello designers, <strong>how many of us think about the future a lot?</strong> I know I do, it&#8217;s probably a personal thing but thinking about the future is something I do quite often. Lately, my head has been contemplating <strong>the future of our field,</strong> particularly after I listened to the <a href="https://www.creativeboom.com/podcast/stefan-sagmeister/"><strong>99<sup>th</sup> episode of the Creative Boom Podcast with Stefan Sagmeister.</strong></a> (Highly recommend it)</p>



<p>In this article <strong>I’m not answering to “What does the future of design look like?”</strong> but instead to start a conversation. So, if you feel like it <strong>leave a comment below!</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The current state of design</h2>



<p>Design today has suffered many changes, <strong>we live in a mostly digital age,</strong> and as such <strong>the supports we play with are vastly different.</strong> To me, it&#8217;s interesting to look around and see <strong>different technologies coexist,</strong> you can read a newspaper physically or do it on your phone, and the same for books and many other types of mediums, even other types of products have changed – for example Car UI, <strong>you can drive a 90s car without barely any type of UI or drive the latest generation of cars with <a href="https://www.edenspiekermann.com/whitepaper/how-to-design-in-car-ux-that-doesnt-suck/">incredibly designed car UI.</a></strong> This coexistence is very interesting to me, and I think when I look at the current state of design it&#8217;s interesting the vast types of mediums we have at our disposal.</p>



<p>Design today has fundamentally changed, when we look at history,<strong> we see how it has evolved from a discipline that no one knew to one of the biggest fields of study</strong> <strong>in the world.</strong> Obviously, this also translated into an <strong>increase in competition.</strong></p>



<p>However, a <strong>side-effect </strong>related to the evolution of technology is how it has become <strong>more accessible. </strong>Thanks to the dawn of the internet era and the development of software, <strong>what was once a specialized area filled with few but incredibly talented people has now become an increasingly competitive field with a lot of untalented unknowledgeable people producing lackluster work.</strong></p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Imagine if suddenly a bunch of courses and tools were invented and introduced to make a doctor’s job easier but as a consequence, everyone thought that just by learning how to clean a wound they instantly could become a doctor. That’s how the landscape of design is today.</h4>



<p>Although a bit exaggerated, I’ve created this comparison as a <strong>way to explain to you my view</strong> on a lot of design projects and people. <strong>I don’t have anything against it, but it creates a lot of problems, </strong>particularly the devaluation of a designer’s job.</p>



<p>The most recent innovation that was talked about by everyone and created a lot of buzz in several industries without a doubt has been AI, <strong>probably the biggest creation in the last 10 years.</strong></p>



<p>In design AI created kind of a panic, we saw a lot of the people previously mentioned feel threatened and a lot of businesses replacing design and marketing teams at a very fast rate. But one has to ask, <strong>is this a bad thing?</strong> I will talk about this a bit later but to me, it isn’t such a big problem.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Looking into the past to project the future</h2>



<p>I think its <strong>very smart to look into the past to project the future,</strong> this is even more valid when we talk about technology.</p>



<p>Remember about the<strong> buzz </strong>when <strong>personal computers</strong> were first introduced? <strong>It completely changed the design landscape,</strong> what once took <strong>hours to do through tedious analog processes,</strong> was now <strong>possible to do with a few clicks,</strong> without you having to get your hands dirty. <strong>Isn’t this the same with AI?</strong></p>



<p>AI like personal computers <strong>scared a lot of people</strong> but in my view in the near future<strong> it will become a nearly invaluable piece of technology</strong> for many people’s lives. Even software manufacturers have already adapted to the times starting to offer a lot of AI based tools, like for example <strong>Photoshop’s generative AI tool.</strong></p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Like the personal computer or the internet, a lot of people freaked out with AI but eventually, those who accept these tools grow to outdo their colleagues who don’t. </h4>



<p>So, I’m not saying that you should use AI but be smart and look into it, so like many designers in the past who didn’t you don’t fall into oblivion.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Will AI replace designers?</h2>



<p>Throughout this article, I’ve pretty much given my opinion on AI and how it’s affecting the world but the top question is <strong>if it’s going to replace us?</strong></p>



<p>In my humble opinion it will replace a lot of work that you didn’t want to be involved in, <strong>a lot of clients who want cheap solutions</strong> that know nothing about design probably will use AI.</p>



<p>The clients who realize design is a<strong> human based field that creates products for human based clients </strong>will dismiss AI. This is already happening but I do believe it will only increase in the future.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Inherently this means, less bad-quality clients, more people interested in your services, more competition, and probably more money.</h4>



<p>So those who are good will <strong>undoubtedly stand out </strong>against a plethora of average unhuman work.</p>



<p>In the future<strong> AI will only replace bad clients,</strong> <strong>not good quality designers</strong> who take clients through an extensive process that culminates in the final result. At the end of the day,<strong> design is very human and the end product is for humans so replacement by AI isn’t an option</strong> for those who are serious about their business.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Is design a good career for the future?</h2>



<p>Honestly, I feel <strong>praise for good designers will only increase </strong>as we move to an age of <strong>pure digital trash.</strong></p>



<p>The more you look into developing your <strong>design skills and soft-skills</strong> the better. </p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Soft-skills in particular will be increasingly more important. The more you understand your client, and the more you build a human-level relationship the better, particularly for the end product.</h4>



<p>I also expect <strong>designer salaries and project budgets </strong>will in general increase, <strong>alongside with the competition</strong> for a job position. This will be a direct consequence of lower-budget clients moving to AI-based tools.</p>



<p>In my view, <strong>design will be a good career for the future</strong> as we continue to move to an even more digitalized industry. <strong>But,</strong> beware of the few points I talked about,<strong> the increase in competition and lackluster work will be very real, and you will have to seek inspiration in unusual places and possibly fight harder for an average job.</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What are the biggest problems facing designers in the future?</h2>



<p>The world we are heading towards seems a much better place in many areas, <strong><a href="https://sagmeister.com/work/now-is-better-book/">Stefan Sagmeister’s new book put this into perspective for me,</a> </strong>and I’m excited about the possibilities that we will have when AI and other technologies such as <strong>virtual and augmented reality</strong> play a bigger role in our lives.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">I feel like designers will have a very important role in the successful communication of world issues that become either worse or less mentioned in media.</h4>



<p>A long time from now I believe<strong> traditional media will completely change</strong> alongside<strong> traditional advertising</strong> making designers rethink new ways to communicate.</p>



<p><strong>Motion will become an even bigger part of our day-to-day, infiltrating itself into all the design fields.</strong> Static content will either disappear or become a very point of focus.</p>



<p>Social media will reach a <strong>blow-up point </strong>and this is when a new formula will appear, as such <strong>we will have to readapt.</strong></p>



<p><strong>Typeface design and major typefaces will have to adapt</strong> as we move to an age of further developed augmented and virtual reality.</p>



<p>We are eventually going to reach a point in which the <strong>current brutalist and maximalist trends will disappear in favor of a much more depurated approach</strong> from the days of designers such as <strong>Massimo Vignelli.</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What does the future look like for graphic designers?</h2>



<p>To me the future looks bright,<strong> I do believe traditional graphic design will change,</strong> perhaps our work category will change definitely to <strong>communication designer</strong> or<strong> visual designer, </strong>we already see a lot of these terms being used frequently.</p>



<p>Subsequently, education in design will change, and a <strong>focus on motion, product, and digital design </strong>seems to be an obvious update to the standard curriculum. </p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Perhaps the introduction of terms such as innovation in design or human-to-human design will become classes.</h4>



<p>With the constant development of technology, <strong>we face exciting new challenges every day,</strong> it will be our role like those who came before<strong> to adapt to a new age.</strong></p>



<p>I’m excited to see the future of design and although it will, to me, be more competitive it will also create <strong>interesting new opportunities</strong> to communicate.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">On a final note, this article is very speculative but it was written to kickstart an important conversation</h2>



<p>As people involved in this industry, we need to be able to start and maintain conversations about the future. <strong>Get involved.</strong></p>



<p>If you are interested in reading more, please check out <a href="/5-must-read-books-for-designers/"><strong>my last article.</strong></a></p>



<p>Please write a thoughtful comment below, I will try to answer all of them!</p>



<p>Stay safe.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/what-does-the-future-of-design-look-like/">What does the future of design look like?</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Hugo&#039;s Notes</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/what-does-the-future-of-design-look-like/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 Must-read books for designers</title>
		<link>/5-must-read-books-for-designers/</link>
					<comments>/5-must-read-books-for-designers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hugo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 14:28:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tips]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=206</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>If you are a designer or are interested in design start with these 5 must-read books for designers. In this article I will share with you some of my favorite design books and why I like them so much. Photo by Ugur Akdemir on Unsplash Hey everyone, lately I’ve been rereading a few design books [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/5-must-read-books-for-designers/">5 Must-read books for designers</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Hugo&#039;s Notes</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>If you are a designer or are interested in design start with these <strong>5 must-read books for designers.</strong> In this article I will share with you some of my favorite design books and why I like them so much.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/ugur-akdemir-XT-o5O458as-unsplash-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-207" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/ugur-akdemir-XT-o5O458as-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/ugur-akdemir-XT-o5O458as-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/ugur-akdemir-XT-o5O458as-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/ugur-akdemir-XT-o5O458as-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/ugur-akdemir-XT-o5O458as-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@ugur?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Ugur Akdemir</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/assorted-book-lot-XT-o5O458as?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Unsplash</a></p>



<p>Hey everyone, lately I’ve been rereading a few design books that I have around, mainly because of this article. Today I hope to share with you the <strong>5 books</strong> that, in my opinion, <strong>should be on everyone’s shelves.</strong></p>



<p>In a nutshell here are the books I’ll be talking about:</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.rit.edu/vignellicenter/sites/rit.edu.vignellicenter/files/documents/The%20Vignelli%20Canon.pdf"><strong>The Vignelli Canon</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="https://static.googleusercontent.com/media/fonts.google.com/en//knowledge/stop_stealing_sheep.pdf"><strong>Stop Stealing Sheep Find How Type Works</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Thinking-Type-2nd-revised-expanded/dp/1568989695/ref=sr_1_1?crid=27GQHNNEFZ9VA&amp;keywords=thinking+with+type&amp;qid=1699020278&amp;sprefix=thinking+with+type%252Caps%252C151&amp;sr=8-1&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=184a77f78f45bd64169dd654114b7bc4&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325"><strong>Thinking with Type</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Logotype-Mini-Michael-Evamy/dp/1780678576/ref=sr_1_1?crid=S5PBRRG10IKM&amp;keywords=logotype&amp;qid=1699020357&amp;sprefix=logotype%252Caps%252C149&amp;sr=8-1&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=d39f843df91e04fd7ed6eece49de6566&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325"><strong>Logotype</strong></a> &amp; <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Symbol-Mini-Steven-Bateman/dp/1780671849/ref=sr_1_3?crid=DFELVS6SDUBG&amp;keywords=symbol+book&amp;qid=1699020416&amp;sprefix=symbol+book%252Caps%252C154&amp;sr=8-3&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=0fd6771fd85e67e5b38493475b10967f&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325"><strong>Symbol</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="https://shop.itemzero.com/products/the-book-block/"><strong>The Book Block and The Book Cover</strong></a></li>
</ul>



<p>As per usual I would love to see what your suggestions for essential books are! Eventually, I would love to write another article on this topic, so <strong>send me your suggestions</strong> and they may be featured next time.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The Vignelli Canon</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="682" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/vignellicanon-1024x682.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-208" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/vignellicanon-1024x682.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/vignellicanon-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/vignellicanon-768x511.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/vignellicanon.jpg 1400w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Photo by David Hall</p>



<p>Written by the late iconic designer Massimo Vignelli, <strong>“The Vignelli Canon”</strong> is in my opinion of the most important design books ever made. It serves as a guide to the principles of what good design is while at the same time giving us incredible <strong>insights</strong> into Vignelli’s <strong>thought process, methodology, and philosophy.</strong></p>



<p>From the iconic list of 6 typefaces, I talked about in my <a href="/these-are-the-only-6-typefaces-you-need/"><strong>last article</strong></a> to the core ideas behind his designs, this book serves almost as a<strong> bible for anyone looking to become a designer.</strong></p>



<p>In an age where we are seeing more and more minimalist work being produced for the sake of being minimalist or style trends bringing back brutalism and maximalism, <strong>“The Vignelli Canon”</strong> is a nice reminder of what design isn’t and what it should be.</p>



<p>I truly believe everyone would love to read the lessons in this book, it is available to be bought <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Vignelli-Canon-Massimo/dp/3037782250/ref=sr_1_1?crid=2YODJL2ULJC05&amp;keywords=vignelli+canon&amp;qid=1699020710&amp;sprefix=vignelli+canon%252Caps%252C146&amp;sr=8-1&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=11ef91bc8d64483a31632b5eeabf7d0d&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325"><strong>here</strong></a> or totally free to download <a href="https://www.rit.edu/vignellicenter/sites/rit.edu.vignellicenter/files/documents/The%20Vignelli%20Canon.pdf"><strong>here.</strong></a> Amazingly, this book is<strong> completely free</strong> being yet another small detail that gives us a glimpse of the <strong>type of individual Vignelli was.</strong></p>



<p>Doing the research for this article I also came across <a href="https://soundcloud.com/designmatters/massimo-vignelli"><strong>this episode of the podcast Design Matters with Debbie Milman,</strong></a> although it was released 10 years ago, this episode still holds up and personally, I believe you will find a lot of value in it.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Stop Stealing Sheep Find How Type Works</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="682" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/stopstealingsheep-1024x682.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-209" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/stopstealingsheep-1024x682.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/stopstealingsheep-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/stopstealingsheep-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/stopstealingsheep.jpg 1061w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Photo by Erik Spiekermann</p>



<p>As a total fanboy, I really like this book written by also legendary designer and typographer <strong>Erik Spiekermann!</strong> &#8220;Stop Stealing Sheep Find How Type Works” is an <strong>incredible journey </strong>that leaves us understanding how important type is and how to use it.</p>



<p>This 4<sup>th</sup> edition is<strong> updated with a new chapter on variable typefaces,</strong> several examples on how to effectively communicate with type, and a full selection of new typefaces used and referenced throughout the book.</p>



<p>Although it’s a compact book it encourages reading and I guarantee every time you open it up you will find and learn something new.</p>



<p>This book is available to be <a href="https://shop.p98a.com/products/p98a-find-out-how-type-works-by-erik-spiekermann-4th-edition"><strong>bought through Erik’s experimental type gallery P98A</strong></a> and its also available for free on <a href="https://static.googleusercontent.com/media/fonts.google.com/en//knowledge/stop_stealing_sheep.pdf"><strong>Google Fonts,</strong></a> which is awesome!</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Thinking with type</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="682" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/thinkingwithtype-1024x682.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-210" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/thinkingwithtype-1024x682.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/thinkingwithtype-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/thinkingwithtype-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/thinkingwithtype-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/thinkingwithtype.jpg 2000w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Photo by Konstantinas Ladauskas</p>



<p>Do I have to say anything? Ellen Lupton’s iconic book <strong>“Thinking with Type”</strong> was released a long time ago but it still holds up as it is frequently updated by the author. Let’s be real your university probably had this book in their references and for a good reason!</p>



<p><strong>“Thinking with Type”</strong> is a comprehensive guide to topics such as font selection, spacing, grids, and layout design, providing practical advice and examples for designers.</p>



<p>I frequently find myself rereading this book and I learn something new every time!<strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Thinking-Type-2nd-revised-expanded/dp/1568989695/ref=sr_1_1?crid=27GQHNNEFZ9VA&amp;keywords=thinking+with+type&amp;qid=1699020278&amp;sprefix=thinking+with+type%252Caps%252C151&amp;sr=8-1&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=184a77f78f45bd64169dd654114b7bc4&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325">You can acquire a copy here.</a></strong> Unfortunately, there isn’t a free copy of this book I can link to you, perhaps one day <strong>Google Fonts</strong> will collaborate with Ellen, <strong>that would be awesome!</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Logotype &amp; Symbol</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="667" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/logotype.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-211" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/logotype.jpg 1000w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/logotype-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/logotype-768x512.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure>



<p>Photo by Inkbot Design</p>



<p>If you’re like me and many other designers in the world <strong>seeking inspiration and references is basically a part of our day-to-day routines.</strong> When we talk about branding projects<strong> having good references for inspiration that you can pull out at any time is also essential.</strong></p>



<p>While for many years the holy grail of logo reference has been a book called<strong> “Logo Modernism”</strong>, which is a mammoth of a book, today I want to tell you about the two alternatives <strong>“Logotype &amp; Symbol”.</strong></p>



<p>Like <strong>“Logo Modernism”</strong> these two books, which I personally think you should buy together, serve as a more digestible alternative. If you already own the mammoth you will find <strong>“Logotype &amp; Symbol”</strong> still useful as there isn’t much duplicated content between books.</p>



<p>Personally, I really like these and whenever I’m working on any kind of branding project, <strong>they are extremely useful,</strong> if you are in a team their size is also useful to share between people.</p>



<p>You can buy a <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Logotype-Mini-Michael-Evamy/dp/1780678576/ref=sr_1_1?crid=S5PBRRG10IKM&amp;keywords=logotype&amp;qid=1699020357&amp;sprefix=logotype%252Caps%252C149&amp;sr=8-1&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=d39f843df91e04fd7ed6eece49de6566&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325"><strong>copy here,</strong></a> which allows you to choose between a physical or a digital copy which is also cool!</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The Book Block and The Book Cover</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="684" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/thebookblock-1024x684.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-212" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/thebookblock-1024x684.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/thebookblock-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/thebookblock-768x513.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/thebookblock.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Photo by Luís Espinheira </p>



<p>Last but not least a suggestion that I’m sure you will love. <strong>“The Book Block and The Book Cover”</strong> are perfect books for anyone looking to work on editorial design, they are incredibly useful tools.</p>



<p>Created by Portuguese studio <strong>itemzero</strong> they present, in a very straight to the point useful way the key ingredients needed to design a great publication.</p>



<p>Explaining different techniques with a plethora of variations <strong>this book is in my view essential for anyone working in the industry.</strong></p>



<p>Last but not least for my Portuguese audience it also is multilingual which is awesome. You can acquire a copy <strong><a href="https://shop.itemzero.com/products/the-book-block/">here</a>,</strong> they frequently have discounts so stay alert!</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">On a final note, I hope you found these books useful and please remember to share your must-haves</h2>



<p>Today’s article was on the shorter side but I hope you truly found this information useful.</p>



<p>You can read the last article <strong><a href="/these-are-the-only-6-typefaces-you-need/">here</a>.</strong></p>



<p>Thank you for reading, stay safe and have fun!</p>
<p>The post <a href="/5-must-read-books-for-designers/">5 Must-read books for designers</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Hugo&#039;s Notes</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/5-must-read-books-for-designers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>These are the only 6 typefaces you need</title>
		<link>/these-are-the-only-6-typefaces-you-need/</link>
					<comments>/these-are-the-only-6-typefaces-you-need/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hugo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 14:24:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Typography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=179</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In the current day and age of design we have thousands and thousands of typefaces to choose from, so in this article following the lessons of modernist designers like Massimo Vignelli, I’m going to tell you the only 6 typefaces you need and that are the basis of my collection. Photo by Bruno Martins on [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/these-are-the-only-6-typefaces-you-need/">These are the only 6 typefaces you need</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Hugo&#039;s Notes</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In the current day and age of design we have <strong>thousands and thousands of typefaces to choose from,</strong> so in this article following the lessons of modernist designers like <strong>Massimo Vignelli,</strong> I’m going to tell you <strong>the only 6 typefaces you need and that are the basis of my collection.</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="682" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/bruno-martins-4cwf-iW6I1Q-unsplash-1024x682.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-185" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/bruno-martins-4cwf-iW6I1Q-unsplash-1024x682.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/bruno-martins-4cwf-iW6I1Q-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/bruno-martins-4cwf-iW6I1Q-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/bruno-martins-4cwf-iW6I1Q-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/bruno-martins-4cwf-iW6I1Q-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@brunus?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Bruno Martins</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/brown-and-black-wooden-cross-4cwf-iW6I1Q?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Unsplash</a></p>



<p>Hello designers, recently I’ve been rereading a few books and articles on typefaces, particularly the new <a href="https://www.neue.shop/fonts/neue-serie57"><strong>Neue series 57 made by Neue Type Foundry in collaboration with Erik Spiekermann.</strong></a> These books and articles made me think a lot about type design and how it has evolved so much over the years.</p>



<p>Particularly I’ve been also rereading the infamous <strong><a href="https://www.rit.edu/vignellicenter/sites/rit.edu.vignellicenter/files/documents/The%20Vignelli%20Canon.pdf">Vignelli canon written by Massimo Vignelli</a>,</strong> one of the most important designers in history. In the book Vignelli teaches us about his philosophy on design and <strong>shares with us</strong> his iconic list of the only <strong>6 typefaces you need,</strong> claiming that <strong>you can trash the rest.</strong></p>



<p>Rediscovering this made me think <strong>“Hmm would his list today be the same?”</strong> with the evolution of technology and design trends I imagine his list would also evolve with the times. The matter of the fact is <strong>it’s still a relevant list that all designers still talk about today!</strong></p>



<p>The way you should see this article is very simple – <strong>it’s my own view </strong>of what those 6 typefaces would be,<strong> not an updated Vignelli list,</strong> just my list.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">“In the new computer age the proliferation of typefaces and type manipulations represents a new level of visual pollution threating our culture. Out of thousands of typefaces, all we need are a few basic ones, and trash the rest. So come and see A Few Basic Typefaces” <em>– Massimo Vignelli</em></h2>



<p>In a nutshell here is Vignelli’s list:</p>



<ul>
<li>Garamond</li>



<li>Bodoni</li>



<li>Century Expanded</li>



<li>Futura</li>



<li>Times Roman</li>



<li>Helvetica</li>
</ul>



<p>This list in my view <strong>is still very viable</strong> but I don’t think a lot of these typefaces<strong> stand the test of time </strong>as good as they probably should, <strong>either they have been redesigned or there are just better options.</strong> <strong>Don’t take this opinion from just me,</strong> see what people like <strong>Erik Spiekermann</strong> think of <strong>Helvetica,</strong> probably the most iconic typeface ever made – <a href="https://spiekermann.com/en/helvetica-sucks/"><strong>“Helvetica sucks. It really wasn’t designed for small sizes on screens. Words like milliliter can be very difficult to decipher.”</strong></a></p>



<p>To me these 6 typefaces <strong>lack features that most designers need today,</strong> I’m not saying I can put together a better list, but <strong>here is my attempt:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://fonts.google.com/specimen/EB+Garamond?query=eb+garamond"><strong>Eb Garamond</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="https://fonts.google.com/specimen/Bodoni+Moda?query=bodoni+moda"><strong>Bodoni Moda</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="https://fonts.google.com/specimen/Playfair+Display"><strong>Playfair Display</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="https://fonts.google.com/specimen/Poppins?query=poppins"><strong>Poppins</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.edenspiekermann.com/insights/mozilla-fira-fox/"><strong>Fira Sans</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.fontshare.com/fonts/switzer"><strong>Switzer</strong></a></li>
</ul>



<p>A small note if you have your own list please tell me about it in the comment section, <strong>I would love to know!</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Eb Garamond</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="500" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/ebgaramond.png" alt="" class="wp-image-200" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/ebgaramond.png 1000w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/ebgaramond-300x150.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/ebgaramond-768x384.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure>



<p>Made as a <strong>revival of Claude Garamond’s original 1532 typeface,</strong> which is present on Vignelli’s list, this version was made for the digital age. The source for the letterforms comes from a scan of the <strong>“Berner Specimen”</strong> composed in 1592 by Conrad Berner.</p>



<p>Its letterforms are <strong>elegant and well-proportioned,</strong> striking a balance between classic aesthetics and modern legibility, making it <strong>suitable for various applications, including body text and headings.</strong></p>



<p>EB Garamond is versatile, offering different weights and styles.<strong> It&#8217;s also an open-source typeface!</strong></p>



<p>With an extensive character set, it supports various characters and diacritics, making it suitable for multilingual projects. <strong>Its attention to detail during the revival and refinement process ensures a high-quality typeface with consistent design features. </strong>EB Garamond works well in both print and digital contexts, thanks to its design that maintains its elegance and legibility in various sizes and applications.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Why is this typeface on my list?</h4>



<p>Like <strong>Vignelli</strong> it made sense to me to include Garamond although in my case a more updated version of it, <strong>it’s a perfect typeface for a variety of uses,</strong> it has a lower contrast between strokes but it exhibits a classic timeless design.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Bodoni Moda</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="500" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/bodonimoda.png" alt="" class="wp-image-199" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/bodonimoda.png 1000w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/bodonimoda-300x150.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/bodonimoda-768x384.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure>



<p>On the same line as EB Garamond Bodoni Moda is also a <strong>revival for the digital age </strong>designed by Owen Earl. It&#8217;s a <strong>contemporary reinterpretation of the classic Bodoni typeface loved by Vignelli, </strong>originally created by the Italian typographer Giambattista Bodoni in the late 18th century. The typeface&#8217;s historical connection gives it a touch of <strong>timeless sophistication,</strong> making it a suitable choice for a range of design applications.</p>



<p>One of Bodoni Moda&#8217;s key strengths is its <strong>high contrast between thick and thin strokes,</strong> which is a hallmark of the Bodoni style. This contrast gives the typeface a <strong>distinct and striking appearance</strong> that works exceptionally well for headlines, titles, and other display text. <strong>The sharp, geometric letterforms contribute to a sense of refinement and modernity.</strong></p>



<p>Bodoni Moda is available in various weights and styles, making it versatile for different design projects. The typeface&#8217;s versatility extends to its ability to be used in both print and digital media. <strong>Its clean and precise design ensures that it remains legible and aesthetically pleasing, even at small text sizes.</strong></p>



<p>It is an excellent choice for projects that require a blend of classic elegance and modern sophistication.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Why is this typeface on my list?</h4>



<p>I love Bodoni Moda, besides being a great revival t<strong>he contrasts in each letterform gives it a sharp, refined look.</strong> It’s a perfect companion for EB Garamond and should be in your collection.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Playfair Display</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="500" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/playfairdisplay.png" alt="" class="wp-image-197" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/playfairdisplay.png 1000w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/playfairdisplay-300x150.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/playfairdisplay-768x384.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure>



<p>Playfair Display is an<strong> elegant and versatile typeface with a distinct historical charm.</strong> It was inspired by the work of John Baskerville, a renowned 18th-century typographer. This historical association imparts a <strong>timeless and classic quality </strong>to Playfair Display, making it an excellent choice for a wide range of design projects.</p>



<p>One of the key strengths of Playfair Display is like Bodoni Moda <strong>its combination of high contrast between thick and thin strokes and the graceful, well-proportioned letterforms.</strong> This balance between classic aesthetics and modern readability makes it a versatile choice suitable for both body text and headings. The typeface manages to strike a <strong>harmonious equilibrium </strong>between the two, making it a perfect option for projects that require a touch of sophistication.</p>



<p>Playfair Display comes in various styles and weights, offering flexibility for different design needs.<strong> This versatility ensures that it can be used effectively for a variety of applications,</strong> from traditional print materials to contemporary web design.</p>



<p>Playfair Display&#8217;s appeal lies in its<strong> historical lineage, elegant high-contrast design, versatility, and open-source availability. </strong>It is a typeface that seamlessly blends classic aesthetics with modern readability.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Why is this typeface on my list?</h4>



<p>Although fairly similar to the previous two options Playfair Display is<strong> unique in the smaller details,</strong> I really like specific characters like the <strong>“Q” </strong>or the <strong>“r” </strong>and also the number selection. In conjunction with the previous two typefaces, <strong>it covers most of my serif needs.</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Poppins</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="500" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/poppins.png" alt="" class="wp-image-198" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/poppins.png 1000w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/poppins-300x150.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/poppins-768x384.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure>



<p>Poppins is a contemporary and adaptable typeface that combines a <strong>clean, sans-serif design with a touch of approachability and friendliness. </strong>It was designed by type designer Ninad Kale, with a focus on <strong>modernity and readability, </strong>making it a versatile choice for a wide range of design projects.</p>



<p>One of the key strengths of Poppins is its <strong>simplicity and legibility. </strong>The typeface features <strong>well-proportioned, straightforward letterforms that are easy to read,</strong> making it suitable for both body text and headings. Its design is crisp and clear, which is particularly well-suited for digital media and screen usage.</p>



<p>Poppins offers a variety of weights and styles. <strong>This diversity allows for flexibility in design,</strong> ensuring that it can be used effectively in a multitude of contexts, from web design to branding and print materials.</p>



<p>Poppins&#8217; appeal lies in its modern and approachable design, legibility, and versatility. <strong>It&#8217;s a typeface that seamlessly blends contemporary aesthetics with readability.</strong></p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Why is this typeface on my list?</h4>



<p>I picked Poppins as an <strong>alternative to Futura, which I don’t like.</strong> To me Poppins is Futura with a more refined letterform design, it’s<strong> slightly more geometric</strong> but it <strong>shares the key qualities of Futura.</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Fira Sans</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="500" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/firasans.png" alt="" class="wp-image-196" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/firasans.png 1000w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/firasans-300x150.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/firasans-768x384.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure>



<p>Initially designed as a <strong>commission from Firefox to Edenspiekermann </strong>Fira Sans is a modern and adaptable sans-serif typeface designed by <strong>Erik Spiekermann and Ralph du Carrois.</strong> It was crafted taking as a base the well-known iconic <strong>FF Meta </strong>to provide a highly legible and functional option, making it a versatile choice for a variety of design projects.</p>



<p>One of the key strengths of Fira Sans is its <strong>exceptional legibility.</strong> The letterforms are<strong> clean, balanced, and well-proportioned,</strong> ensuring easy readability, which is crucial for body text, headings, and user interfaces. This makes Fira Sans an excellent choice for content across various mediums.</p>



<p>Fira Sans offers an extensive range of weights and styles, including regular, italic, bold, and condensed versions. This wide variety of options allows designers to tailor their typographic choices to fit the specific requirements of a project,<strong> from web design to branding and editorial layouts.</strong></p>



<p>Fira Sans&#8217;s appeal lies in its modern design, exceptional legibility, extensive weights and styles, and open-source availability.<strong> It is a versatile and reliable typeface</strong> that works well in a wide array of design applications.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Why is this typeface on my list?</h4>



<p>I really like Fira Sans, it’s one of my favorite typefaces and I still cannot believe it’s free and open-source. Designed by one of my favorite designers it’s a <strong>humanistic sans-serif typeface that fits the list really well, </strong>it’s one of the key elements I believe <strong>Vignelli’s list lacks.</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Switzer</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="500" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/switzer.png" alt="" class="wp-image-195" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/switzer.png 1000w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/switzer-300x150.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/switzer-768x384.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure>



<p>Inspired by<strong> neo-grotesk Swiss typefaces </strong>Switzer is a typeface designed by Indian Type Foundry. This modern interpretation translated to a modern geometric sans-serif that is very legible.</p>



<p>Like Fira Sans and Poppins, the key strength is its <strong>exceptional legibility and simplicity. </strong>The letterforms although geometric have a lot of character. <strong>Balanced, clean, and very straightforward </strong>Switzer is an <strong>essential typeface.</strong></p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Why is this typeface on my list?</h4>



<p>In my opinion, this typeface solves the main issues I and many designers have with Helvetica, <strong>it has character but it still shares the key qualities of Helvetica.</strong> It’s a workhorse of a typeface completely free which is also incredible.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">So, this was my list, with these 6 typefaces I believe most designers will have their needs covered. Compared to Vignelli’s list it actually is fairly similar although I’ve replaced one of the serifs for a humanistic sans-serif typeface which in my opinion, and for my work, was the missing ingredient!</h2>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What makes this list good?</h2>



<p><strong>Versatility</strong> was the key aspect when I was making this list, I wanted three serifs and three sans-serifs that <strong>were versatile but that at the same time covered the several aspects that make each category unique. </strong>When looking to<strong> Vignelli’s </strong>list and mine you can clearly see what I mean, both lists follow the same thought process.</p>



<p>I wanted to also include the most amount of <strong>variable and web-ready typefaces </strong>as I believe this type of technology is the future.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Why have I chosen only free typefaces?</h2>



<p>Mainly because they are<strong> widely available and easier to integrate, </strong>but also because <strong>I don’t like the fact that I have to pay thousands for Helvetica when better, free typefaces are available. </strong>I don’t like the types of prices most foundries ask for a single individual font, as a student it bothered me.<strong> I’m really glad we live in a time and age where free typefaces are a lot of the times good or better than paid ones.</strong></p>



<p>In the future, I hope projects like <strong>Google Fonts </strong>or <strong>Adobe Fonts </strong>continue to make proper efforts to support type designers and provide great typefaces for free. I will also always support foundries that make great typefaces open-source, free, or adequately priced. <strong>You’re awesome!</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">On a final note, let me remind you that mine or Vignelli’s list are just a basis, you can and should always expand on it and search for better alternatives.</h2>



<p>Even if you look at Vignelli’s work you will see other typefaces, for example, the Ducati logo he designed uses Univers. So<strong> be open to new horizons and support type designers and small foundries</strong> whenever you can!</p>



<p>Thank you for reading, as per usual I would love to read your opinion.</p>



<p>You can read the last article <a href="/5-must-have-items-every-designer-needs-in-their-toolkit/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/these-are-the-only-6-typefaces-you-need/">These are the only 6 typefaces you need</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Hugo&#039;s Notes</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/these-are-the-only-6-typefaces-you-need/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 must-have items every designer needs in their toolkit</title>
		<link>/5-must-have-items-every-designer-needs-in-their-toolkit/</link>
					<comments>/5-must-have-items-every-designer-needs-in-their-toolkit/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hugo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 14:14:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=155</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>During my time in college and the beginning of my career, I’ve found out a lot of stuff that isn’t really that useful for my work and a lot of stuff that is, with this in mind today I want to share with you 5 items that are must-haves for every designer’s toolkit. Photo by [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/5-must-have-items-every-designer-needs-in-their-toolkit/">5 must-have items every designer needs in their toolkit</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Hugo&#039;s Notes</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>During my time in college and the beginning of my career, <strong>I’ve found out a lot of stuff that isn’t really that useful for my work and a lot of stuff that is,</strong> with this in mind today I want to share with you 5 items that are must-haves for every designer’s toolkit.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/theme-photos-CGpifH3FjOA-unsplash-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-160" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/theme-photos-CGpifH3FjOA-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/theme-photos-CGpifH3FjOA-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/theme-photos-CGpifH3FjOA-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/theme-photos-CGpifH3FjOA-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/theme-photos-CGpifH3FjOA-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@themephotos?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Theme Photos</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/tuned-on-macbook-CGpifH3FjOA?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Unsplash</a></p>



<p><strong>First of all, some disclaimers</strong>. I’m not going to suggest stuff that is very basic like a laptop, there are already a bunch of articles like this, I wanted to instead suggest useful items that go beyond the very basic of what you need. Another quick disclaimer, some links here are going to be affiliate links, no cost for you but it helps me out if you buy stuff through the link.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">If you are completely new, and you truly were searching for a very basic article of what you needed, here is a very quick list of stuff that hopefully will help you, so you don’t spend your time reading 1000 articles.</h4>



<p>Although you may not need all of this it is going to cover 99% of your needs when starting. The most important thing is to not be a gear nerd, start with what you have and build it up, anyways here are some suggestions for essentials:</p>



<ol>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MacBook-13-inch-Storage-English/dp/B0CB7619C5/ref=sr_1_2_sspa?crid=3O4OCFDUEVEV4&amp;keywords=macbook%252Bair%252Bm1&amp;qid=1698423727&amp;sprefix=mabook%252Bair%252Bm1%252Caps%252C155&amp;sr=8-2-spons&amp;sp_csd=d2lkZ2V0TmFtZT1zcF9hdGY&amp;th=1&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=e226893acacd9887515f01f98648dece&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325"><strong>Laptop</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="http://adobe.com/"><strong>Adobe software</strong></a> and if appliable <a href="http://figma.com/"><strong>Figma</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Minimalism-Art-Classic-Notebook-Journal/dp/B077Y3N8NN/ref=sr_1_1_sspa?crid=3D06EFD274X5X&amp;keywords=graphic%252Bdiary&amp;qid=1698423889&amp;sprefix=graphic%252Bdiary%252Caps%252C158&amp;sr=8-1-spons&amp;sp_csd=d2lkZ2V0TmFtZT1zcF9hdGY&amp;th=1&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=8976fd711e3ad60eb335c723dc77a5b8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325"><strong>Graphic diary</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Kingston-DataTraveler-Exodia-128GB-DTX/dp/B08JD4TBM3/ref=sr_1_4?crid=3TGO88RNB8TE1&amp;keywords=usb%252Bkingston&amp;qid=1697706811&amp;sprefix=usb%252Bkingston%252Caps%252C190&amp;sr=8-4&amp;th=1&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=a291591cfdb9ed5aa0039df482045bcd&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325"><strong>USB drive</strong></a> &amp;/or <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08GTYFC37/ref=twister_B0C6YZGJFH?_encoding=UTF8&amp;th=1&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=5b949e90b0315a238043d629b5d7c020&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325"><strong>External hard drive</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Stainless-Conversion-Metric-Straight-Measurement/dp/B08TWX79NC/ref=sxin_16_pa_sp_search_thematic_sspa?content-id=amzn1.sym.1b6a73e3-769d-477e-9f54-0fe90c31162a%253Aamzn1.sym.1b6a73e3-769d-477e-9f54-0fe90c31162a&amp;crid=26T56SF6NDPZ0&amp;cv_ct_cx=metal+ruler&amp;keywords=metal+ruler&amp;pd_rd_i=B08TWX79NC&amp;pd_rd_r=1af55778-1ffd-4f22-a87a-ad5ffa53cffa&amp;pd_rd_w=r7C8Z&amp;pd_rd_wg=EnUST&amp;pf_rd_p=1b6a73e3-769d-477e-9f54-0fe90c31162a&amp;pf_rd_r=1CXN9W6WNV56V4GYWDD7&amp;qid=1698424049&amp;sbo=RZvfv%252F%252FHxDF%252BO5021pAnSA%253D%253D&amp;sprefix=metal+ruler%252Caps%252C152&amp;sr=1-1-9cb21890-b538-4fe1-898e-473f8bb6c1fa-spons&amp;sp_csd=d2lkZ2V0TmFtZT1zcF9zZWFyY2hfdGhlbWF0aWM&amp;psc=1&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=fc9b8f19f364b8f3b34ef4ac4a6c280a&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325"><strong>Metal ruler</strong></a>, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/VViViD-Precision-Hobby-Craft-Cutting-Including/dp/B06XSR29J7/ref=sr_1_59?crid=2LI939PIZ05FQ&amp;keywords=xacto+knife&amp;qid=1698424219&amp;sprefix=xacto+knif%252Caps%252C182&amp;sr=8-59&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=977be96d091e556fb56ff580ca14dae3&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325"><strong>X-acto Knife</strong></a> &amp; <a href="https://www.amazon.com/US-Art-Supply-Professional-Scrapbooking/dp/B00L5I8RJC/ref=sr_1_50?crid=2LI939PIZ05FQ&amp;keywords=xacto%252Bknife&amp;qid=1698424192&amp;sprefix=xacto%252Bknif%252Caps%252C182&amp;sr=8-50&amp;th=1&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=6238f7036bdac3d39c0b071b5834ad8a&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325"><strong>Cutting Mat</strong></a></li>



<li>Tracing Paper, normal paper &amp; Cardstock of different colors</li>



<li>Pencils of different strengths &amp; Pens</li>



<li>Printer &amp; Scanner</li>



<li>Good books (I’m going to write an article on design book suggestions next week, stay tuned)</li>



<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/KS1-Headphones-Resolution-Detachable-Auriculares/dp/B08TWPZB9P/ref=sr_1_1_sspa?crid=2BVTAWJG9WHC2&amp;keywords=kbear%252Bks1&amp;qid=1698424660&amp;sprefix=kbear%252Bks1%252Caps%252C154&amp;sr=8-1-spons&amp;sp_csd=d2lkZ2V0TmFtZT1zcF9hdGY&amp;th=1&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=ffe02f4e272af4585fcdad2409a25fa0&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325"><strong>In-ear monitors</strong></a> &amp; Good Music</li>
</ol>



<p>Some stuff I haven&#8217;t linked because <strong>it either depends on preference or just overall knowledge</strong> I have with said product, for example I really like the Staedtler Norris line, specifically the B1 pencil and I have no knowledge on what the best printers are although I like Epson. With the basics removed out of the way <strong>here are the another 5 must-have items that every designer needs in their toolkit.</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Pantone Formula Guides</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="1000" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/pantone-color-books.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-169" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/pantone-color-books.jpg 1000w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/pantone-color-books-300x300.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/pantone-color-books-150x150.jpg 150w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/pantone-color-books-768x768.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure>



<p>It’s funny that I just wrote <a href="/we-need-to-talk-about-pantone/"><strong>this article</strong></a> on <a href="http://pantone.com/"><strong>Pantone</strong></a> and the first thing I’m suggesting is their Formula Guide sets. <strong>They are extremely useful for a variety of applications and a variety of designers.</strong> It’s a color system that has been <strong>refined and standardized</strong> over decades and it can now be in the palm of your hands (literally).</p>



<p>I used them at university for a bunch of different projects and I use them now on basically a day-to-day basis in a plethora of different projects. <strong>They are an essential item every agency and studio owns </strong>and an item that should be on your acquirement list.</p>



<p><strong>Don’t be</strong> that designer who picks Pantone colors by looking at their monitors, please I beg you. I’ve met a few people who have done work like this and it bothers me on a whole new level.</p>



<p>Personally, I have the standard non-bridge Formula Guide set which I bought before the whole Adobe and Pantone situation which led to the dreadful implementation of Pantone Connect. If you are acquiring your Pantone catalogs now, I recommend you to get the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Pantone-Bridge-Guides-Coated-Uncoated/dp/B0BY9QWBWF/ref=sr_1_15?keywords=pantone+color+bridge&amp;qid=1698498734&amp;sr=8-15&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=ad4d4d1ca1f00f696427323ce9856d63&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325"><strong>Pantone Formula Guide Bridge Coated &amp; Uncoated set,</strong></a> so you don’t have issues when picking colors for projects where you need CMYK and RGB values.</p>



<p>Also, a quick tip Pantone on the back of their Formula guide sets claim they last for only a year, <strong>if you preserve your guides in a dark environment with no humidity, they will last you years. </strong>One of my teachers showed us her guides with 40+ years of use, the colors were mostly perfect. Think about it.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">CMY color wheel</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="845" height="1024" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/cmy-color-wheel-845x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-170" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/cmy-color-wheel-845x1024.jpg 845w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/cmy-color-wheel-248x300.jpg 248w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/cmy-color-wheel-768x931.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/cmy-color-wheel.jpg 1238w" sizes="(max-width: 845px) 100vw, 845px" /></figure>



<p>This item was also recommended by a teacher and it took me years to find it online being sold again. It’s a color wheel that helps you figure out color combinations, there’s also an <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.cmycolorwheel.cmy&amp;hl=en&amp;gl=US"><strong>app that I would recommend for Android</strong></a> that I used previously. To be honest, if you can buy a physical version of the wheel, it’s cheap and feels better than the one on your phone.</p>



<p>This color wheel is very well printed with a fair amount of accuracy and attention to detail which is also important. Using a color wheel is in my opinion an<strong> essential part of my workflow </strong>and an inexpensive incredibly useful tool.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Also, if you don’t want to get the one from the link I provided, make sure you get a CMY color wheel, don’t get a RYB color wheel.</h4>



<p>The RYB color wheel was created in the <strong>early days of color theory when we did not know about the existence of pigments Cyan and Magenta </strong>which are nowadays the standard for printing.</p>



<p><strong>The RYB color wheel unfortunately is still taught in a lot of schools and even universities,</strong> even a lot of design books still teach that model and subsequently there are a lot of wheels around that follow the RYB model, while it’s great for painting it’s awful for design, just remember that.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/COLOR-WHEEL-COMPANY-BOOK/dp/B004YDDBM8/ref=sr_1_3?crid=3MQHGV8RTE4WP&amp;keywords=cmy+color+wheel&amp;qid=1698499645&amp;sprefix=cmy+color+wheel%252Caps%252C167&amp;sr=8-3&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=46d3450a3c81e453942643919efc1477&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325"><strong>Basically, make sure you buy a CMY color wheel</strong></a><strong> </strong>which is much more useful and updated. Also, a huge thank you to Professor Dulce for teaching this and explaining it in detail, happy to have learned from you.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Ergonomic Chair</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="640" height="360" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/my-back.gif" alt="" class="wp-image-158" style="aspect-ratio:1.7777777777777777;width:751px;height:auto"/></figure>



<p>Don’t be like <strong>Spiderman </strong>get a good quality chair. I’m going to be honest with you here I don’t have any specific recommendation to give you since everybody is different, but there are a few tips I can give you:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Forget about gaming chairs</strong> most of them are offensively bad for your posture, racing chairs are for racing not for you to be looking at a monitor 8h per day.</li>



<li>If it’s very cheap the materials are probably not that great, <strong>consider getting fewer features</strong> to save money instead of losing on material quality.</li>



<li>I really like <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hEC4wn6ayaY&amp;ab_channel=BTODtv"><strong>this video</strong></a> comparing chairs, I think you should watch it.</li>
</ul>



<p>Every person is different but maintaining a good posture is a universal thing, I also recommend you to do a lot of breaks and frequent exercise. <strong>There is no chair on the market that will fix any of these issues for you.</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Good mouse and keyboard</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="1024" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/mx-keys-1024x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-175" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/mx-keys-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/mx-keys-300x300.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/mx-keys-150x150.jpg 150w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/mx-keys-768x768.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/mx-keys-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/mx-keys-2048x2048.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>A good mouse and keyboard are essential tools to us who actually properly use them for hours per day, but beware the industry is full of bad products.</p>



<p>What I can recommend from experience is the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Logitech-K120-Arabic-Black-keyboard/dp/B00P7Z7SXU/ref=sr_1_3?crid=Z0AC640RDYFH&amp;keywords=logitech+k120&amp;qid=1698500660&amp;sprefix=logitech+k120%252Caps%252C164&amp;sr=8-3&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=756af2e9a26235ca1304d272d8ef6b93&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325"><strong>Logitech k120 keyboard</strong></a> which I used for years, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Glorious-Model-Wireless-Gaming-Mouse/dp/B098RDJZFM/ref=sr_1_4?crid=71MLAP7T20LH&amp;keywords=model+o&amp;qid=1698500736&amp;sprefix=model+o%252Caps%252C173&amp;sr=8-4&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=07f322bdd329e080b561d6638e52cc32&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325"><strong>the model O,</strong></a> the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Logitech-LIGHTSYNC-Wired-Gaming-Mouse/dp/B07YN82X3B/ref=sr_1_3?crid=20HM4OAUAB7V6&amp;keywords=g203&amp;qid=1698500815&amp;sprefix=g203%25252Caps%25252C168&amp;sr=8-3&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=1a40e4b1c173e582670efd65e9ca0c9f&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325"><strong>G203 Prodigy mouse,</strong></a> and the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Logitech-Master-Advanced-Wireless-Mouse/dp/B07XC2FWD1/ref=sr_1_3?crid=KNWUZAOKJ2TX&amp;keywords=mx%252Bmaster%252B3&amp;qid=1698501295&amp;sprefix=mx%252Bmaster%252B3%252Caps%252C189&amp;sr=8-3&amp;th=1&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=dd7e46ccfb5d98067d7ed91617def009&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325"><strong>Mx Master 3.</strong></a></p>



<p>The K120 keyboard is cheap, works great, and in my opinion is an absolute steal, out of the mice I recommended all of them are also equally great but the Mx Master 3 is by far my favorite mouse ever, so much that I’m even getting another one to use in my internship.</p>



<p>Also, I recently bought the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Logitech-Keys-Combo-Customizable-Illumination/dp/B0BKVY4WKT/ref=sr_1_2?crid=25B6H6S0QKYZB&amp;keywords=logitech%252Bmx%252Bkeys%252Bcombo&amp;qid=1698500573&amp;sprefix=logitech%252Bmx%252Bkeys%252Bcombo%252Caps%252C189&amp;sr=8-2&amp;th=1&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=a8b9fc45e71398421dd23c39eab9cc7e&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325"><strong>Mx Master 3 and Mx Keys combo</strong></a> which I’m going to review on the blog, stay tuned.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Paper catalogs</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="704" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Fedrigoni-Paper-Box-1024x704.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-177" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Fedrigoni-Paper-Box-1024x704.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Fedrigoni-Paper-Box-300x206.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Fedrigoni-Paper-Box-768x528.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Fedrigoni-Paper-Box.jpg 1160w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p><strong>Last but not least on my list are paper catalogs.</strong> I absolutely don’t understand why people don’t talk about these more often they are <strong>essential tools for anyone working with any type of physical stuff</strong> they need to design. Business cards, books, magazines, and newspapers all need one thing – paper!</p>



<p>So, a catalog is by far one of the most useful tools you can have around.</p>



<p>My recommendation is to first check local print manufacturers, in Portugal, we have <a href="https://inapaportugal.pt/"><strong>Inapa,</strong></a> for example. These are probably the most common types of papers that your printers provide. Beyond this I would recommend two paper manufacturer catalogs – <a href="https://www.metapaper.io/en/paper/sample-book/"><strong>Metapaper’s Sample Book</strong></a> and <a href="https://fedrigoni.com/en/news/paper-box-fedrigoni-paper/"><strong>Fedrigoni’s Paper Box.</strong></a></p>



<p>Out of these two<strong> Fedrigoni’s paper box</strong> is the most complete although it is a paid product and unfortunately currently is slightly outdated since they have removed some products.</p>



<p>I have a nice customer experience with them and you can request any paper samples you want from their website for free! <strong>They are very considerate!</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">On a final note I wanted to just tell you that tools are just tools, without the knowledge you can have the best laptop and not be an amazing designer, skills come first – don’t be a gearhead.</h2>



<p>If you liked this article please comment below! I will try to read and answer all of them.</p>



<p>You can read the previous article <a href="/we-need-to-talk-about-pantone/"><strong>here!</strong></a></p>



<p>Thank you for reading, stay safe.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/5-must-have-items-every-designer-needs-in-their-toolkit/">5 must-have items every designer needs in their toolkit</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Hugo&#039;s Notes</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/5-must-have-items-every-designer-needs-in-their-toolkit/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>We need to talk about Pantone</title>
		<link>/we-need-to-talk-about-pantone/</link>
					<comments>/we-need-to-talk-about-pantone/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hugo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 11:44:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pantone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pricing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=148</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Pantone is one of the most well-known companies in the design industry, they are the industry standard for color solutions and they have built a monopoly over their slice of the market, hence why we need to talk about them. Photo by Mika Baumeister on Unsplash Hello fellow readers, I want to start this article [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/we-need-to-talk-about-pantone/">We need to talk about Pantone</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Hugo&#039;s Notes</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong><a href="http://pantone.com/">Pantone</a> </strong>is one of the most well-known companies in the design industry, they are the <strong>industry standard</strong> for color solutions and they have built a <strong>monopoly </strong>over their slice of the market, hence why we need to talk about them.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="684" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/mika-baumeister-PtabTe6iJ_8-unsplash-1024x684.jpg" alt="Pantone Formula Guide Catalog" class="wp-image-149" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/mika-baumeister-PtabTe6iJ_8-unsplash-1024x684.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/mika-baumeister-PtabTe6iJ_8-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/mika-baumeister-PtabTe6iJ_8-unsplash-768x513.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/mika-baumeister-PtabTe6iJ_8-unsplash-1536x1026.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/mika-baumeister-PtabTe6iJ_8-unsplash-2048x1368.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@mbaumi?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Mika Baumeister</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/white-green-and-blue-textile-PtabTe6iJ_8?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Unsplash</a></p>



<p>Hello fellow readers, I want to start this article by telling you that like many of you <strong>I really like Pantone</strong> and I really like their color system, but as an active user of their products <strong>I recognize some of their mistakes.</strong> </p>



<p>The truth is their move to <strong>Pantone Connect</strong> left a very sour taste in everyone’s mouth, which is one of the reasons why we need to talk about them.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The Monopoly of Color</h2>



<p>Over the last few years, <strong>Pantone has built a huge monopoly on the color industry,</strong> thanks to their proprietary Matching System used universally in various industries. </p>



<p>Although some people say that their intellectual property is a <strong>legal mess,</strong> I believe it’s important we focus on the fact <strong>they have basically no competition.</strong></p>



<p>It’s funny to go back and see how the company evolved, some things have changed but their main product hasn’t changed at all – <strong>the system.</strong> It’s also interesting to talk with someone like my <a href="/my-blogging-story-why-i-started-and-how-you-can-start-right-now/"><strong>dad</strong></a> and realize that there used to be a point in time when they gave away formula guide catalogs for free.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Invaluable tools for creatives, the standardization of color, and a subscription model for their worst innovation to date have all been the major factors that led to the monopoly they built.</h4>



<p>To put this in very simple terms <strong>what can we do without Pantone? Pretty much nothing.</strong></p>



<p>Look, this article isn’t just to talk about them in a negative light, <strong>I do like Pantone, I do like their color system, and I do like the fact they have standardized color. </strong>It’s useful and it makes sense.</p>



<p>Although they can do anything they want with their product, the<strong> lack of competition</strong> means<strong> they can also pull stuff like Pantone Connect </strong>and their fight with <a href="http://adobe.com/"><strong>Adobe</strong></a> without having much opposition –<strong> this is what actually leaves me worried.</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The whole Adobe and Pantone battle and why we all lost with it</h2>



<p>So many articles have been written on this topic one wonders if it even makes sense to talk about it any further. <strong>Their whole battle didn’t make sense at all and we all lost,</strong> including the companies involved in this mess.</p>



<p>Why? Because <strong>we lost a tool that was integrated</strong> and extremely useful and the two major parties involved lost huge amounts of reputation and clients.</p>



<p>I understand Pantone’s argument that<strong> “they have not updated the catalogs for ten years”</strong> and their need to be paid more money by Adobe and guarantee they update their catalogs, but <strong>what I don’t understand is why didn’t they just implement Pantone Connect as a part of Adobe software</strong> going forward. Judging by the amount of money they paid for Figma I’m sure Adobe could spend a few dollars making sure their software has all the tools we need.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">I’ll do you one even better if you are a competitor of Adobe, besides all the features you know we need, give Pantone a call to distribute your software with Connect. I’m sure Adobe would freak out a bit.</h4>



<p>Look <strong>I love both companies I really do</strong>, but give me a break we all lost and I think it’s very obvious how bad this whole situation is.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Why Pantone Connect doesn’t make sense</h2>



<p>If anyone that was involved in the process of development of Connect is reading,<strong> I’m sorry but your software just doesn’t work. Also, the whole business model of Connect doesn’t work.</strong></p>



<p>If you don’t pay a staggering amount of money their add-on, their website, and their app are basically <strong>completely useless</strong> since the only feature of their software most of us need is <strong>behind a paywall.</strong></p>



<p>What feature? <strong>To see color data.</strong> For example, let’s say I have a standard formula guide coated catalog and my logo uses the color Yellow C, <strong>if I want to go to their website and see the information of what the best corresponding CMYK and RGB values would be I can’t – unless I have Connect.</strong></p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">I know the existence of workarounds but the point I want to make is that this completely breaks Pantone’s mission of standardizing color when I have to be subscribed to just see what their recommended CMYK value for Yellow C would be.</h4>



<p>Oh, by the way, this also makes <strong>Formula Guide catalogs that aren’t the bridge set useless, </strong>since you have to pay thousands for the software. It also makes Connect useless for bridge buyers.</p>



<p>But the worst of all for Pantone is <strong>it doesn’t even make sense for any printer or design agency to even own Connect, </strong>if I’m for example designing a book and I need a specific Pantone color on a page I will just make it a garish color and tell my printer that page number X is to be printed in the Pantone Color of my choice.</p>



<p>This also leads to situations in which the printer for example has Connect but the agency doesn’t, so we always in one way or another go back to what I said.<strong> This didn’t happen when Pantone color books were a part of Adobe software, even if outdated.</strong></p>



<p>So, with this whole move,<strong> Pantone has built a completely useless software,</strong> with an average of 1.2 stars on Play Store for their app, and the formula guides, that aren’t from the bridge set, are also<strong> useless.</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Can Pantone solve this?</h2>



<p><strong>To be honest with you I think this is a problem very difficult to solve for them.</strong> It would need a complete redraw of their current strategy, but if they are up to it, I believe it’s a fixable problem.</p>



<p>First, they should try to <strong>mend their relationship with Adobe or make Connect an integrated part of a competitor&#8217;s software,</strong> this would make their product essential and it would be good for Adobe/The competitor and for them.</p>



<p>Of course, this means that Adobe or any other company <strong>would provide a good deal for Pantone</strong> and Pantone would relinquish their pricing model for their add-on. </p>



<p>They could even keep the subscription for the website and app, or perhaps create a premium model for the add-on and all the platforms with the free version being more generous.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">On their website, add-on and app make color data visible to everyone, the rest of the features you can hide behind a paywall.</h4>



<p>These changes could basically<strong> fix all their problems </strong>with their software ultimately leading to it being more useful and all their catalog selection being relevant again.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">On a final note, I believe we all as consumers should unite a little more against these issues, after all we are their user base</h2>



<p><strong>A few notes:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>I know Pantone Connect is offered for some time when you buy their Formula Guide Catalogs, but I still <strong>firmly believe </strong>right now their business model has affected the value proposition of both the base Formula Guide Catalogs and Connect itself.</li>



<li>These types of articles are meant to <strong>kickstart a conversation,</strong> so please leave your comments below</li>



<li>If you want to buy Formula Guide Catalogs I recommend <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Pantone-FORMULA-GUIDE-COATED-UNCOATED/dp/B0BJ13LVD4/ref=sr_1_4?crid=2SA8WHQT0X290&amp;keywords=pantone%252Bformula%252Bguide%252Bbridge&amp;qid=1698405823&amp;sprefix=pantone%252Bformula%252Bguide%252Bbridg%252Caps%252C148&amp;sr=8-4&amp;th=1&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=24ae9d0643e2b2942520404d7adb4d16&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325"><strong>these</strong></a></li>
</ul>



<p>You can read the article I wrote about Adobe <a href="/how-adobe-could-stop-piracy-right-now-and-why-they-are-not-doing-it/"><strong>here</strong></a>.</p>



<p>Thank you for reading, stay safe!</p>
<p>The post <a href="/we-need-to-talk-about-pantone/">We need to talk about Pantone</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Hugo&#039;s Notes</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/we-need-to-talk-about-pantone/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What I learned as a designer from these album covers</title>
		<link>/what-i-learned-as-a-designer-from-these-album-covers/</link>
					<comments>/what-i-learned-as-a-designer-from-these-album-covers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hugo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 12:14:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Album cover design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Code Orange]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Color theory]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Compositon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daft Punk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Red Hot Chili Peppers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Soundgarden]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Black Keys]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Typography]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=133</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Music is great, no doubt about that, and in this article, I want to explore some of my favorite album covers and what I learned from them as a designer. I have such a huge love for music I can’t even describe it, it’s just such a huge part of who I am! So obviously [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/what-i-learned-as-a-designer-from-these-album-covers/">What I learned as a designer from these album covers</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Hugo&#039;s Notes</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Music is great, no doubt about that, and in this article, <strong>I want to explore some of my favorite album covers and what I learned from them as a designer.</strong> I have such a huge love for music I can’t even describe it, it’s just such a huge part of who I am! So obviously when looking for inspiration out there I always love to look at new and old album covers.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/oleg-ivanov-7x4ngEfelyE-unsplash-1024x683.jpg" alt="Photo of a person filliping through vinyls at a store" class="wp-image-134" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/oleg-ivanov-7x4ngEfelyE-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/oleg-ivanov-7x4ngEfelyE-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/oleg-ivanov-7x4ngEfelyE-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/oleg-ivanov-7x4ngEfelyE-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/oleg-ivanov-7x4ngEfelyE-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@olegivanovpht?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Oleg Ivanov</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/person-checking-the-file-7x4ngEfelyE?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Unsplash</a></p>



<p><strong>What kind of music do you listen to while you work? </strong>For me it’s always something kind of relaxing but with a good beat so it helps me to focus. </p>



<p>As I’m writing this I’m listening to <strong>Daft Punk</strong> albums because I’ve been having this huge nostalgia trip, and I’m such a huge fan of the robots! <strong>Please do leave your favorite albums in the comments below, I would love to find new music to listen to!</strong></p>



<p>Anyways, with this article I want to dive into some of my <strong>favorite albums,</strong> talking about their cover designs and how I’ve used them as a learning tool for stuff like composition, color combinations, layout, etc. </p>



<p><strong>There is a lot we can learn from our day-to-day activities</strong> and as designers it’s basically essential that you look at everything with an eagle eye. Sometimes I find myself analyzing a weird milk carton or something random and there’s a lot to take away from these little things. </p>



<p>So, take this article as a <strong>call for action,</strong> look at stuff around you with a designer approach and you will see what I’m talking about!</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">In a nutshell these will be the album covers I’m going to talk about:</h4>



<ul>
<li><strong>Daft Punk</strong> &#8211; Discovery</li>



<li><strong>Soundgarden </strong>&#8211; Badmotorfinger</li>



<li><strong>Code Orange</strong> &#8211; The Above</li>



<li><strong>The Black Keys</strong> &#8211; Brothers</li>



<li><strong>Red Hot Chili Peppers</strong> &#8211; By the Way</li>
</ul>



<p>Also, a quick note, if you have any albums, you would love me to talk about, please leave a comment or write me an email, always open to suggestions!</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Daft Punk &#8211; Discovery</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="592" height="600" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/R-2879-1236035472.jpg" alt="Discovery by Daft Punk album cover" class="wp-image-135" style="aspect-ratio:0.9866666666666667;width:750px;height:auto" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/R-2879-1236035472.jpg 592w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/R-2879-1236035472-296x300.jpg 296w" sizes="(max-width: 592px) 100vw, 592px" /></figure>



<p>Album Cover image from <a href="https://www.discogs.com/">Discogs</a></p>



<p>Released on <strong>March 12, 2001</strong> &#8211; Discovery is the second studio album by the iconic French duo<strong> Daft Punk.</strong> This album was a cornerstone for electronic music and a master class on sampling techniques. </p>



<p>It also had a movie released in 2003, serving as a visual companion for the album named <strong>“Interstella 5555: The 5tory of the 5ecret 5tar 5ystem”,</strong> this movie was animated by <strong>Toei Animation</strong>, and I would recommend you watch it and experience it.</p>



<p>To me this is <strong>one of my favorite albums of all time,</strong> it’s basically perfect and its album cover is incredibly iconic, I would even consider it a <strong>landmark</strong> of pop culture.</p>



<p>The previous album Homework also had such an interesting cover which like Discovery’s is a <strong>photograph!</strong> Yeah, I was also mind blown!</p>



<p>The Daft Punk logo which is also iconic, and the center piece of both albums was actually designed by <strong>Guy-Man</strong>, the gold robot. Although it may look 3d it actually isn’t this album cover was done using liquid metal by photographer <strong><a href="https://www.mitch.fr/">Mitch Feinberg.</a></strong></p>



<p>Unfortunately, I couldn’t really find a lot of information around about the exact process, but <strong>I sent an email to Mitch to try and figure it out.</strong> </p>



<p>If I learn anything new from him, <strong>I will write an article about it!</strong></p>



<p>There is a lot we can learn from this cover, but my <strong>main takeaway</strong> is that we should try and find ways to do our work more physically, nowadays we are bound to technology, and although it’s awesome that we have ways of doing stuff that we didn’t had 20 years ago sometimes <strong>being out there experimenting with materials and different processes of what we are used to, may translate in a very interesting result </strong>that we were not expecting.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Soundgarden &#8211; Badmotorfinger</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="600" height="600" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/R-2499366-1523173854-2423.jpg" alt="Badmotorfinger by Soundgarden Album Cover" class="wp-image-137" style="aspect-ratio:1;width:750px;height:auto" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/R-2499366-1523173854-2423.jpg 600w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/R-2499366-1523173854-2423-300x300.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/R-2499366-1523173854-2423-150x150.jpg 150w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></figure>



<p>Album Cover image from <a href="https://www.discogs.com/">Discogs</a></p>



<p>Badmotorfinger is such an iconic album, released on October 8, 1991, by <strong>Soundgarden</strong> it quickly became an historic part of the grunge movement.</p>



<p>What makes the cover of this album so cool is the <strong>typography and the color combinations</strong>. I absolutely love it and I think you and I can learn a lot from it. </p>



<p>Red, yellow and purple are three colors that don’t make much sense but when put together they just work.</p>



<p>The main takeaway is to<strong> experiment with color and overall composition of elements,</strong> sometimes we tend to get stuck with grids or formulas that we have learned, and we could experiment and get amazing results. </p>



<p><strong>Formulas are good but sometimes we need to explore beyond them.</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Code Orange – The above</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="599" height="546" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/R-28429588-1697995453-7695.jpg" alt="The Above by Code Orange Album Cover" class="wp-image-138" style="aspect-ratio:1.0970695970695972;width:750px;height:auto" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/R-28429588-1697995453-7695.jpg 599w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/R-28429588-1697995453-7695-300x273.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 599px) 100vw, 599px" /></figure>



<p>Album Cover image from <a href="https://www.discogs.com/">Discogs</a></p>



<p>First, let me say I love <strong>Code Orange,</strong> if you haven’t listened to their stuff check it out. I was a huge fan of their older album cover designs. </p>



<p><strong>Bold colors, bold typography it just worked.</strong></p>



<p>I think The Above was a nice <strong>improvement</strong> on their formula for album cover design and the overall vinyl set looks awesome.</p>



<p>I really think<strong> composition</strong> is a big takeaway from this cover, the focus on the image and the overall graphic treatment is also a very interesting point.</p>



<p>What I takeaway from this is that we sometimes avoid using simple compositions, but <strong>this album turns a very simple composition which is very effective and levels it up with the graphic treatmen</strong>t. So don’t be afraid of using effective more simple compositions, embrace white space and experiment with effects/digital treatment.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The Black Keys &#8211; Brothers</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="600" height="600" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/R-2284952-1626530490-7581.jpg" alt="Brothers by The Black Keys Album Cover" class="wp-image-139" style="aspect-ratio:1;width:750px;height:auto" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/R-2284952-1626530490-7581.jpg 600w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/R-2284952-1626530490-7581-300x300.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/R-2284952-1626530490-7581-150x150.jpg 150w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></figure>



<p>Album Cover image from <a href="https://www.discogs.com/">Discogs</a></p>



<p>Brothers is the sixth studio album of <strong>The Black Keys </strong>released on May 18, 2010. This album cover became an instant classic, red, black, white and Cooper Black – <strong>what more could we ask for!</strong></p>



<p>I really do think it’s perhaps one of the<strong> most iconic albums covers of the 2010s,</strong> alongside AM by <strong>Artic </strong>Monkeys. Albums that just embraced simplicity and showed that sometimes less is more.</p>



<p>If you must take any album here and use it as an example of what an iconic album cover can look like I would recommend Brothers. Again, the same points I previously mentioned apply here, composition, color, typography, embracing white space. <strong>Do I need to say more?</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Red Hot Chili Peppers – By the way</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="600" height="600" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/R-1162737-1197254678.jpg" alt="By the Way by The Red Hot Chili Peppers Album Cover" class="wp-image-140" style="aspect-ratio:1;width:750px;height:auto" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/R-1162737-1197254678.jpg 600w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/R-1162737-1197254678-300x300.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/R-1162737-1197254678-150x150.jpg 150w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></figure>



<p>Album Cover image from <a href="https://www.discogs.com/">Discogs</a></p>



<p>Arguably my favorite band, I just had to mention them. Their eighth studio album <strong>By the Way </strong>was released July 9, 2002.</p>



<p>I talked about breaking formulas before and experimentation, but I really do think the By the Way album cover is probably one of the best examples of this. <strong>It’s incredibly expressive and features a very interesting typography treatment too.</strong></p>



<p>If had to take any lesson from it, it would be the same that I took from Discovery, <strong>to experiment with materials, get away from the computer and try stuff out.</strong> I don’t really like to paint or draw but sometimes we need to get uncomfortable to create unique stuff.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">On a final note, the main takeaways here are to experiment with design elements, get uncomfortable, less is more, formulas are good and sometimes breaking them is also good.</h2>



<p>This is about it, I know this wasn’t very extensive, this was as I said in the beginning to just make the point that you should look at things differently and take lessons from them.</p>



<p>I hope you found this article useful, please if you have any suggestions leave a comment below, I will try to read and answer them all!</p>



<p>Also, you can read the previous <a href="/5-things-every-design-student-needs-to-hear/"><strong>article here!</strong></a></p>



<p>Thank you for reading, I hope you enjoyed!</p>
<p>The post <a href="/what-i-learned-as-a-designer-from-these-album-covers/">What I learned as a designer from these album covers</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Hugo&#039;s Notes</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/what-i-learned-as-a-designer-from-these-album-covers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 things every design student needs to hear</title>
		<link>/5-things-every-design-student-needs-to-hear/</link>
					<comments>/5-things-every-design-student-needs-to-hear/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hugo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 10:48:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[college]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[people]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=122</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As a recently graduated graphic designer, kick-starting my career, there are certain things that If I was starting all over again, I would tell myself, so here are 5 things that I believe every design student needs to hear. Photo by Unseen Studio on Unsplash Hello fellow readers, today I wanted to talk with those [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/5-things-every-design-student-needs-to-hear/">5 things every design student needs to hear</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Hugo&#039;s Notes</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As a <strong>recently graduated graphic designer</strong>, kick-starting my career, there are certain things that If I was starting all over again, I would tell myself, so here are <strong>5 things that I believe every design student needs to hear.</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/unseen-studio-s9CC2SKySJM-unsplash-1024x683.jpg" alt="Image of a person holding a pen related to the article name - 5 things that every design student needs to hear " class="wp-image-123" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/unseen-studio-s9CC2SKySJM-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/unseen-studio-s9CC2SKySJM-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/unseen-studio-s9CC2SKySJM-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/unseen-studio-s9CC2SKySJM-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/unseen-studio-s9CC2SKySJM-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@craftedbygc?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Unseen Studio</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/person-writing-on-brown-wooden-table-near-white-ceramic-mug-s9CC2SKySJM?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Unsplash</a></p>



<p>Hello fellow readers, today I wanted to talk with those of you that are <strong>currently in college or thinking of going to college and studying design</strong>. My studying journey was good, I was a fairly successful student, I didn’t exactly fail any classes, but <strong>there is always room for improvement.</strong> Although my learning chapter isn’t exactly done, as I intend to eventually get a master’s degree, I feel like I can share with you valuable information, so here it is, <strong>my top 5 things that you and every design student needs to hear.</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">1 – Understand what college for designers means and take the most out of it</h2>



<p>I’ve read so many articles in the past about college for designers and <strong>if it’s worth it or if it’s foolish</strong> to even go to college for design. In my opinion this is kind of a <strong>silly question.</strong> The reason being that it simply varies from person to person. <strong>I’ve met amazing designers who went to college and amazing designers who didn’t and were self-taught.</strong></p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">If you can afford it and are in this should I go or shouldn’t I go situation, I will always answer the same thing – go for it! </h4>



<p>If this is an <strong>area that you actually like,</strong> University is going to be awesome for you, mainly because you will spend countless hours<strong> with experts</strong> in their fields! That’s a lot of value. Also, in the increasingly saturated market of graphic designers, having a degree sometimes <strong>will influence</strong> a lot of recruiters to even consider you, if candidate A and B are equal in terms of portfolio, soft skills, etc… but one holds a degree and the other one doesn’t, it’s simply the <strong>deciding factor that’s going to take you out.</strong></p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">On the other hand, If you are being forced to go by your parents or If you just want to go to university studying design because you want to hold a degree – simply don’t go. </h4>



<p>Choose another option instead. I can’t really recommend you any specific course, but I guarantee you <strong>design isn’t the way,</strong> If I were in your shoes, I would just see <strong>what course</strong> translated into the job that pays the <strong>highest.</strong></p>



<p>If you are actually interested in going to university studying design because you have a passion for it, I want to help you understand <strong>what exactly you are getting out of it.</strong> As I previously mentioned professors that are experts in their fields is going to be the main advantage of taking a degree.</p>



<p>If you expect to learn software and stuff like that you are wrong, <strong>that’s going to be your homework</strong>. </p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">The main purpose of any design program in the world is to teach you the fundamentals and help you develop upon them. </h4>



<p>By the end you should expect to <strong>master the concepts</strong> you learned and how to <strong>apply them.</strong> Don’t expect classes about how to use illustrator 101, yes they exist but a lot of times they do not add any significant knowledge besides what you can see on youtube.</p>



<p>As a student I had colleagues in all the above-mentioned situations, but the main reason I became a standout student is because <strong>I understood the system and what it means to go to college for design.</strong> <strong>I needed to be able to form connections</strong> with those that were teaching me so that I could get the <strong>most value </strong>out of it. Of course, this means that you need to be an <strong>exemplary class member,</strong> don’t miss class, deliver work on time, don’t take shortcuts and <strong>be serious.</strong></p>



<p>The number of students I’ve met who wasted years of their lives and finished courses <strong>knowing nothing</strong> is genuinely <strong>hard to believe. </strong>All because they missed classes, went partying, had zero sense of responsibility and were genuinely uninterested.</p>



<p><strong>You can live your life the way you want </strong>and although I was one of top students of my class while I had two jobs and didn’t even complain <strong>I’m not saying you need to do the same.</strong> Just make sure you are happy with the options you make <strong>now and later.</strong> Everything you do eventually comes around, <strong>it’s a cycle.</strong></p>



<p>The message that I want to share with you in this point is simple, <strong>think about your decisions</strong> and how it affects you.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">2 – Be curious, make questions, solve problems and create new ones</h2>



<p>The first question that really got me extremely curious in university was <strong>“What is design?&#8221;</strong>, I was so speechless and surprised with the fact that <strong>I couldn’t find the words to explain what design is,</strong> to me it was something around the lines of making logos, talking with clients, making magazines, books and other stuff. The answer that our teacher gave us was a simple one, but it blew my mind <strong>“design is solving problems”.</strong></p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Why am I reminiscing on this? Because that moment was important to me, I learned for the first-time what design was all about and I was curious to know more.</h4>



<p>The first tip that I want to give you in this second point is a simple one –<strong> be curious.</strong> Curiosity fuels creativity, make questions, foolish questions, don’t be afraid of being curious and asking around, this is what takes your learning from good to great. I<strong>nvolving yourself is an important step,</strong> talent without curiosity, without questions is just wasted potential. I’ve met average students that became great designers because they were curious and made questions. <strong>Don’t be afraid!</strong></p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">At university you will solve problems, a lot of them, these are going to be given to you by your teachers, but are you going to be that person that sticks with just the program? </h4>



<p>University is about <strong>exploration</strong> and figuring stuff out and that ties up with curiosity, so <strong>be curious, solve problems,</strong> but also and perhaps most importantly<strong> create new problems</strong> that you can solve by yourself.</p>



<p>This isn’t as difficult as it sounds, to me I did this by <strong>finding competitions</strong> that I could be a part of, by <strong>kickstarting certain projects </strong>or by <strong>learning new software or techniques</strong> that weren’t taught to me. </p>



<p>I did all of this after-school stuff whilst having <strong>two jobs,</strong> so you do not have any possible excuse besides being lazy. <strong>Get up, do it, now!</strong></p>



<p>In an increasingly saturated market where everyone who uses canva thinks they are designers <strong>it’s difficult to stand out</strong> so if you pickup up things like web development, 3d, motion design, video editing, etc… <strong>in your free time,</strong> when you start searching for a job <strong>a door will eventually more easily open</strong> for you. I know this because<strong> only a month or two after finishing my degree</strong> I already was doing an internship, perhaps it wasn’t what I wanted to initially do, but a door was open and that’s my point.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">3 – Always carry a usb drive</h2>



<p>Okay, this is kind of just me being a little mad at some of my fellow university colleagues, but for god sakes <strong>buy a usb drive!</strong> They are cheap nowadays and you are going to need them to carry files around for a variety of purposes, even if it is to just figure out minimum dimensions for a logo. <strong>Don’t be that person that doesn’t have a usb drive </strong>or an external hard drive and just ask if someone has it, it’s foolish!</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">In my opinion if you carry around a laptop with good storage a smaller usb drive is all you need, if you use university computers then I recommend you get an external hard drive. </h4>



<p>It really <strong>depends on your use case,</strong> but always have backups of your projects. <strong>I’m serious,</strong> it’s unprofessional and very realistic the number of times I listened to someone say, <strong>“I just lost all of my work for X project because my pc broke”</strong>, don’t be like this you have zero excuse when hard drives exist, and cloud storage exist.</p>



<p>Also, to make it simple for you <strong>here are some suggestions at different price points,</strong> all the links will be <strong>affiliated </strong>– always <strong>do your own research on stuff you buy,</strong> don’t simply take mine or others recommendations as the rule.</p>



<p><strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Kingston-DataTraveler-Exodia-128GB-DTX/dp/B08JD4TBM3/ref=sr_1_4?crid=3TGO88RNB8TE1&amp;keywords=usb%252Bkingston&amp;qid=1697706811&amp;sprefix=usb%252Bkingston%252Caps%252C190&amp;sr=8-4&amp;th=1&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=a291591cfdb9ed5aa0039df482045bcd&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325">Kingston DataTraveler Exodia</a></strong> – I have a few of these, I don’t know if it’s an exclusive deal to Portugal, but I bought mine in a kit that came with two, so do research on that. <strong>They are really good for the money</strong> I use them almost every day, no complaints, Kingston hit me up, I like your products.</p>



<p><strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08GTYFC37/ref=twister_B0C6YZGJFH?_encoding=UTF8&amp;th=1&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=5b949e90b0315a238043d629b5d7c020&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325">SanDisk Portable SSD</a></strong> – A few options here in terms of what storage you get, see what fits your budget, but 2TB usb 3.2 up to 1050MB/s at $119.99 feels like a decent deal to me.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">4 – Find time to live life</h2>



<p>In a period of time that’s going to be tense,<strong> find the time to live your life.</strong> This probably would be one of the biggest tips I would give to myself looking back. </p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">I always have a very serious relationship with my work and sometimes I forget that I must live my life. </h4>



<p>For the years I was in college I had basically <strong>no personal time</strong> and this affected my <strong>mental health,</strong> but now as an older individual I have learned that you must have personal time and I really do value my moments of relaxation a lot. So, if you are starting college, <strong>work hard, but find time to chill a little,</strong> watch a movie, read a book, paint, take care of plants, work out, I don’t know what fits your mood. </p>



<p>I will say this, in the minuscule time I had for myself <strong>I always worked out </strong>because it kept my mental health in check, so if you don’t currently do any form of exercise <strong>that’s my recommendation.</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">5 – If you don’t fit in with everybody else, you’re probably in the right track</h2>



<p>There is such a need that people in general have to fit in that <strong>I personally don’t get.</strong> People are quick to try and form groups. Perhaps this is something more personal, but I never quite <strong>liked the idea of forming a group and putting people </strong>aside, even worse is when people retroactively choose to be jerks about it.</p>



<p>I always tried to be nice and helpful to others and to connect with everyone and be an open book, but these types of things <strong>make me want to just be on my shell. </strong>This is perhaps why I have very few friends and even fewer best friends.</p>



<p>On my university years I never quite fitted in with my classmates and I honestly think most of them didn’t really like me a lot, but I was not searching for their approval &#8211; so I kind of get them! I just did my own thing and if someone wanted help or to talk, I didn’t have a problem with that, I just didn’t offer shortcuts, that was my rule.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">I’m telling you this not because I want your compassion but because I want to tell you something that I never see people telling each other. You don’t need a group, you can be alone and find success, if you don’t like people’s attitudes or behaviors don’t join them. Let them be the ones to find you.</h4>



<p>On another note, people can and will be jerks there is simply no way of avoiding it, even I am not a hero, and I was a jerk a few times. It’s life, not everyone is perfect, that’s what makes us human. </p>



<p>Although there are <strong>those who apologize and those who don’t.</strong> The takeaway of this point is that you can be yourself, <strong>you don’t need others approvals, you don’t need to join people that you don’t want to be around and you definitely don’t need to agree with something you do not believe.</strong> So please fellow readers be aware of others humans!</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">On a final note, and because depression is a real thing among students, please feel free to contact me if you need someone to not judge you and just talk.</h2>



<p>I hope these five tips help you on your journey. <strong>If you have tips</strong> for others or any opinion about this article <strong>please do leave a comment bellow!</strong> I will try to read and answer them all!</p>



<p>If you are new to the blog, I recommend reading this <a href="/my-blogging-story-why-i-started-and-how-you-can-start-right-now/"><strong>article!</strong></a></p>



<p>Also, if you want more content, please do consider checking out my social media platforms!</p>



<p>Thank you for reading, I hope you enjoyed!</p>
<p>The post <a href="/5-things-every-design-student-needs-to-hear/">5 things every design student needs to hear</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Hugo&#039;s Notes</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/5-things-every-design-student-needs-to-hear/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>My Blogging Story: Why I Started and How You Can Start Right Now</title>
		<link>/my-blogging-story-why-i-started-and-how-you-can-start-right-now/</link>
					<comments>/my-blogging-story-why-i-started-and-how-you-can-start-right-now/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hugo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 16:30:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Change]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cloudflare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Domain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dreamer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dreaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Father]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Graphic Designer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Medium]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Platform]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Portugal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WordPress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=70</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>If you are reading this hello there! My name is Hugo and this is the first ever article I am writing for my blog. Writing isn’t easy, as a matter of fact, I haven’t actively written anything in ages, well at least in a longer format and not notes in my notebook. With this in [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/my-blogging-story-why-i-started-and-how-you-can-start-right-now/">My Blogging Story: Why I Started and How You Can Start Right Now</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Hugo&#039;s Notes</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>If you are reading this hello there! <strong>My name is Hugo </strong>and this is the first ever article I am writing for my blog. Writing isn’t easy, as a matter of fact, I haven’t actively written anything in ages, well at least in a longer format and not notes in my notebook. With this in mind hopefully I can take you through my blogging origin story and explain why I started and <strong>how you can start right now!</strong> A question for sure arises to you fellow reader –<strong> why?</strong> Well, this isn’t exactly the easiest question to answer but my answer can be scaled down to one simple fact – <strong>I am a dreamer!</strong> </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large wp-duotone-unset-1"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="768" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/nick-morrison-FHnnjk1Yj7Y-unsplash-1024x768.jpg" alt="a laptop and a cup on a table with the purpose of showing what your setup could be as someone starting their blog right now" class="wp-image-101" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/nick-morrison-FHnnjk1Yj7Y-unsplash-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/nick-morrison-FHnnjk1Yj7Y-unsplash-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/nick-morrison-FHnnjk1Yj7Y-unsplash-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/nick-morrison-FHnnjk1Yj7Y-unsplash-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/nick-morrison-FHnnjk1Yj7Y-unsplash-2048x1536.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@nickmorrison?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Nick Morrison</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/FHnnjk1Yj7Y?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Unsplash</a></p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">In this article you are going to learn a little about the person behind the project &#8211; basically I&#8217;ll tell you why I started my blogging journey and how you can start yours!</h4>



<p>My name as I previously mentioned is <strong>Hugo Carvalho</strong> and I’m a graphic designer from Portugal. Although I’m still at the very beginning of my career I’ve already had incredible experiences thanks to the fact I was always involved with <strong>volunteering</strong> and activist organizations from a very young age.</p>



<p>My passion for volunteering and changing the world is as old as my passion for <strong>design</strong>, so it only makes sense<strong> I believe I can join both</strong> in one way or another.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Like father like son</h2>



<p>I think a big part of telling you my blogging and personal story is related to the relationship I have with my dad –<strong> he’s awesome!</strong> </p>



<p>Although not present in most of childhood he was and is a great parent, example and leader, he was the one who initially years ago <strong>made me want to become a designer</strong>, although to be honest at the time I didn’t knew it at all. </p>



<p>Let me explain &#8211; my father has worked for the biggest printers in Portugal such as Lidergraf and Naveprinter as one of the very best printers they had.</p>



<p>So as the story goes, one day my mom decided to take me to visit my dad late at work and this was basically <strong>officially the first time I fell in love with design</strong> as he showed me the huge rolls of paper, proofs of what he was printing, pantone reference books and of course the magnifying lens they use for proofing the projects.</p>



<p>Looking back to it now as I’m writing this it’s funny how life has turned out and how we basically have a bunch of topics to talk about and we even could work together at the same company. It’s truly as the saying goes – <strong>like father like son</strong>.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The boy who dreamed</h2>



<p>I’m such a huge dreamer and I’m not telling you this lightly <strong>I truly have a big relationship with dreaming.</strong> </p>



<p>It makes me happy knowing that even if I can’t sometimes make all my dreams happen, I still continue to push new dreams into the equation,<strong> it’s a big part of who I am and what defines me.</strong></p>



<p>When I was young, I would frequently imagine the world in the future, besides the fact that I thought flying cars would be around already I also dreamt about a different society than what we have now. A <strong>fairer, more equal world</strong> where humans would co-exist – no wars, no homelessness, no discrimination.</p>



<p>Perhaps I dreamt and still dream too high but, in many ways, I hope to die knowing the world that little Hugo imagined was not just a mere dream.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Why Design = Change</h2>



<p>One of my goals as a <strong>designer who cares about the world </strong>that surrounds him is to show that design has changed the world and can change the world, making it a better place. Although this isn’t the main reason why I’ve started this blog it hopefully helps to explain my thought process.</p>



<p><strong>Design = Change</strong> is eventually one of my ultimate long-term dreams turned goals that I see culminating in a book about design for social change, the blog definitely helps with my writing situation but this is a long-term idea and concept that I want to explore.</p>



<p>So hopefully now that you know<strong> </strong>a part of<strong> my story</strong> you can see what I mean and expand upon this concept in your own blogging story, but I still have to explain you why I started and how you can start right now &#8211; stay tuned!</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Why I began a blog?</h2>



<p>Well now we are reaching to an interesting part of my blogging story, so let me tell you how I started so we can get to the good part where I tell you how you can start <strong>right now!</strong> </p>



<p>Recently I finished my bachelor’s degree in graphic design and after trying and failing to move to another country and get into a design agency (I will release an article about this one day) I stayed in Portugal and I’m now doing a nine-month internship in a multinational company at their marketing department, alongside this I’m kickstarting my own design studio (it&#8217;s still in early development).</p>



<p>This blog is in many ways a way for me to <strong>express myself</strong>, to <strong>share my struggles</strong>, to <strong>inspire</strong> and hopefully one day to <strong>achieve a certain level of establishment</strong> like the designers I respect and are inspired by. Hey maybe one day I’m even invited to talk at a TED talk or an event – <strong>the sky isn’t the limit for this dreamer!</strong></p>



<p>Also in a day and age where short-form copy paste mindless boring content is the mainstream on social media and other platforms, <strong>writing a blog feels truly refreshing.</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How I started and how you start a blog now</h2>



<p>Do you want to start your own blog? Don’t worry this is going to be my <strong>nonsense guide on how the hell I figured this out </strong>so the only thing stopping you from writing a blog about your mom’s cookies online is yourself, also a disclaimer, I’m not talking about stuff that you can easily watch in one of the videos I’m going to link bellow like “How to make a website with WordPress”.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">First you will need to figure out two easy things</h4>



<ul>
<li>Figure out what you want to talk about</li>



<li>Figure out if you are using a platform for blogs or if you are making it from scratch</li>
</ul>



<p>Figuring out what you are going to talk about should be the easy first step,<strong> just write about something that excites you</strong>. You love to cook with your mom? Write about that! You love to walk your dog? Write about that! </p>



<p>It’s easy <strong>just find something you love and write about that</strong>, on my own case I knew I wanted to talk about design and stuff related about design because guess what, it’s what I love – easy.</p>



<p>Choosing a platform becomes the <strong>pain the ass</strong> to be honest thanks to the increasing variety of platforms that exist on the market, so it’s genuinely going to <strong>need some research on your part</strong> but here is a small compilation of my own process and conclusions.</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.blogger.com/"><strong>Blogger</strong></a> if you want something incredibly easy but without much customization (also free if you don’t connect your own domain)</li>



<li><strong><a href="https://medium.com/">Medium</a> </strong>as either your main option or something secondary where you import your blog posts to hopefully generate more traffic</li>



<li>Build your own website with a powerful CMS, you have thousands of options here from <a href="http://squarespace.com/"><strong>squarespace</strong></a> to <a href="http://wix.com/"><strong>wix</strong></a> to <a href="http://wordpress.com/"><strong>wordpress</strong></a>, it’s like the multiverse – infinite options.</li>
</ul>



<h5 class="wp-block-heading">My current setup consists of a domain bought through <a href="https://www.cloudflare.com/"><strong>cloudflare</strong></a> pointing towards a <a href="https://vrlps.co/edsm8ck/cp"><strong>cloudways</strong></a> server with a <a href="https://wordpress.org/"><strong>wordpress</strong></a> installation.</h5>



<p>I’m not going to touch on what plugins I’m using and stuff like that because wordpress is a <strong>build your own scenario</strong> platform so it doesn’t make sense.</p>



<p>Some notes on my setup though, first <a href="https://www.cloudflare.com/"><strong>cloudflare</strong></a> has a small problem if you are on the completely free tier and you buy a domain with them – <strong>you cannot point to other nameservers.</strong> </p>



<p>This wasn’t a problem on my use case because I wanted to <strong>run my DNS towards <a href="https://www.cloudflare.com/">cloudflare</a> anyways </strong>but it excluded some web hosting providers that for some reason only were allowing me to add this domain if I changed my nameservers. </p>



<p>Second, this is probably not the cheapest solution but it works for me as I wanted to <strong>host two websites in the same server</strong>, my studio’s website which I haven’t made yet and my blog. Third<strong> I’m not a web developer</strong> so this setup probably isn’t the best – <strong>do your research!</strong></p>



<p>Also I’m using google analytics, google search console and <strong><a href="https://www.cloudflare.com/">cloudflare</a></strong> to analyze website performance and gmail’s API for the emails that get routed from the contact form (this was a pain to setup). In the future I’m also considering adding google ads in a non-intrusive way.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">On a final note, I just wanted to tell that<strong> I’m excited</strong> to write here and that you can of course expect me to keep you updated! More stuff about the studio coming soon!</h2>



<p>In terms of posting frequency, you can expect <strong>1 – 3 articles per week</strong>, sometimes more sometimes less, let’s go with the flow.</p>



<p>Also, if you want more content, please do consider checking out my <strong>social media</strong> platforms! Feel free to also leave a comment, I will try to read them all!</p>



<p>Thank you for reading, I hope you enjoyed my blogging story, understood how I started and hopefully got some motivation and knowledge on how you can start right now!</p>



<p>You can also contact me through <strong><a href="/contact/">here</a>!</strong> I&#8217;ll try to answer to emails as soon as possible!</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Some links (non-affiliate):</h4>



<ul>
<li><strong>freeCodeCamp</strong>: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9VPq1JxMfkA&amp;ab_channel=freeCodeCamp.org">How to Make a WordPress Blog and Website – Tutorial for Beginners 2022</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.cloudflare.com/"><strong>cloudflare</strong></a></li>



<li><strong><a href="https://vrlps.co/edsm8ck/cp">cloudways</a></strong> &#8211; Get $25 free hosting credit by signing up with my link.</li>
</ul>
<p>The post <a href="/my-blogging-story-why-i-started-and-how-you-can-start-right-now/">My Blogging Story: Why I Started and How You Can Start Right Now</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Hugo&#039;s Notes</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/my-blogging-story-why-i-started-and-how-you-can-start-right-now/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- plugin=object-cache-pro client=phpredis metric#hits=1732 metric#misses=35 metric#hit-ratio=98.0 metric#bytes=654914 metric#prefetches=0 metric#store-reads=85 metric#store-writes=3 metric#store-hits=180 metric#store-misses=29 metric#sql-queries=10 metric#ms-total=151.62 metric#ms-cache=12.07 metric#ms-cache-avg=0.1387 metric#ms-cache-ratio=8.0 -->
