<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Tips Archives - Hugo&#039;s Notes</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/tips/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/category/tips/</link>
	<description>Hugo&#039;s Notes: Design and other thoughts from a designer.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 13:14:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/cropped-favicon-32x32.webp</url>
	<title>Tips Archives - Hugo&#039;s Notes</title>
	<link>/category/tips/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>5 important things bloggers need to know</title>
		<link>/5-important-things-bloggers-need-to-know/</link>
					<comments>/5-important-things-bloggers-need-to-know/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hugo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 13:12:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tips]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=229</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>After about a month in the blogging scene I’ve learned a few important things that leveled up my content, today I want to share with you these 5 things that you and all bloggers need to know! Photo by Daniel Thomas on Unsplash Around a month ago I was in my bedroom thinking about writing [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/5-important-things-bloggers-need-to-know/">5 important things bloggers need to know</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Hugo&#039;s Notes</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>After about a month in the blogging scene <strong>I’ve learned a few important things that leveled up my content,</strong> today I want to share with you these 5 things that you and all bloggers need to know!</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/daniel-thomas-6_NXEMZbUq0-unsplash-1024x683.jpg" alt="Image of a person writing on a laptop" class="wp-image-230" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/daniel-thomas-6_NXEMZbUq0-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/daniel-thomas-6_NXEMZbUq0-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/daniel-thomas-6_NXEMZbUq0-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/daniel-thomas-6_NXEMZbUq0-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/daniel-thomas-6_NXEMZbUq0-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@soy_danielthomas?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Daniel Thomas</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/person-using-black-and-silver-laptop-computer-6_NXEMZbUq0?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Unsplash</a></p>



<p>Around a month ago I was in my bedroom thinking about writing and how I could improve my lackluster skills, suddenly an idea came to mind – <strong>what if I start a blog?</strong> I could write about anything that I felt truly passionate about and in return, I would improve my skills. <strong>Pretty good deal.</strong></p>



<p>After this first month of writing about several topics that varied from tips to my latest review of the MX Keys S Combo, I’ve been having a lot of fun. Most of my readers have been friends and random online strangers which I’m very grateful for! Seriously <strong>reading the few comments I got and seeing people interact with whatever I posted was genuinely awesome</strong> and I hope it just continues to grow onwards.</p>



<p>Although I want to be honest with you, I write not because I’m looking for approval or adoring fans but rather as a therapy for my creative mind – seriously.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Nowadays mindless content being pushed into our dopamine-filled heads is almost a day-to-day guarantee, so being able to slow down and write about whatever goes on in my mind is awesome.</h4>



<p>But anyway, if you haven’t read <a href="/my-blogging-story-why-i-started-and-how-you-can-start-right-now/"><strong>my very first article,</strong></a> I would recommend it as I go into why I started blogging and how you can also start your own thing.</p>



<p>Today’s article is in many ways <strong>a follow up, </strong>what are the lessons that I learnt from my first month blogging? Well in this article I’m going to share with you, fellow reader, 5 <strong>important things bloggers need to know.</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">1 – Besides you, no one cares</h2>



<p>I previously mentioned the impact of the current state of content and how blogging could be a refuge in this modern-day dopamine apocalypse,<strong> the truth is that fewer people are going to read whatever you write </strong>– consequences.</p>



<p>To me, this is fine, <strong>I wasn’t expecting my blog to become the next The New Yorker </strong>or to compete for the attention of people, but I very quickly realized that it was going to become truly, <strong>incredibly difficult to reach people.</strong></p>



<p>To add to the pressure point, I feel like most people who are even reading blogs are looking for solutions to problems,<em> they want to quickly get an answer.</em></p>



<p>In consequence, more thought-based articles like this one <strong>fall into oblivion a lot of the times, </strong>which I think is rather interesting.</p>



<p>As I previously said, to me this isn’t a problem,<strong> I write because I wanted a place where I could improve my writing skills and share some thoughts. </strong>I was not expecting a huge audience, and you shouldn’t as well!</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Write for the sake of writing, because it is a fun thing to do, not because it will be a foolish obligatory thing adding up to the 50 other foolish obligatory things you’re doing.</h4>



<p>If you are the only one who cares, accept and keep writing when you feel like it. I said I would write about 1-3 articles per week, I’ve managed to consistently write 2 articles every week, last week I was not feeling it and I simply didn’t write a second article. <strong>You must not feel obligated to do something that should be fun to do, I was not in the mood I simply did not wrote an article – period.</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">2 – Get to the point</h2>



<p><strong>People want solutions to problems they don’t have, </strong>they don’t have time, they don’t care about the person writing. Creating a piece of content that people will at least read means <strong>you have to get to the point. Even if it means writing shorter articles.</strong></p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">People usually like a well-paced story over a boring 2000-page eternal journey that never ends. So, give them that.</h4>



<p>But also write <strong>fun stuff, stuff that you would want to read and share with others. </strong>Keep it smart and simple.</p>



<p>Getting to the point is hard but don’t forget design school – <strong>less is more.</strong> Don’t go around 1000 words to say you really hate oranges,<strong> just say you hate oranges</strong> and explain why you hate oranges after that. People will be much more invested.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">3 – Pose questions and solve problems</h2>



<p>To me most articles I write either come from a question that I have, a problem that I wish was solved, or just an urge to write about something.</p>



<p>Out of all the posts I wrote the past month <strong>the ones I wrote that posed questions and offered solutions were the ones to get the most amount of engagement.</strong></p>



<p>So, the next time you write an article for your blog think about this, <strong>what problem do you have a solution for? What question do you have that others may also have?</strong></p>



<p>Humans are inherently curious beings, so like the little kid you once were,<strong> ask questions, lots of them.</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">4 – Be human</h2>



<p>In an age where <strong>most content you now see online is basically generated by AI,</strong> being human will in my view be very important in the future.</p>



<p><strong>Showing my human side is something that I never imagined I would struggle with, </strong>but I have come up with my own conclusions about that.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Write in the first person, address the audience, be direct, share experiences, and don’t be afraid of being silly.</h4>



<p>Throughout my articles, I really tried to employ these tactics in order for <strong>my blog to be or feel more human </strong>to whoever reads it. By talking about my dad on a post, my struggles as a student, or just simply by sharing a Spider-Man meme, <strong>suddenly what was once a robotic post now feels more human,</strong> more relatable, more me, more you.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">5 – What do you want to read?</h2>



<p>Although writing for the sake of writing is a good thing, no judging. <strong>Writing about something that you are interested in inherently allows you to understand people in your target audience.</strong></p>



<p>The next time you write an article don’t just think about what you want to write,<strong> think about what you would also like to read.</strong></p>



<p>Writing, like many things, is a constant exercise that takes time, takes practice and allows for development. <strong>My first articles probably weren’t that good,</strong> but they served a purpose – to allow me to grow.</p>



<p>If you take this into consideration, <strong>you will feel much more comfortable,</strong> writing will not be so much about an audience, but it will be more like this thing we do for us that others can be a part of.  </p>



<p>If you write what you want to read it will also provide you with more ideas, make you more invested and consequently <strong>make you create better articles.</strong></p>



<p>So, the next time you write, <strong>think about those who read!</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">On a final note, I would love for you to share your blog on the comment section below</h2>



<p>As part of the design community, I see this space as a place of sharing, so if you are also starting a blog or have your blog <strong>share it below,</strong> it could be a blog about anything, I’m interested to read what you write about in your free time.</p>



<p>Thank you for reading, as per usual, you can read the previous article <a href="/mx-keys-s-combo-review-is-it-worth-the-hype/"><strong>here</strong>.</a></p>



<p>See ya later alligator!</p>
<p>The post <a href="/5-important-things-bloggers-need-to-know/">5 important things bloggers need to know</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Hugo&#039;s Notes</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/5-important-things-bloggers-need-to-know/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The key skill every designer needs to learn in 2024</title>
		<link>/the-key-skill-every-designer-needs-to-learn-in-2024/</link>
					<comments>/the-key-skill-every-designer-needs-to-learn-in-2024/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hugo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 17:04:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[augmented reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blender]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[people]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[skill]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=218</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In a world of constant change, the design industry is continuously evolving, with these changes we must also evolve so in this article I will talk about the key skill every designer needs to learn in 2024. Photo by Jason Goodman on Unsplash In my last article, I talked about my vision for the future [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/the-key-skill-every-designer-needs-to-learn-in-2024/">The key skill every designer needs to learn in 2024</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Hugo&#039;s Notes</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In a world of constant change, <strong>the design industry is continuously evolving</strong>, with these changes <strong>we must also evolve </strong>so in this article I will talk about the <strong>key skill every designer needs to learn in 2024.</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/jason-goodman-Oalh2MojUuk-unsplash-1024x683.jpg" alt="Image of a group of designers working on a project" class="wp-image-220" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/jason-goodman-Oalh2MojUuk-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/jason-goodman-Oalh2MojUuk-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/jason-goodman-Oalh2MojUuk-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/jason-goodman-Oalh2MojUuk-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/jason-goodman-Oalh2MojUuk-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@jasongoodman_youxventures?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Jason Goodman</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/woman-placing-sticky-notes-on-wall-Oalh2MojUuk?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Unsplash</a></p>



<p><a href="/what-does-the-future-of-design-look-like/"><strong>In my last article,</strong></a> I talked about my vision for the future of design and <strong>how we are very close to massive changes in the industry.</strong> Out of the several things I wrapped my head around one stood out to me the most – <strong>the future is motion.</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Static is out, motion is in</h2>



<p>Over the last few years motion design undoubtedly has taken the world by storm, if we take a close look at the last 10 years, <strong>motion design has steadily, alongside UI/UX, become an increasingly important area of design.</strong></p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">From TV to smartphones to ads on the street, everything nowadays is slowly becoming less static. The new possibilities in terms of technology have been increasing the types of supports we can use motion in, to me motion will be a part of every designer’s skillset in a few years.</h4>



<p>In many ways,<strong> when we look at the world that surrounds us,</strong> more and more, <strong>we see static formats slowly disappearing. </strong>An example of this in Portugal recently has been the introduction of digital Mupis on bus stops.</p>



<p>What was once a place for a <strong>completely static poster</strong> is now basically a <strong>digital playground for motion design.</strong> This is just an example, but many more places are suffering these types of changes, from the introduction of the e-book to televisions replacing static posters in movie theaters, e<strong>verything is changing to become less static.</strong></p>



<p><strong>I challenge you to take a look around you</strong> and identify these small details in our day-to-day activities, you will most likely see different examples than the one I previously mentioned, <strong>you just need to keep your eyes wide open.</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The evolution of software and hardware</h2>



<p>Like the Mupis I was talking about technology in general has improved dramatically over the years. <strong>We are lucky to be a part of one of the most interesting generations ever.</strong></p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">If you took a look at the world 25 years ago it was a vastly different place in terms of technology, forget your high res Tv, your laptop, your smartphone, your high-speed internet connection and bring back the CRTs, the Nokia phones, the dial-up internet and all the other marvels of late 90s technology.</h4>



<p>My point is – <strong>there has been a dramatic change in technology in a very short time frame.</strong> Although nowadays its starting to slow down a bit <strong>the evolution of technology is as obvious as my name being Hugo.</strong></p>



<p>Over the last few years, a lot of these technological revolutions have turned out to be related to <strong>finding new ways of implementing screens into your life.</strong> Making them <strong>cheaper and easier to make</strong> has only translated into the <strong>propagation of screens to almost everything we use</strong> that involves some type of technology.</p>



<p>In the future Motion Design will be important as we move to an <strong>era of new supports</strong> like augmented and virtual reality, but also as we move to an era of <strong>full/increasing replacement of static media.</strong></p>



<p><strong>The world of advertising and media is already changing by the clock so we must evolve and adapt with the times. </strong>Accepting that motion is going to be a big part of your life is the first step.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The new age of social media</h2>



<p>Remember good old <strong>MSN,</strong> no? What about <strong>Hi5?</strong> Hey, do you even remember<strong> Facebook?</strong></p>



<p>It’s very strange how social media platforms have been changing over the years, but one thing that isn’t strange to me is <strong>how every single one of them started to get some type of way of showing you videos</strong>.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Instagram, X (rip Twitter), Facebook, TikTok, and others have one thing in common besides basically copying each other – the possibility of sharing videos.</h4>



<p>This fact <strong>single-handedly makes Motion Design even more important.</strong> If you want to stand out you can’t be static.</p>



<p>As we move into the future, platforms focused on video sharing seem to be slowly taking over,<strong> Motion Design in my eyes will play an essential role in the future of social media.</strong> Every brand, every product, everything really <strong>will seek to have motion attached to it.</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Animation has never been more accessible</h2>



<p>On one side we have an <strong>ever-expanding industry</strong> only increasing in the future, on the other, <strong>we have software that has become easier to use.</strong> We don’t need the mess that was Flash animation, nowadays we have <strong>After-effects,</strong> several 3d and 2d animation software, and of course the incredible <a href="http://blender.org/"><strong>Blender.</strong></a></p>



<p>Thanks to <strong>YouTube, platforms like Skillshare, and School of Motion</strong> learning Motion Design has never been <strong>cheaper and more accessible.</strong></p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">I have to say I really do like Blender, the community is incredible, and personally speaking, I see it taking over the industry standard Cinema 4D in the near future.</h4>



<p>The fact that a piece of software is so loved and remains free shows the type of people behind <strong>Blender </strong>and why it is<strong> the tool to learn </strong>if you are looking to learn 3D and animation.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="576" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/untitled-1024x576.png" alt="3d image of a credit card mockup" class="wp-image-219" style="width:750px;height:auto" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/untitled-1024x576.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/untitled-300x169.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/untitled-768x432.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/untitled-1536x864.png 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/untitled.png 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Cool Credit Card Mockup I made in Blender (I still have to figure out the whole animation thing)</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Why is motion design a key skill that every designer needs to learn in 2024?</h2>



<p>Last but not least on my to-talk list is the answer to the starting question of this article. <strong>It’s a key skill every designer should learn because motion design has never been easier and more important in our industry.</strong></p>



<p>Recently award-winning agencies such as <a href="http://studiodumbar.com/"><strong>Studio Dumbar</strong></a> and <a href="http://wolffolins.com/"><strong>Wolff Olins</strong></a> have been releasing successful project after successful project. The <strong>one key ingredient </strong>almost every project they share has in common is <strong>motion.</strong></p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">If you look at these agencies motion stands almost as a core component in every single project and its no coincidence that they have become two of the most popular agencies in the world.</h4>



<p>So, I suggest you <em>look </em><strong>around you, accept motion and work on your skillset, </strong>because believe me this will become the future.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">On a final note, here are a few suggestions if you want to get started with motion design</h2>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/@DerekElliott"><strong>Derek Elliot</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.schoolofmotion.com/"><strong>School of Motion</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/@blenderguru"><strong>Blender Guru</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/@BenMarriott"><strong>Ben Marriott</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/@SonduckFilm"><strong>SounduckFilm</strong></a></li>
</ul>



<p>Although on the shorter side, <strong>I do hope this article has at least made you interested in motion, </strong>don’t forget to leave a comment below I’m interested to read your opinions.</p>



<p>Think different. Make difference.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/the-key-skill-every-designer-needs-to-learn-in-2024/">The key skill every designer needs to learn in 2024</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Hugo&#039;s Notes</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/the-key-skill-every-designer-needs-to-learn-in-2024/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 Must-read books for designers</title>
		<link>/5-must-read-books-for-designers/</link>
					<comments>/5-must-read-books-for-designers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hugo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 14:28:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tips]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=206</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>If you are a designer or are interested in design start with these 5 must-read books for designers. In this article I will share with you some of my favorite design books and why I like them so much. Photo by Ugur Akdemir on Unsplash Hey everyone, lately I’ve been rereading a few design books [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/5-must-read-books-for-designers/">5 Must-read books for designers</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Hugo&#039;s Notes</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>If you are a designer or are interested in design start with these <strong>5 must-read books for designers.</strong> In this article I will share with you some of my favorite design books and why I like them so much.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/ugur-akdemir-XT-o5O458as-unsplash-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-207" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/ugur-akdemir-XT-o5O458as-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/ugur-akdemir-XT-o5O458as-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/ugur-akdemir-XT-o5O458as-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/ugur-akdemir-XT-o5O458as-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/ugur-akdemir-XT-o5O458as-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@ugur?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Ugur Akdemir</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/assorted-book-lot-XT-o5O458as?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Unsplash</a></p>



<p>Hey everyone, lately I’ve been rereading a few design books that I have around, mainly because of this article. Today I hope to share with you the <strong>5 books</strong> that, in my opinion, <strong>should be on everyone’s shelves.</strong></p>



<p>In a nutshell here are the books I’ll be talking about:</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.rit.edu/vignellicenter/sites/rit.edu.vignellicenter/files/documents/The%20Vignelli%20Canon.pdf"><strong>The Vignelli Canon</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="https://static.googleusercontent.com/media/fonts.google.com/en//knowledge/stop_stealing_sheep.pdf"><strong>Stop Stealing Sheep Find How Type Works</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Thinking-Type-2nd-revised-expanded/dp/1568989695/ref=sr_1_1?crid=27GQHNNEFZ9VA&amp;keywords=thinking+with+type&amp;qid=1699020278&amp;sprefix=thinking+with+type%252Caps%252C151&amp;sr=8-1&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=184a77f78f45bd64169dd654114b7bc4&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325"><strong>Thinking with Type</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Logotype-Mini-Michael-Evamy/dp/1780678576/ref=sr_1_1?crid=S5PBRRG10IKM&amp;keywords=logotype&amp;qid=1699020357&amp;sprefix=logotype%252Caps%252C149&amp;sr=8-1&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=d39f843df91e04fd7ed6eece49de6566&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325"><strong>Logotype</strong></a> &amp; <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Symbol-Mini-Steven-Bateman/dp/1780671849/ref=sr_1_3?crid=DFELVS6SDUBG&amp;keywords=symbol+book&amp;qid=1699020416&amp;sprefix=symbol+book%252Caps%252C154&amp;sr=8-3&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=0fd6771fd85e67e5b38493475b10967f&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325"><strong>Symbol</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="https://shop.itemzero.com/products/the-book-block/"><strong>The Book Block and The Book Cover</strong></a></li>
</ul>



<p>As per usual I would love to see what your suggestions for essential books are! Eventually, I would love to write another article on this topic, so <strong>send me your suggestions</strong> and they may be featured next time.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The Vignelli Canon</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="682" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/vignellicanon-1024x682.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-208" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/vignellicanon-1024x682.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/vignellicanon-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/vignellicanon-768x511.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/vignellicanon.jpg 1400w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Photo by David Hall</p>



<p>Written by the late iconic designer Massimo Vignelli, <strong>“The Vignelli Canon”</strong> is in my opinion of the most important design books ever made. It serves as a guide to the principles of what good design is while at the same time giving us incredible <strong>insights</strong> into Vignelli’s <strong>thought process, methodology, and philosophy.</strong></p>



<p>From the iconic list of 6 typefaces, I talked about in my <a href="/these-are-the-only-6-typefaces-you-need/"><strong>last article</strong></a> to the core ideas behind his designs, this book serves almost as a<strong> bible for anyone looking to become a designer.</strong></p>



<p>In an age where we are seeing more and more minimalist work being produced for the sake of being minimalist or style trends bringing back brutalism and maximalism, <strong>“The Vignelli Canon”</strong> is a nice reminder of what design isn’t and what it should be.</p>



<p>I truly believe everyone would love to read the lessons in this book, it is available to be bought <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Vignelli-Canon-Massimo/dp/3037782250/ref=sr_1_1?crid=2YODJL2ULJC05&amp;keywords=vignelli+canon&amp;qid=1699020710&amp;sprefix=vignelli+canon%252Caps%252C146&amp;sr=8-1&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=11ef91bc8d64483a31632b5eeabf7d0d&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325"><strong>here</strong></a> or totally free to download <a href="https://www.rit.edu/vignellicenter/sites/rit.edu.vignellicenter/files/documents/The%20Vignelli%20Canon.pdf"><strong>here.</strong></a> Amazingly, this book is<strong> completely free</strong> being yet another small detail that gives us a glimpse of the <strong>type of individual Vignelli was.</strong></p>



<p>Doing the research for this article I also came across <a href="https://soundcloud.com/designmatters/massimo-vignelli"><strong>this episode of the podcast Design Matters with Debbie Milman,</strong></a> although it was released 10 years ago, this episode still holds up and personally, I believe you will find a lot of value in it.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Stop Stealing Sheep Find How Type Works</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="682" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/stopstealingsheep-1024x682.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-209" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/stopstealingsheep-1024x682.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/stopstealingsheep-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/stopstealingsheep-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/stopstealingsheep.jpg 1061w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Photo by Erik Spiekermann</p>



<p>As a total fanboy, I really like this book written by also legendary designer and typographer <strong>Erik Spiekermann!</strong> &#8220;Stop Stealing Sheep Find How Type Works” is an <strong>incredible journey </strong>that leaves us understanding how important type is and how to use it.</p>



<p>This 4<sup>th</sup> edition is<strong> updated with a new chapter on variable typefaces,</strong> several examples on how to effectively communicate with type, and a full selection of new typefaces used and referenced throughout the book.</p>



<p>Although it’s a compact book it encourages reading and I guarantee every time you open it up you will find and learn something new.</p>



<p>This book is available to be <a href="https://shop.p98a.com/products/p98a-find-out-how-type-works-by-erik-spiekermann-4th-edition"><strong>bought through Erik’s experimental type gallery P98A</strong></a> and its also available for free on <a href="https://static.googleusercontent.com/media/fonts.google.com/en//knowledge/stop_stealing_sheep.pdf"><strong>Google Fonts,</strong></a> which is awesome!</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Thinking with type</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="682" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/thinkingwithtype-1024x682.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-210" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/thinkingwithtype-1024x682.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/thinkingwithtype-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/thinkingwithtype-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/thinkingwithtype-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/thinkingwithtype.jpg 2000w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Photo by Konstantinas Ladauskas</p>



<p>Do I have to say anything? Ellen Lupton’s iconic book <strong>“Thinking with Type”</strong> was released a long time ago but it still holds up as it is frequently updated by the author. Let’s be real your university probably had this book in their references and for a good reason!</p>



<p><strong>“Thinking with Type”</strong> is a comprehensive guide to topics such as font selection, spacing, grids, and layout design, providing practical advice and examples for designers.</p>



<p>I frequently find myself rereading this book and I learn something new every time!<strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Thinking-Type-2nd-revised-expanded/dp/1568989695/ref=sr_1_1?crid=27GQHNNEFZ9VA&amp;keywords=thinking+with+type&amp;qid=1699020278&amp;sprefix=thinking+with+type%252Caps%252C151&amp;sr=8-1&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=184a77f78f45bd64169dd654114b7bc4&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325">You can acquire a copy here.</a></strong> Unfortunately, there isn’t a free copy of this book I can link to you, perhaps one day <strong>Google Fonts</strong> will collaborate with Ellen, <strong>that would be awesome!</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Logotype &amp; Symbol</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="667" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/logotype.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-211" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/logotype.jpg 1000w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/logotype-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/logotype-768x512.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure>



<p>Photo by Inkbot Design</p>



<p>If you’re like me and many other designers in the world <strong>seeking inspiration and references is basically a part of our day-to-day routines.</strong> When we talk about branding projects<strong> having good references for inspiration that you can pull out at any time is also essential.</strong></p>



<p>While for many years the holy grail of logo reference has been a book called<strong> “Logo Modernism”</strong>, which is a mammoth of a book, today I want to tell you about the two alternatives <strong>“Logotype &amp; Symbol”.</strong></p>



<p>Like <strong>“Logo Modernism”</strong> these two books, which I personally think you should buy together, serve as a more digestible alternative. If you already own the mammoth you will find <strong>“Logotype &amp; Symbol”</strong> still useful as there isn’t much duplicated content between books.</p>



<p>Personally, I really like these and whenever I’m working on any kind of branding project, <strong>they are extremely useful,</strong> if you are in a team their size is also useful to share between people.</p>



<p>You can buy a <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Logotype-Mini-Michael-Evamy/dp/1780678576/ref=sr_1_1?crid=S5PBRRG10IKM&amp;keywords=logotype&amp;qid=1699020357&amp;sprefix=logotype%252Caps%252C149&amp;sr=8-1&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=d39f843df91e04fd7ed6eece49de6566&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325"><strong>copy here,</strong></a> which allows you to choose between a physical or a digital copy which is also cool!</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The Book Block and The Book Cover</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="684" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/thebookblock-1024x684.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-212" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/thebookblock-1024x684.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/thebookblock-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/thebookblock-768x513.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/thebookblock.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Photo by Luís Espinheira </p>



<p>Last but not least a suggestion that I’m sure you will love. <strong>“The Book Block and The Book Cover”</strong> are perfect books for anyone looking to work on editorial design, they are incredibly useful tools.</p>



<p>Created by Portuguese studio <strong>itemzero</strong> they present, in a very straight to the point useful way the key ingredients needed to design a great publication.</p>



<p>Explaining different techniques with a plethora of variations <strong>this book is in my view essential for anyone working in the industry.</strong></p>



<p>Last but not least for my Portuguese audience it also is multilingual which is awesome. You can acquire a copy <strong><a href="https://shop.itemzero.com/products/the-book-block/">here</a>,</strong> they frequently have discounts so stay alert!</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">On a final note, I hope you found these books useful and please remember to share your must-haves</h2>



<p>Today’s article was on the shorter side but I hope you truly found this information useful.</p>



<p>You can read the last article <strong><a href="/these-are-the-only-6-typefaces-you-need/">here</a>.</strong></p>



<p>Thank you for reading, stay safe and have fun!</p>
<p>The post <a href="/5-must-read-books-for-designers/">5 Must-read books for designers</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Hugo&#039;s Notes</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/5-must-read-books-for-designers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>These are the only 6 typefaces you need</title>
		<link>/these-are-the-only-6-typefaces-you-need/</link>
					<comments>/these-are-the-only-6-typefaces-you-need/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hugo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 14:24:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Typography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=179</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In the current day and age of design we have thousands and thousands of typefaces to choose from, so in this article following the lessons of modernist designers like Massimo Vignelli, I’m going to tell you the only 6 typefaces you need and that are the basis of my collection. Photo by Bruno Martins on [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/these-are-the-only-6-typefaces-you-need/">These are the only 6 typefaces you need</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Hugo&#039;s Notes</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In the current day and age of design we have <strong>thousands and thousands of typefaces to choose from,</strong> so in this article following the lessons of modernist designers like <strong>Massimo Vignelli,</strong> I’m going to tell you <strong>the only 6 typefaces you need and that are the basis of my collection.</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="682" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/bruno-martins-4cwf-iW6I1Q-unsplash-1024x682.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-185" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/bruno-martins-4cwf-iW6I1Q-unsplash-1024x682.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/bruno-martins-4cwf-iW6I1Q-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/bruno-martins-4cwf-iW6I1Q-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/bruno-martins-4cwf-iW6I1Q-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/bruno-martins-4cwf-iW6I1Q-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@brunus?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Bruno Martins</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/brown-and-black-wooden-cross-4cwf-iW6I1Q?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Unsplash</a></p>



<p>Hello designers, recently I’ve been rereading a few books and articles on typefaces, particularly the new <a href="https://www.neue.shop/fonts/neue-serie57"><strong>Neue series 57 made by Neue Type Foundry in collaboration with Erik Spiekermann.</strong></a> These books and articles made me think a lot about type design and how it has evolved so much over the years.</p>



<p>Particularly I’ve been also rereading the infamous <strong><a href="https://www.rit.edu/vignellicenter/sites/rit.edu.vignellicenter/files/documents/The%20Vignelli%20Canon.pdf">Vignelli canon written by Massimo Vignelli</a>,</strong> one of the most important designers in history. In the book Vignelli teaches us about his philosophy on design and <strong>shares with us</strong> his iconic list of the only <strong>6 typefaces you need,</strong> claiming that <strong>you can trash the rest.</strong></p>



<p>Rediscovering this made me think <strong>“Hmm would his list today be the same?”</strong> with the evolution of technology and design trends I imagine his list would also evolve with the times. The matter of the fact is <strong>it’s still a relevant list that all designers still talk about today!</strong></p>



<p>The way you should see this article is very simple – <strong>it’s my own view </strong>of what those 6 typefaces would be,<strong> not an updated Vignelli list,</strong> just my list.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">“In the new computer age the proliferation of typefaces and type manipulations represents a new level of visual pollution threating our culture. Out of thousands of typefaces, all we need are a few basic ones, and trash the rest. So come and see A Few Basic Typefaces” <em>– Massimo Vignelli</em></h2>



<p>In a nutshell here is Vignelli’s list:</p>



<ul>
<li>Garamond</li>



<li>Bodoni</li>



<li>Century Expanded</li>



<li>Futura</li>



<li>Times Roman</li>



<li>Helvetica</li>
</ul>



<p>This list in my view <strong>is still very viable</strong> but I don’t think a lot of these typefaces<strong> stand the test of time </strong>as good as they probably should, <strong>either they have been redesigned or there are just better options.</strong> <strong>Don’t take this opinion from just me,</strong> see what people like <strong>Erik Spiekermann</strong> think of <strong>Helvetica,</strong> probably the most iconic typeface ever made – <a href="https://spiekermann.com/en/helvetica-sucks/"><strong>“Helvetica sucks. It really wasn’t designed for small sizes on screens. Words like milliliter can be very difficult to decipher.”</strong></a></p>



<p>To me these 6 typefaces <strong>lack features that most designers need today,</strong> I’m not saying I can put together a better list, but <strong>here is my attempt:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://fonts.google.com/specimen/EB+Garamond?query=eb+garamond"><strong>Eb Garamond</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="https://fonts.google.com/specimen/Bodoni+Moda?query=bodoni+moda"><strong>Bodoni Moda</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="https://fonts.google.com/specimen/Playfair+Display"><strong>Playfair Display</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="https://fonts.google.com/specimen/Poppins?query=poppins"><strong>Poppins</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.edenspiekermann.com/insights/mozilla-fira-fox/"><strong>Fira Sans</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.fontshare.com/fonts/switzer"><strong>Switzer</strong></a></li>
</ul>



<p>A small note if you have your own list please tell me about it in the comment section, <strong>I would love to know!</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Eb Garamond</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="500" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/ebgaramond.png" alt="" class="wp-image-200" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/ebgaramond.png 1000w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/ebgaramond-300x150.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/ebgaramond-768x384.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure>



<p>Made as a <strong>revival of Claude Garamond’s original 1532 typeface,</strong> which is present on Vignelli’s list, this version was made for the digital age. The source for the letterforms comes from a scan of the <strong>“Berner Specimen”</strong> composed in 1592 by Conrad Berner.</p>



<p>Its letterforms are <strong>elegant and well-proportioned,</strong> striking a balance between classic aesthetics and modern legibility, making it <strong>suitable for various applications, including body text and headings.</strong></p>



<p>EB Garamond is versatile, offering different weights and styles.<strong> It&#8217;s also an open-source typeface!</strong></p>



<p>With an extensive character set, it supports various characters and diacritics, making it suitable for multilingual projects. <strong>Its attention to detail during the revival and refinement process ensures a high-quality typeface with consistent design features. </strong>EB Garamond works well in both print and digital contexts, thanks to its design that maintains its elegance and legibility in various sizes and applications.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Why is this typeface on my list?</h4>



<p>Like <strong>Vignelli</strong> it made sense to me to include Garamond although in my case a more updated version of it, <strong>it’s a perfect typeface for a variety of uses,</strong> it has a lower contrast between strokes but it exhibits a classic timeless design.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Bodoni Moda</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="500" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/bodonimoda.png" alt="" class="wp-image-199" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/bodonimoda.png 1000w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/bodonimoda-300x150.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/bodonimoda-768x384.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure>



<p>On the same line as EB Garamond Bodoni Moda is also a <strong>revival for the digital age </strong>designed by Owen Earl. It&#8217;s a <strong>contemporary reinterpretation of the classic Bodoni typeface loved by Vignelli, </strong>originally created by the Italian typographer Giambattista Bodoni in the late 18th century. The typeface&#8217;s historical connection gives it a touch of <strong>timeless sophistication,</strong> making it a suitable choice for a range of design applications.</p>



<p>One of Bodoni Moda&#8217;s key strengths is its <strong>high contrast between thick and thin strokes,</strong> which is a hallmark of the Bodoni style. This contrast gives the typeface a <strong>distinct and striking appearance</strong> that works exceptionally well for headlines, titles, and other display text. <strong>The sharp, geometric letterforms contribute to a sense of refinement and modernity.</strong></p>



<p>Bodoni Moda is available in various weights and styles, making it versatile for different design projects. The typeface&#8217;s versatility extends to its ability to be used in both print and digital media. <strong>Its clean and precise design ensures that it remains legible and aesthetically pleasing, even at small text sizes.</strong></p>



<p>It is an excellent choice for projects that require a blend of classic elegance and modern sophistication.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Why is this typeface on my list?</h4>



<p>I love Bodoni Moda, besides being a great revival t<strong>he contrasts in each letterform gives it a sharp, refined look.</strong> It’s a perfect companion for EB Garamond and should be in your collection.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Playfair Display</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="500" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/playfairdisplay.png" alt="" class="wp-image-197" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/playfairdisplay.png 1000w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/playfairdisplay-300x150.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/playfairdisplay-768x384.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure>



<p>Playfair Display is an<strong> elegant and versatile typeface with a distinct historical charm.</strong> It was inspired by the work of John Baskerville, a renowned 18th-century typographer. This historical association imparts a <strong>timeless and classic quality </strong>to Playfair Display, making it an excellent choice for a wide range of design projects.</p>



<p>One of the key strengths of Playfair Display is like Bodoni Moda <strong>its combination of high contrast between thick and thin strokes and the graceful, well-proportioned letterforms.</strong> This balance between classic aesthetics and modern readability makes it a versatile choice suitable for both body text and headings. The typeface manages to strike a <strong>harmonious equilibrium </strong>between the two, making it a perfect option for projects that require a touch of sophistication.</p>



<p>Playfair Display comes in various styles and weights, offering flexibility for different design needs.<strong> This versatility ensures that it can be used effectively for a variety of applications,</strong> from traditional print materials to contemporary web design.</p>



<p>Playfair Display&#8217;s appeal lies in its<strong> historical lineage, elegant high-contrast design, versatility, and open-source availability. </strong>It is a typeface that seamlessly blends classic aesthetics with modern readability.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Why is this typeface on my list?</h4>



<p>Although fairly similar to the previous two options Playfair Display is<strong> unique in the smaller details,</strong> I really like specific characters like the <strong>“Q” </strong>or the <strong>“r” </strong>and also the number selection. In conjunction with the previous two typefaces, <strong>it covers most of my serif needs.</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Poppins</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="500" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/poppins.png" alt="" class="wp-image-198" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/poppins.png 1000w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/poppins-300x150.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/poppins-768x384.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure>



<p>Poppins is a contemporary and adaptable typeface that combines a <strong>clean, sans-serif design with a touch of approachability and friendliness. </strong>It was designed by type designer Ninad Kale, with a focus on <strong>modernity and readability, </strong>making it a versatile choice for a wide range of design projects.</p>



<p>One of the key strengths of Poppins is its <strong>simplicity and legibility. </strong>The typeface features <strong>well-proportioned, straightforward letterforms that are easy to read,</strong> making it suitable for both body text and headings. Its design is crisp and clear, which is particularly well-suited for digital media and screen usage.</p>



<p>Poppins offers a variety of weights and styles. <strong>This diversity allows for flexibility in design,</strong> ensuring that it can be used effectively in a multitude of contexts, from web design to branding and print materials.</p>



<p>Poppins&#8217; appeal lies in its modern and approachable design, legibility, and versatility. <strong>It&#8217;s a typeface that seamlessly blends contemporary aesthetics with readability.</strong></p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Why is this typeface on my list?</h4>



<p>I picked Poppins as an <strong>alternative to Futura, which I don’t like.</strong> To me Poppins is Futura with a more refined letterform design, it’s<strong> slightly more geometric</strong> but it <strong>shares the key qualities of Futura.</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Fira Sans</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="500" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/firasans.png" alt="" class="wp-image-196" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/firasans.png 1000w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/firasans-300x150.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/firasans-768x384.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure>



<p>Initially designed as a <strong>commission from Firefox to Edenspiekermann </strong>Fira Sans is a modern and adaptable sans-serif typeface designed by <strong>Erik Spiekermann and Ralph du Carrois.</strong> It was crafted taking as a base the well-known iconic <strong>FF Meta </strong>to provide a highly legible and functional option, making it a versatile choice for a variety of design projects.</p>



<p>One of the key strengths of Fira Sans is its <strong>exceptional legibility.</strong> The letterforms are<strong> clean, balanced, and well-proportioned,</strong> ensuring easy readability, which is crucial for body text, headings, and user interfaces. This makes Fira Sans an excellent choice for content across various mediums.</p>



<p>Fira Sans offers an extensive range of weights and styles, including regular, italic, bold, and condensed versions. This wide variety of options allows designers to tailor their typographic choices to fit the specific requirements of a project,<strong> from web design to branding and editorial layouts.</strong></p>



<p>Fira Sans&#8217;s appeal lies in its modern design, exceptional legibility, extensive weights and styles, and open-source availability.<strong> It is a versatile and reliable typeface</strong> that works well in a wide array of design applications.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Why is this typeface on my list?</h4>



<p>I really like Fira Sans, it’s one of my favorite typefaces and I still cannot believe it’s free and open-source. Designed by one of my favorite designers it’s a <strong>humanistic sans-serif typeface that fits the list really well, </strong>it’s one of the key elements I believe <strong>Vignelli’s list lacks.</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Switzer</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="500" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/switzer.png" alt="" class="wp-image-195" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/switzer.png 1000w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/switzer-300x150.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/switzer-768x384.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure>



<p>Inspired by<strong> neo-grotesk Swiss typefaces </strong>Switzer is a typeface designed by Indian Type Foundry. This modern interpretation translated to a modern geometric sans-serif that is very legible.</p>



<p>Like Fira Sans and Poppins, the key strength is its <strong>exceptional legibility and simplicity. </strong>The letterforms although geometric have a lot of character. <strong>Balanced, clean, and very straightforward </strong>Switzer is an <strong>essential typeface.</strong></p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Why is this typeface on my list?</h4>



<p>In my opinion, this typeface solves the main issues I and many designers have with Helvetica, <strong>it has character but it still shares the key qualities of Helvetica.</strong> It’s a workhorse of a typeface completely free which is also incredible.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">So, this was my list, with these 6 typefaces I believe most designers will have their needs covered. Compared to Vignelli’s list it actually is fairly similar although I’ve replaced one of the serifs for a humanistic sans-serif typeface which in my opinion, and for my work, was the missing ingredient!</h2>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What makes this list good?</h2>



<p><strong>Versatility</strong> was the key aspect when I was making this list, I wanted three serifs and three sans-serifs that <strong>were versatile but that at the same time covered the several aspects that make each category unique. </strong>When looking to<strong> Vignelli’s </strong>list and mine you can clearly see what I mean, both lists follow the same thought process.</p>



<p>I wanted to also include the most amount of <strong>variable and web-ready typefaces </strong>as I believe this type of technology is the future.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Why have I chosen only free typefaces?</h2>



<p>Mainly because they are<strong> widely available and easier to integrate, </strong>but also because <strong>I don’t like the fact that I have to pay thousands for Helvetica when better, free typefaces are available. </strong>I don’t like the types of prices most foundries ask for a single individual font, as a student it bothered me.<strong> I’m really glad we live in a time and age where free typefaces are a lot of the times good or better than paid ones.</strong></p>



<p>In the future, I hope projects like <strong>Google Fonts </strong>or <strong>Adobe Fonts </strong>continue to make proper efforts to support type designers and provide great typefaces for free. I will also always support foundries that make great typefaces open-source, free, or adequately priced. <strong>You’re awesome!</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">On a final note, let me remind you that mine or Vignelli’s list are just a basis, you can and should always expand on it and search for better alternatives.</h2>



<p>Even if you look at Vignelli’s work you will see other typefaces, for example, the Ducati logo he designed uses Univers. So<strong> be open to new horizons and support type designers and small foundries</strong> whenever you can!</p>



<p>Thank you for reading, as per usual I would love to read your opinion.</p>



<p>You can read the last article <a href="/5-must-have-items-every-designer-needs-in-their-toolkit/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/these-are-the-only-6-typefaces-you-need/">These are the only 6 typefaces you need</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Hugo&#039;s Notes</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/these-are-the-only-6-typefaces-you-need/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 must-have items every designer needs in their toolkit</title>
		<link>/5-must-have-items-every-designer-needs-in-their-toolkit/</link>
					<comments>/5-must-have-items-every-designer-needs-in-their-toolkit/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hugo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 14:14:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=155</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>During my time in college and the beginning of my career, I’ve found out a lot of stuff that isn’t really that useful for my work and a lot of stuff that is, with this in mind today I want to share with you 5 items that are must-haves for every designer’s toolkit. Photo by [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/5-must-have-items-every-designer-needs-in-their-toolkit/">5 must-have items every designer needs in their toolkit</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Hugo&#039;s Notes</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>During my time in college and the beginning of my career, <strong>I’ve found out a lot of stuff that isn’t really that useful for my work and a lot of stuff that is,</strong> with this in mind today I want to share with you 5 items that are must-haves for every designer’s toolkit.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/theme-photos-CGpifH3FjOA-unsplash-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-160" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/theme-photos-CGpifH3FjOA-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/theme-photos-CGpifH3FjOA-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/theme-photos-CGpifH3FjOA-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/theme-photos-CGpifH3FjOA-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/theme-photos-CGpifH3FjOA-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@themephotos?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Theme Photos</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/tuned-on-macbook-CGpifH3FjOA?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Unsplash</a></p>



<p><strong>First of all, some disclaimers</strong>. I’m not going to suggest stuff that is very basic like a laptop, there are already a bunch of articles like this, I wanted to instead suggest useful items that go beyond the very basic of what you need. Another quick disclaimer, some links here are going to be affiliate links, no cost for you but it helps me out if you buy stuff through the link.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">If you are completely new, and you truly were searching for a very basic article of what you needed, here is a very quick list of stuff that hopefully will help you, so you don’t spend your time reading 1000 articles.</h4>



<p>Although you may not need all of this it is going to cover 99% of your needs when starting. The most important thing is to not be a gear nerd, start with what you have and build it up, anyways here are some suggestions for essentials:</p>



<ol>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MacBook-13-inch-Storage-English/dp/B0CB7619C5/ref=sr_1_2_sspa?crid=3O4OCFDUEVEV4&amp;keywords=macbook%252Bair%252Bm1&amp;qid=1698423727&amp;sprefix=mabook%252Bair%252Bm1%252Caps%252C155&amp;sr=8-2-spons&amp;sp_csd=d2lkZ2V0TmFtZT1zcF9hdGY&amp;th=1&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=e226893acacd9887515f01f98648dece&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325"><strong>Laptop</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="http://adobe.com/"><strong>Adobe software</strong></a> and if appliable <a href="http://figma.com/"><strong>Figma</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Minimalism-Art-Classic-Notebook-Journal/dp/B077Y3N8NN/ref=sr_1_1_sspa?crid=3D06EFD274X5X&amp;keywords=graphic%252Bdiary&amp;qid=1698423889&amp;sprefix=graphic%252Bdiary%252Caps%252C158&amp;sr=8-1-spons&amp;sp_csd=d2lkZ2V0TmFtZT1zcF9hdGY&amp;th=1&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=8976fd711e3ad60eb335c723dc77a5b8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325"><strong>Graphic diary</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Kingston-DataTraveler-Exodia-128GB-DTX/dp/B08JD4TBM3/ref=sr_1_4?crid=3TGO88RNB8TE1&amp;keywords=usb%252Bkingston&amp;qid=1697706811&amp;sprefix=usb%252Bkingston%252Caps%252C190&amp;sr=8-4&amp;th=1&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=a291591cfdb9ed5aa0039df482045bcd&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325"><strong>USB drive</strong></a> &amp;/or <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08GTYFC37/ref=twister_B0C6YZGJFH?_encoding=UTF8&amp;th=1&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=5b949e90b0315a238043d629b5d7c020&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325"><strong>External hard drive</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Stainless-Conversion-Metric-Straight-Measurement/dp/B08TWX79NC/ref=sxin_16_pa_sp_search_thematic_sspa?content-id=amzn1.sym.1b6a73e3-769d-477e-9f54-0fe90c31162a%253Aamzn1.sym.1b6a73e3-769d-477e-9f54-0fe90c31162a&amp;crid=26T56SF6NDPZ0&amp;cv_ct_cx=metal+ruler&amp;keywords=metal+ruler&amp;pd_rd_i=B08TWX79NC&amp;pd_rd_r=1af55778-1ffd-4f22-a87a-ad5ffa53cffa&amp;pd_rd_w=r7C8Z&amp;pd_rd_wg=EnUST&amp;pf_rd_p=1b6a73e3-769d-477e-9f54-0fe90c31162a&amp;pf_rd_r=1CXN9W6WNV56V4GYWDD7&amp;qid=1698424049&amp;sbo=RZvfv%252F%252FHxDF%252BO5021pAnSA%253D%253D&amp;sprefix=metal+ruler%252Caps%252C152&amp;sr=1-1-9cb21890-b538-4fe1-898e-473f8bb6c1fa-spons&amp;sp_csd=d2lkZ2V0TmFtZT1zcF9zZWFyY2hfdGhlbWF0aWM&amp;psc=1&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=fc9b8f19f364b8f3b34ef4ac4a6c280a&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325"><strong>Metal ruler</strong></a>, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/VViViD-Precision-Hobby-Craft-Cutting-Including/dp/B06XSR29J7/ref=sr_1_59?crid=2LI939PIZ05FQ&amp;keywords=xacto+knife&amp;qid=1698424219&amp;sprefix=xacto+knif%252Caps%252C182&amp;sr=8-59&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=977be96d091e556fb56ff580ca14dae3&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325"><strong>X-acto Knife</strong></a> &amp; <a href="https://www.amazon.com/US-Art-Supply-Professional-Scrapbooking/dp/B00L5I8RJC/ref=sr_1_50?crid=2LI939PIZ05FQ&amp;keywords=xacto%252Bknife&amp;qid=1698424192&amp;sprefix=xacto%252Bknif%252Caps%252C182&amp;sr=8-50&amp;th=1&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=6238f7036bdac3d39c0b071b5834ad8a&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325"><strong>Cutting Mat</strong></a></li>



<li>Tracing Paper, normal paper &amp; Cardstock of different colors</li>



<li>Pencils of different strengths &amp; Pens</li>



<li>Printer &amp; Scanner</li>



<li>Good books (I’m going to write an article on design book suggestions next week, stay tuned)</li>



<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/KS1-Headphones-Resolution-Detachable-Auriculares/dp/B08TWPZB9P/ref=sr_1_1_sspa?crid=2BVTAWJG9WHC2&amp;keywords=kbear%252Bks1&amp;qid=1698424660&amp;sprefix=kbear%252Bks1%252Caps%252C154&amp;sr=8-1-spons&amp;sp_csd=d2lkZ2V0TmFtZT1zcF9hdGY&amp;th=1&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=ffe02f4e272af4585fcdad2409a25fa0&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325"><strong>In-ear monitors</strong></a> &amp; Good Music</li>
</ol>



<p>Some stuff I haven&#8217;t linked because <strong>it either depends on preference or just overall knowledge</strong> I have with said product, for example I really like the Staedtler Norris line, specifically the B1 pencil and I have no knowledge on what the best printers are although I like Epson. With the basics removed out of the way <strong>here are the another 5 must-have items that every designer needs in their toolkit.</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Pantone Formula Guides</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="1000" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/pantone-color-books.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-169" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/pantone-color-books.jpg 1000w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/pantone-color-books-300x300.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/pantone-color-books-150x150.jpg 150w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/pantone-color-books-768x768.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure>



<p>It’s funny that I just wrote <a href="/we-need-to-talk-about-pantone/"><strong>this article</strong></a> on <a href="http://pantone.com/"><strong>Pantone</strong></a> and the first thing I’m suggesting is their Formula Guide sets. <strong>They are extremely useful for a variety of applications and a variety of designers.</strong> It’s a color system that has been <strong>refined and standardized</strong> over decades and it can now be in the palm of your hands (literally).</p>



<p>I used them at university for a bunch of different projects and I use them now on basically a day-to-day basis in a plethora of different projects. <strong>They are an essential item every agency and studio owns </strong>and an item that should be on your acquirement list.</p>



<p><strong>Don’t be</strong> that designer who picks Pantone colors by looking at their monitors, please I beg you. I’ve met a few people who have done work like this and it bothers me on a whole new level.</p>



<p>Personally, I have the standard non-bridge Formula Guide set which I bought before the whole Adobe and Pantone situation which led to the dreadful implementation of Pantone Connect. If you are acquiring your Pantone catalogs now, I recommend you to get the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Pantone-Bridge-Guides-Coated-Uncoated/dp/B0BY9QWBWF/ref=sr_1_15?keywords=pantone+color+bridge&amp;qid=1698498734&amp;sr=8-15&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=ad4d4d1ca1f00f696427323ce9856d63&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325"><strong>Pantone Formula Guide Bridge Coated &amp; Uncoated set,</strong></a> so you don’t have issues when picking colors for projects where you need CMYK and RGB values.</p>



<p>Also, a quick tip Pantone on the back of their Formula guide sets claim they last for only a year, <strong>if you preserve your guides in a dark environment with no humidity, they will last you years. </strong>One of my teachers showed us her guides with 40+ years of use, the colors were mostly perfect. Think about it.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">CMY color wheel</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="845" height="1024" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/cmy-color-wheel-845x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-170" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/cmy-color-wheel-845x1024.jpg 845w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/cmy-color-wheel-248x300.jpg 248w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/cmy-color-wheel-768x931.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/cmy-color-wheel.jpg 1238w" sizes="(max-width: 845px) 100vw, 845px" /></figure>



<p>This item was also recommended by a teacher and it took me years to find it online being sold again. It’s a color wheel that helps you figure out color combinations, there’s also an <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.cmycolorwheel.cmy&amp;hl=en&amp;gl=US"><strong>app that I would recommend for Android</strong></a> that I used previously. To be honest, if you can buy a physical version of the wheel, it’s cheap and feels better than the one on your phone.</p>



<p>This color wheel is very well printed with a fair amount of accuracy and attention to detail which is also important. Using a color wheel is in my opinion an<strong> essential part of my workflow </strong>and an inexpensive incredibly useful tool.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Also, if you don’t want to get the one from the link I provided, make sure you get a CMY color wheel, don’t get a RYB color wheel.</h4>



<p>The RYB color wheel was created in the <strong>early days of color theory when we did not know about the existence of pigments Cyan and Magenta </strong>which are nowadays the standard for printing.</p>



<p><strong>The RYB color wheel unfortunately is still taught in a lot of schools and even universities,</strong> even a lot of design books still teach that model and subsequently there are a lot of wheels around that follow the RYB model, while it’s great for painting it’s awful for design, just remember that.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/COLOR-WHEEL-COMPANY-BOOK/dp/B004YDDBM8/ref=sr_1_3?crid=3MQHGV8RTE4WP&amp;keywords=cmy+color+wheel&amp;qid=1698499645&amp;sprefix=cmy+color+wheel%252Caps%252C167&amp;sr=8-3&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=46d3450a3c81e453942643919efc1477&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325"><strong>Basically, make sure you buy a CMY color wheel</strong></a><strong> </strong>which is much more useful and updated. Also, a huge thank you to Professor Dulce for teaching this and explaining it in detail, happy to have learned from you.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Ergonomic Chair</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="640" height="360" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/my-back.gif" alt="" class="wp-image-158" style="aspect-ratio:1.7777777777777777;width:751px;height:auto"/></figure>



<p>Don’t be like <strong>Spiderman </strong>get a good quality chair. I’m going to be honest with you here I don’t have any specific recommendation to give you since everybody is different, but there are a few tips I can give you:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Forget about gaming chairs</strong> most of them are offensively bad for your posture, racing chairs are for racing not for you to be looking at a monitor 8h per day.</li>



<li>If it’s very cheap the materials are probably not that great, <strong>consider getting fewer features</strong> to save money instead of losing on material quality.</li>



<li>I really like <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hEC4wn6ayaY&amp;ab_channel=BTODtv"><strong>this video</strong></a> comparing chairs, I think you should watch it.</li>
</ul>



<p>Every person is different but maintaining a good posture is a universal thing, I also recommend you to do a lot of breaks and frequent exercise. <strong>There is no chair on the market that will fix any of these issues for you.</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Good mouse and keyboard</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="1024" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/mx-keys-1024x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-175" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/mx-keys-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/mx-keys-300x300.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/mx-keys-150x150.jpg 150w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/mx-keys-768x768.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/mx-keys-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/mx-keys-2048x2048.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>A good mouse and keyboard are essential tools to us who actually properly use them for hours per day, but beware the industry is full of bad products.</p>



<p>What I can recommend from experience is the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Logitech-K120-Arabic-Black-keyboard/dp/B00P7Z7SXU/ref=sr_1_3?crid=Z0AC640RDYFH&amp;keywords=logitech+k120&amp;qid=1698500660&amp;sprefix=logitech+k120%252Caps%252C164&amp;sr=8-3&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=756af2e9a26235ca1304d272d8ef6b93&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325"><strong>Logitech k120 keyboard</strong></a> which I used for years, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Glorious-Model-Wireless-Gaming-Mouse/dp/B098RDJZFM/ref=sr_1_4?crid=71MLAP7T20LH&amp;keywords=model+o&amp;qid=1698500736&amp;sprefix=model+o%252Caps%252C173&amp;sr=8-4&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=07f322bdd329e080b561d6638e52cc32&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325"><strong>the model O,</strong></a> the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Logitech-LIGHTSYNC-Wired-Gaming-Mouse/dp/B07YN82X3B/ref=sr_1_3?crid=20HM4OAUAB7V6&amp;keywords=g203&amp;qid=1698500815&amp;sprefix=g203%25252Caps%25252C168&amp;sr=8-3&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=1a40e4b1c173e582670efd65e9ca0c9f&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325"><strong>G203 Prodigy mouse,</strong></a> and the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Logitech-Master-Advanced-Wireless-Mouse/dp/B07XC2FWD1/ref=sr_1_3?crid=KNWUZAOKJ2TX&amp;keywords=mx%252Bmaster%252B3&amp;qid=1698501295&amp;sprefix=mx%252Bmaster%252B3%252Caps%252C189&amp;sr=8-3&amp;th=1&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=dd7e46ccfb5d98067d7ed91617def009&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325"><strong>Mx Master 3.</strong></a></p>



<p>The K120 keyboard is cheap, works great, and in my opinion is an absolute steal, out of the mice I recommended all of them are also equally great but the Mx Master 3 is by far my favorite mouse ever, so much that I’m even getting another one to use in my internship.</p>



<p>Also, I recently bought the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Logitech-Keys-Combo-Customizable-Illumination/dp/B0BKVY4WKT/ref=sr_1_2?crid=25B6H6S0QKYZB&amp;keywords=logitech%252Bmx%252Bkeys%252Bcombo&amp;qid=1698500573&amp;sprefix=logitech%252Bmx%252Bkeys%252Bcombo%252Caps%252C189&amp;sr=8-2&amp;th=1&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=a8b9fc45e71398421dd23c39eab9cc7e&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325"><strong>Mx Master 3 and Mx Keys combo</strong></a> which I’m going to review on the blog, stay tuned.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Paper catalogs</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="704" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Fedrigoni-Paper-Box-1024x704.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-177" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Fedrigoni-Paper-Box-1024x704.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Fedrigoni-Paper-Box-300x206.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Fedrigoni-Paper-Box-768x528.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Fedrigoni-Paper-Box.jpg 1160w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p><strong>Last but not least on my list are paper catalogs.</strong> I absolutely don’t understand why people don’t talk about these more often they are <strong>essential tools for anyone working with any type of physical stuff</strong> they need to design. Business cards, books, magazines, and newspapers all need one thing – paper!</p>



<p>So, a catalog is by far one of the most useful tools you can have around.</p>



<p>My recommendation is to first check local print manufacturers, in Portugal, we have <a href="https://inapaportugal.pt/"><strong>Inapa,</strong></a> for example. These are probably the most common types of papers that your printers provide. Beyond this I would recommend two paper manufacturer catalogs – <a href="https://www.metapaper.io/en/paper/sample-book/"><strong>Metapaper’s Sample Book</strong></a> and <a href="https://fedrigoni.com/en/news/paper-box-fedrigoni-paper/"><strong>Fedrigoni’s Paper Box.</strong></a></p>



<p>Out of these two<strong> Fedrigoni’s paper box</strong> is the most complete although it is a paid product and unfortunately currently is slightly outdated since they have removed some products.</p>



<p>I have a nice customer experience with them and you can request any paper samples you want from their website for free! <strong>They are very considerate!</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">On a final note I wanted to just tell you that tools are just tools, without the knowledge you can have the best laptop and not be an amazing designer, skills come first – don’t be a gearhead.</h2>



<p>If you liked this article please comment below! I will try to read and answer all of them.</p>



<p>You can read the previous article <a href="/we-need-to-talk-about-pantone/"><strong>here!</strong></a></p>



<p>Thank you for reading, stay safe.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/5-must-have-items-every-designer-needs-in-their-toolkit/">5 must-have items every designer needs in their toolkit</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Hugo&#039;s Notes</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/5-must-have-items-every-designer-needs-in-their-toolkit/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 things every design student needs to hear</title>
		<link>/5-things-every-design-student-needs-to-hear/</link>
					<comments>/5-things-every-design-student-needs-to-hear/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hugo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 10:48:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[college]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[people]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=122</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As a recently graduated graphic designer, kick-starting my career, there are certain things that If I was starting all over again, I would tell myself, so here are 5 things that I believe every design student needs to hear. Photo by Unseen Studio on Unsplash Hello fellow readers, today I wanted to talk with those [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/5-things-every-design-student-needs-to-hear/">5 things every design student needs to hear</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Hugo&#039;s Notes</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As a <strong>recently graduated graphic designer</strong>, kick-starting my career, there are certain things that If I was starting all over again, I would tell myself, so here are <strong>5 things that I believe every design student needs to hear.</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/unseen-studio-s9CC2SKySJM-unsplash-1024x683.jpg" alt="Image of a person holding a pen related to the article name - 5 things that every design student needs to hear " class="wp-image-123" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/unseen-studio-s9CC2SKySJM-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/unseen-studio-s9CC2SKySJM-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/unseen-studio-s9CC2SKySJM-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/unseen-studio-s9CC2SKySJM-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/unseen-studio-s9CC2SKySJM-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@craftedbygc?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Unseen Studio</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/person-writing-on-brown-wooden-table-near-white-ceramic-mug-s9CC2SKySJM?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Unsplash</a></p>



<p>Hello fellow readers, today I wanted to talk with those of you that are <strong>currently in college or thinking of going to college and studying design</strong>. My studying journey was good, I was a fairly successful student, I didn’t exactly fail any classes, but <strong>there is always room for improvement.</strong> Although my learning chapter isn’t exactly done, as I intend to eventually get a master’s degree, I feel like I can share with you valuable information, so here it is, <strong>my top 5 things that you and every design student needs to hear.</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">1 – Understand what college for designers means and take the most out of it</h2>



<p>I’ve read so many articles in the past about college for designers and <strong>if it’s worth it or if it’s foolish</strong> to even go to college for design. In my opinion this is kind of a <strong>silly question.</strong> The reason being that it simply varies from person to person. <strong>I’ve met amazing designers who went to college and amazing designers who didn’t and were self-taught.</strong></p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">If you can afford it and are in this should I go or shouldn’t I go situation, I will always answer the same thing – go for it! </h4>



<p>If this is an <strong>area that you actually like,</strong> University is going to be awesome for you, mainly because you will spend countless hours<strong> with experts</strong> in their fields! That’s a lot of value. Also, in the increasingly saturated market of graphic designers, having a degree sometimes <strong>will influence</strong> a lot of recruiters to even consider you, if candidate A and B are equal in terms of portfolio, soft skills, etc… but one holds a degree and the other one doesn’t, it’s simply the <strong>deciding factor that’s going to take you out.</strong></p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">On the other hand, If you are being forced to go by your parents or If you just want to go to university studying design because you want to hold a degree – simply don’t go. </h4>



<p>Choose another option instead. I can’t really recommend you any specific course, but I guarantee you <strong>design isn’t the way,</strong> If I were in your shoes, I would just see <strong>what course</strong> translated into the job that pays the <strong>highest.</strong></p>



<p>If you are actually interested in going to university studying design because you have a passion for it, I want to help you understand <strong>what exactly you are getting out of it.</strong> As I previously mentioned professors that are experts in their fields is going to be the main advantage of taking a degree.</p>



<p>If you expect to learn software and stuff like that you are wrong, <strong>that’s going to be your homework</strong>. </p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">The main purpose of any design program in the world is to teach you the fundamentals and help you develop upon them. </h4>



<p>By the end you should expect to <strong>master the concepts</strong> you learned and how to <strong>apply them.</strong> Don’t expect classes about how to use illustrator 101, yes they exist but a lot of times they do not add any significant knowledge besides what you can see on youtube.</p>



<p>As a student I had colleagues in all the above-mentioned situations, but the main reason I became a standout student is because <strong>I understood the system and what it means to go to college for design.</strong> <strong>I needed to be able to form connections</strong> with those that were teaching me so that I could get the <strong>most value </strong>out of it. Of course, this means that you need to be an <strong>exemplary class member,</strong> don’t miss class, deliver work on time, don’t take shortcuts and <strong>be serious.</strong></p>



<p>The number of students I’ve met who wasted years of their lives and finished courses <strong>knowing nothing</strong> is genuinely <strong>hard to believe. </strong>All because they missed classes, went partying, had zero sense of responsibility and were genuinely uninterested.</p>



<p><strong>You can live your life the way you want </strong>and although I was one of top students of my class while I had two jobs and didn’t even complain <strong>I’m not saying you need to do the same.</strong> Just make sure you are happy with the options you make <strong>now and later.</strong> Everything you do eventually comes around, <strong>it’s a cycle.</strong></p>



<p>The message that I want to share with you in this point is simple, <strong>think about your decisions</strong> and how it affects you.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">2 – Be curious, make questions, solve problems and create new ones</h2>



<p>The first question that really got me extremely curious in university was <strong>“What is design?&#8221;</strong>, I was so speechless and surprised with the fact that <strong>I couldn’t find the words to explain what design is,</strong> to me it was something around the lines of making logos, talking with clients, making magazines, books and other stuff. The answer that our teacher gave us was a simple one, but it blew my mind <strong>“design is solving problems”.</strong></p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Why am I reminiscing on this? Because that moment was important to me, I learned for the first-time what design was all about and I was curious to know more.</h4>



<p>The first tip that I want to give you in this second point is a simple one –<strong> be curious.</strong> Curiosity fuels creativity, make questions, foolish questions, don’t be afraid of being curious and asking around, this is what takes your learning from good to great. I<strong>nvolving yourself is an important step,</strong> talent without curiosity, without questions is just wasted potential. I’ve met average students that became great designers because they were curious and made questions. <strong>Don’t be afraid!</strong></p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">At university you will solve problems, a lot of them, these are going to be given to you by your teachers, but are you going to be that person that sticks with just the program? </h4>



<p>University is about <strong>exploration</strong> and figuring stuff out and that ties up with curiosity, so <strong>be curious, solve problems,</strong> but also and perhaps most importantly<strong> create new problems</strong> that you can solve by yourself.</p>



<p>This isn’t as difficult as it sounds, to me I did this by <strong>finding competitions</strong> that I could be a part of, by <strong>kickstarting certain projects </strong>or by <strong>learning new software or techniques</strong> that weren’t taught to me. </p>



<p>I did all of this after-school stuff whilst having <strong>two jobs,</strong> so you do not have any possible excuse besides being lazy. <strong>Get up, do it, now!</strong></p>



<p>In an increasingly saturated market where everyone who uses canva thinks they are designers <strong>it’s difficult to stand out</strong> so if you pickup up things like web development, 3d, motion design, video editing, etc… <strong>in your free time,</strong> when you start searching for a job <strong>a door will eventually more easily open</strong> for you. I know this because<strong> only a month or two after finishing my degree</strong> I already was doing an internship, perhaps it wasn’t what I wanted to initially do, but a door was open and that’s my point.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">3 – Always carry a usb drive</h2>



<p>Okay, this is kind of just me being a little mad at some of my fellow university colleagues, but for god sakes <strong>buy a usb drive!</strong> They are cheap nowadays and you are going to need them to carry files around for a variety of purposes, even if it is to just figure out minimum dimensions for a logo. <strong>Don’t be that person that doesn’t have a usb drive </strong>or an external hard drive and just ask if someone has it, it’s foolish!</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">In my opinion if you carry around a laptop with good storage a smaller usb drive is all you need, if you use university computers then I recommend you get an external hard drive. </h4>



<p>It really <strong>depends on your use case,</strong> but always have backups of your projects. <strong>I’m serious,</strong> it’s unprofessional and very realistic the number of times I listened to someone say, <strong>“I just lost all of my work for X project because my pc broke”</strong>, don’t be like this you have zero excuse when hard drives exist, and cloud storage exist.</p>



<p>Also, to make it simple for you <strong>here are some suggestions at different price points,</strong> all the links will be <strong>affiliated </strong>– always <strong>do your own research on stuff you buy,</strong> don’t simply take mine or others recommendations as the rule.</p>



<p><strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Kingston-DataTraveler-Exodia-128GB-DTX/dp/B08JD4TBM3/ref=sr_1_4?crid=3TGO88RNB8TE1&amp;keywords=usb%252Bkingston&amp;qid=1697706811&amp;sprefix=usb%252Bkingston%252Caps%252C190&amp;sr=8-4&amp;th=1&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=a291591cfdb9ed5aa0039df482045bcd&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325">Kingston DataTraveler Exodia</a></strong> – I have a few of these, I don’t know if it’s an exclusive deal to Portugal, but I bought mine in a kit that came with two, so do research on that. <strong>They are really good for the money</strong> I use them almost every day, no complaints, Kingston hit me up, I like your products.</p>



<p><strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08GTYFC37/ref=twister_B0C6YZGJFH?_encoding=UTF8&amp;th=1&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=hugosnotes-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=5b949e90b0315a238043d629b5d7c020&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325">SanDisk Portable SSD</a></strong> – A few options here in terms of what storage you get, see what fits your budget, but 2TB usb 3.2 up to 1050MB/s at $119.99 feels like a decent deal to me.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">4 – Find time to live life</h2>



<p>In a period of time that’s going to be tense,<strong> find the time to live your life.</strong> This probably would be one of the biggest tips I would give to myself looking back. </p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">I always have a very serious relationship with my work and sometimes I forget that I must live my life. </h4>



<p>For the years I was in college I had basically <strong>no personal time</strong> and this affected my <strong>mental health,</strong> but now as an older individual I have learned that you must have personal time and I really do value my moments of relaxation a lot. So, if you are starting college, <strong>work hard, but find time to chill a little,</strong> watch a movie, read a book, paint, take care of plants, work out, I don’t know what fits your mood. </p>



<p>I will say this, in the minuscule time I had for myself <strong>I always worked out </strong>because it kept my mental health in check, so if you don’t currently do any form of exercise <strong>that’s my recommendation.</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">5 – If you don’t fit in with everybody else, you’re probably in the right track</h2>



<p>There is such a need that people in general have to fit in that <strong>I personally don’t get.</strong> People are quick to try and form groups. Perhaps this is something more personal, but I never quite <strong>liked the idea of forming a group and putting people </strong>aside, even worse is when people retroactively choose to be jerks about it.</p>



<p>I always tried to be nice and helpful to others and to connect with everyone and be an open book, but these types of things <strong>make me want to just be on my shell. </strong>This is perhaps why I have very few friends and even fewer best friends.</p>



<p>On my university years I never quite fitted in with my classmates and I honestly think most of them didn’t really like me a lot, but I was not searching for their approval &#8211; so I kind of get them! I just did my own thing and if someone wanted help or to talk, I didn’t have a problem with that, I just didn’t offer shortcuts, that was my rule.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">I’m telling you this not because I want your compassion but because I want to tell you something that I never see people telling each other. You don’t need a group, you can be alone and find success, if you don’t like people’s attitudes or behaviors don’t join them. Let them be the ones to find you.</h4>



<p>On another note, people can and will be jerks there is simply no way of avoiding it, even I am not a hero, and I was a jerk a few times. It’s life, not everyone is perfect, that’s what makes us human. </p>



<p>Although there are <strong>those who apologize and those who don’t.</strong> The takeaway of this point is that you can be yourself, <strong>you don’t need others approvals, you don’t need to join people that you don’t want to be around and you definitely don’t need to agree with something you do not believe.</strong> So please fellow readers be aware of others humans!</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">On a final note, and because depression is a real thing among students, please feel free to contact me if you need someone to not judge you and just talk.</h2>



<p>I hope these five tips help you on your journey. <strong>If you have tips</strong> for others or any opinion about this article <strong>please do leave a comment bellow!</strong> I will try to read and answer them all!</p>



<p>If you are new to the blog, I recommend reading this <a href="/my-blogging-story-why-i-started-and-how-you-can-start-right-now/"><strong>article!</strong></a></p>



<p>Also, if you want more content, please do consider checking out my social media platforms!</p>



<p>Thank you for reading, I hope you enjoyed!</p>
<p>The post <a href="/5-things-every-design-student-needs-to-hear/">5 things every design student needs to hear</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Hugo&#039;s Notes</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/5-things-every-design-student-needs-to-hear/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- plugin=object-cache-pro client=phpredis metric#hits=1190 metric#misses=27 metric#hit-ratio=97.8 metric#bytes=485179 metric#prefetches=0 metric#store-reads=70 metric#store-writes=4 metric#store-hits=115 metric#store-misses=21 metric#sql-queries=10 metric#ms-total=295.54 metric#ms-cache=83.02 metric#ms-cache-avg=1.1373 metric#ms-cache-ratio=28.1 sample#redis-hits=201874 sample#redis-misses=86279 sample#redis-hit-ratio=70.1 sample#redis-ops-per-sec=295 sample#redis-evicted-keys=0 sample#redis-used-memory=6822176 sample#redis-used-memory-rss=19656704 sample#redis-memory-fragmentation-ratio=2.9 sample#redis-connected-clients=3 sample#redis-tracking-clients=0 sample#redis-rejected-connections=0 sample#redis-keys=1034 -->
