<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Reviews Archives - Hugo&#039;s Notes</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/reviews/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/category/reviews/</link>
	<description>Hugo&#039;s Notes: Design and other thoughts from a designer.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 16:38:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/cropped-favicon-32x32.webp</url>
	<title>Reviews Archives - Hugo&#039;s Notes</title>
	<link>/category/reviews/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>MX Keys S Combo review – is it worth the hype?</title>
		<link>/mx-keys-s-combo-review-is-it-worth-the-hype/</link>
					<comments>/mx-keys-s-combo-review-is-it-worth-the-hype/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hugo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 16:38:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Typography]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=222</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I needed a new keyboard and mouse so I bought the “holy grail” of keyboard and mouse combos, in this review you will find out if the MX Keys S Combo is worth the hype and praise it gets or if you should avoid it. Photo by Marios Gkortsilas on Unsplash Hello designers, in one [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/mx-keys-s-combo-review-is-it-worth-the-hype/">MX Keys S Combo review – is it worth the hype?</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Hugo&#039;s Notes</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>I needed a new keyboard and mouse so I bought the “holy grail” of keyboard and mouse combos, in this review you will find out if the<strong> MX Keys S Combo </strong>is worth the hype and praise it gets or if you should avoid it.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1024" height="576" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/marios-gkortsilas-JCeQHpTpU24-unsplash-1024x576.png" alt="MX Keys S Combo " class="wp-image-225" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/marios-gkortsilas-JCeQHpTpU24-unsplash-1024x576.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/marios-gkortsilas-JCeQHpTpU24-unsplash-300x169.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/marios-gkortsilas-JCeQHpTpU24-unsplash-768x432.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/marios-gkortsilas-JCeQHpTpU24-unsplash-1536x864.png 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/marios-gkortsilas-JCeQHpTpU24-unsplash-2048x1152.png 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@mr_mgk?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Marios Gkortsilas</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/a-computer-mouse-and-keyboard-on-a-desk-JCeQHpTpU24?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Unsplash</a></p>



<p>Hello designers, in one of my recent articles I talked about tools <a href="/5-must-have-items-every-designer-needs-in-their-toolkit/"><strong>that every designer needs,</strong></a> I wrote in that post that I had recently bought the <strong>MX Keys S Combo</strong> and that soon I would be reviewing it. This is that review.</p>



<p>Before we start I wanted to tell you a few things, first <strong>I’m not in any way or shape sponsored by Logitech</strong> (I wish I was), second if there is a link to the product it&#8217;s going to be <strong>non-affiliated,</strong> thirdly I see a lot of articles like this in which people say that they are not biased, <strong>I’m human and I like Logitech so obviously although I’m going to try to write an unbiased review there are always small bias</strong> we cannot go around – do your own research before buying stuff.</p>



<p>On another note, let me also say that I’m going to be brutally honest,<strong> I will not sugar coat anything for you,</strong> whatever I like I like, whatever I hate I hate, period.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">I’m a Logitech fanboy</h2>



<p>I wanted to start this review by stating what I had previously mentioned, I really like Logitech. <strong>I have been using their products for years,</strong> from their entry-level products like the <strong>G203 Prodigy</strong> to their more expensive items like the<strong> MX Master 3.</strong></p>



<p>Throughout the years their product selection has stood against my abuse, which to be fair isn’t much as I’m very careful with my stuff. The most abuse any of their products saw was my MX Master 3 being thrown around in a case inside my backpack when I went to university and now my internship.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">By mentioning this I hope you understand where my slight bias may come from, I’ve been for the most part a happy customer throughout their whole lineup.</h4>



<p>Their products are in general <strong>high quality, fairly priced, and resistant</strong> – which is basically what I’m ideally looking for.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Why did I buy this combo?</h2>



<p>The main reason I decided to buy this combo is because I wanted to use my MX Master 3 at my internship and retire my 6-year-old K120 keyboard (which I’m also using at work right now).</p>



<p>This specific case put me in a very peculiar situation in which I needed to buy a new keyboard and mouse. I thought about buying a mechanical keyboard and another MX Master 3 since <strong>the experience I had with was so positive,</strong> but as I was endlessly scrolling through product pages, <strong>I ended up finding the MX Keys S Combo on Logitech’s website.</strong></p>



<p>Like many of you, <strong>the amount of hype and positive things I heard or read regarding the MX Keys </strong>was so large I thought <strong>“Wait, incredible mouse, incredible keyboard plus a wrist rest for this price? Take my money!”.</strong></p>



<p>On another note, I thought as a tech enthusiast it would be fun to review this for you,<strong> would the combo be as good as it seemed?</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The lackluster ordering process</h2>



<p>Here I am ordering my combo, Logitech’s official website looked cool, I paid with 0 problems. Got my order made, and now I only needed to receive it.</p>



<p>On Logitech’s European store they claim the delivery takes around <strong>2-3 days,</strong> mine took basically <strong>4 weeks.</strong> Between numerous tickets, they told me they had a<strong> huge number of orders</strong> which in all fairness I see as a Christmas buildup issue more than anything else.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Throughout the 4 weeks, I contacted Logitech’s customer support frequently through the chat-bot on their website, and although it took an eternity to get my order in which they sent me a free mousepad first, and later the combo it eventually came.</h4>



<p>For the most part, I have to be mad at Logitech for the delivery of my order to take so long, but on the other hand, <strong>their customer support was truly refreshing.</strong> They were always very nice to me making sure I got detailed information on why my order hadn’t been delivered.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">A quick cost breakdown</h2>



<p>At this specific point, I wanted to do a quick breakdown of how much I paid for the product. In total, I paid <strong>197.10€.</strong> This included the combo <strong>(Keyboard, Mouse, and Wrist Rest)</strong> plus a free studio series desk mat.</p>



<p>I believe this combo offers a lot of value and is in general a good product for those of you who like me need a keyboard and mouse.</p>



<p>Usually, <strong>you will find discount codes online,</strong> I found one that gave me a little bit of a discount, so stay alert for that as well. Besides this the <strong>bonus desk mat</strong> was a nice addition to the bundle although personally, <strong>I don’t find it that amazing, it’s a very basic desk mat, </strong>slightly on the smaller side but perfect for my use case – to have a desk mat at work and one at home.</p>



<p>If you are curious I use <a href="https://www.corsair.com/us/en/p/mousepads/ch-9413641-ww/mm300-pro-premium-spill-proof-cloth-gaming-mouse-pad-extended-ch-9413641-ww"><strong>this corsair deskmat on my home setup,</strong></a> which I also want to share with you on a separate article.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The good points</h2>



<p>Let’s start with the actual product review, first, <strong>the combo offers in my view a lot of value for the price that I paid.</strong> It seems to me that Logitech has a really good price/performance ratio.</p>



<p>The <strong>MX3S Mouse</strong> is a nice evolution to the standard <strong>MX3, </strong>most of the design and features remain the same with an <strong>improved sensor.</strong> Has a 3+ year user of the standard MX3 I found the MX3S a nice evolution, it features <strong>quieter button clicks</strong> which I personally really enjoy, and an improved sensor with a <strong>higher dpi number,</strong> it also uses the <strong>newer bolt 3 receiver.</strong></p>



<p>Like the MX3 the 3S features an <strong>incredibly designed scroll wheel </strong>that allows you to change between infinite scrolling and standard scrolling, it’s also the best scroll wheel I’ve ever used on any mouse ever.</p>



<p>Like the keyboard, it features a<strong> plethora of customization options through the Logi Options + software, </strong>allowing you to customize your experience. Personally, I don’t really use half of the customization options you have but I see the value in it, I believe designers will find it useful for their workflow.</p>



<p>In my use case, <strong>the feature I find the most valuable is the scroll wheel on the top and the one on the side,</strong> allowing me to do stuff like changing volume, infinite scrolling through webpages/ documents and controlling the timeline on video editing/animation projects. <strong>The improved dpi range is also really good for me </strong>as I really enjoy using a higher dpi.</p>



<p>The keyboard is very interesting to me,<strong> I really like the slim profile and the low noise it produces when typing,</strong> and features like the automatic background light are cool as well. The build construction is in general <strong>high quality with a mostly metal construction.</strong> Like the mouse, it features an extensive list of customization possibilities which is honestly perfect for those of you who use a lot of key binds. The typing experience is relatively nice with the wrist rest offering added comfort, a fixed keyboard inclination that is perfect, and keys that are designed for your fingers.</p>



<p>From the past weeks utilizing the MX Keys S, I’ve got to say, <strong>I really enjoyed the typing experience and if you game it will be good for you as well,</strong> from my time playing Tetris and other games with this keyboard it proved more than capable.</p>



<p>The keyboard also features multiple text on the ctrl/command keys for example as <strong>it’s designed for both Apple and PC.</strong></p>



<p>Last but not least I really liked the fact <strong>I could connect both the keyboard and mouse to the same receiver, </strong>well done and thought out Logitech!</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The not-so-good points</h2>



<p>I’m not going to sugarcoat it in any way or form, I don’t like some things about this combo. First, <strong>I really don’t like the fact both the keyboard and mouse don’t hold any type of internal memory,</strong> to me this is the biggest issue. If you want a certain dpi number, for example, you have to have Logi Options + installed all the time on your device. In products this expensive it’s a<strong> major design flaw.</strong></p>



<p>The keyboard has a very nice construction except for the keys,<strong> they feel very different from the rest of the product.</strong> Honestly, they disappointed me, I was expecting incredible keys but instead, they are mediocre, they feel like low-quality plastic. </p>



<p>Although useful in some scenarios and decent I feel like the <strong>top material on the wrist rest could be better, </strong>it doesn’t make me mad but it definitely feels slightly worse than the rest of the package.</p>



<p>So, the package comes with a usb-c mouse and a usb-c keyboard, both wireless, awesome! What’s the problem? <strong>It only includes a single usb-c cable for charging.</strong> Come on Logitech. The cable itself feels low quality and slightly thin for my liking.</p>



<p>Last but not least <strong>Logi options +</strong> is good but could be better, the fact it always has to be installed is a problem and I found some scenarios throughout the years in which it crashed on me (very rare). I really do like it compared to the rest of the industry, but again, could be better.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">On a final note, I consider this combo to be worth your time but I don’t believe it fits the hype it gets</h2>



<p>This combo has so much built-up hype, specifically the keyboard, which I believe is not that amazing. In general, <strong>you will get a really good product and personally, I’m really happy</strong> but take into consideration the details I’ve given you on these smaller issues. I really liked Logitech’s support and I would recommend you to get their combo <a href="https://www.logitech.com/en-eu/products/combos/mx-keys-s-combo.html"><strong>through their website.</strong></a></p>



<p>You can read my last post<strong> <a href="/the-key-skill-every-designer-needs-to-learn-in-2024/">here.</a></strong> If you own or eventually acquire this keyboard leave a comment below. I’m interested to see what you think!</p>



<p>That’s all folks, have a nice one.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/mx-keys-s-combo-review-is-it-worth-the-hype/">MX Keys S Combo review – is it worth the hype?</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Hugo&#039;s Notes</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/mx-keys-s-combo-review-is-it-worth-the-hype/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- plugin=object-cache-pro client=phpredis metric#hits=498 metric#misses=17 metric#hit-ratio=96.7 metric#bytes=240856 metric#prefetches=0 metric#store-reads=45 metric#store-writes=3 metric#store-hits=38 metric#store-misses=11 metric#sql-queries=10 metric#ms-total=73.87 metric#ms-cache=5.86 metric#ms-cache-avg=0.1246 metric#ms-cache-ratio=7.9 -->
