<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Typography Archives - Hugo&#039;s Notes</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/typography/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/category/typography/</link>
	<description>Hugo&#039;s Notes: Design and other thoughts from a designer.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 10:03:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/cropped-favicon-32x32.webp</url>
	<title>Typography Archives - Hugo&#039;s Notes</title>
	<link>/category/typography/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>These are the only 6 typefaces you need</title>
		<link>/these-are-the-only-6-typefaces-you-need/</link>
					<comments>/these-are-the-only-6-typefaces-you-need/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hugo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 14:24:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Typography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=179</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In the current day and age of design we have thousands and thousands of typefaces to choose from, so in this article following the lessons of modernist designers like Massimo Vignelli, I’m going to tell you the only 6 typefaces you need and that are the basis of my collection. Photo by Bruno Martins on [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/these-are-the-only-6-typefaces-you-need/">These are the only 6 typefaces you need</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Hugo&#039;s Notes</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In the current day and age of design we have <strong>thousands and thousands of typefaces to choose from,</strong> so in this article following the lessons of modernist designers like <strong>Massimo Vignelli,</strong> I’m going to tell you <strong>the only 6 typefaces you need and that are the basis of my collection.</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1024" height="682" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/bruno-martins-4cwf-iW6I1Q-unsplash-1024x682.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-185" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/bruno-martins-4cwf-iW6I1Q-unsplash-1024x682.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/bruno-martins-4cwf-iW6I1Q-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/bruno-martins-4cwf-iW6I1Q-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/bruno-martins-4cwf-iW6I1Q-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/bruno-martins-4cwf-iW6I1Q-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@brunus?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Bruno Martins</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/brown-and-black-wooden-cross-4cwf-iW6I1Q?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Unsplash</a></p>



<p>Hello designers, recently I’ve been rereading a few books and articles on typefaces, particularly the new <a href="https://www.neue.shop/fonts/neue-serie57"><strong>Neue series 57 made by Neue Type Foundry in collaboration with Erik Spiekermann.</strong></a> These books and articles made me think a lot about type design and how it has evolved so much over the years.</p>



<p>Particularly I’ve been also rereading the infamous <strong><a href="https://www.rit.edu/vignellicenter/sites/rit.edu.vignellicenter/files/documents/The%20Vignelli%20Canon.pdf">Vignelli canon written by Massimo Vignelli</a>,</strong> one of the most important designers in history. In the book Vignelli teaches us about his philosophy on design and <strong>shares with us</strong> his iconic list of the only <strong>6 typefaces you need,</strong> claiming that <strong>you can trash the rest.</strong></p>



<p>Rediscovering this made me think <strong>“Hmm would his list today be the same?”</strong> with the evolution of technology and design trends I imagine his list would also evolve with the times. The matter of the fact is <strong>it’s still a relevant list that all designers still talk about today!</strong></p>



<p>The way you should see this article is very simple – <strong>it’s my own view </strong>of what those 6 typefaces would be,<strong> not an updated Vignelli list,</strong> just my list.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">“In the new computer age the proliferation of typefaces and type manipulations represents a new level of visual pollution threating our culture. Out of thousands of typefaces, all we need are a few basic ones, and trash the rest. So come and see A Few Basic Typefaces” <em>– Massimo Vignelli</em></h2>



<p>In a nutshell here is Vignelli’s list:</p>



<ul>
<li>Garamond</li>



<li>Bodoni</li>



<li>Century Expanded</li>



<li>Futura</li>



<li>Times Roman</li>



<li>Helvetica</li>
</ul>



<p>This list in my view <strong>is still very viable</strong> but I don’t think a lot of these typefaces<strong> stand the test of time </strong>as good as they probably should, <strong>either they have been redesigned or there are just better options.</strong> <strong>Don’t take this opinion from just me,</strong> see what people like <strong>Erik Spiekermann</strong> think of <strong>Helvetica,</strong> probably the most iconic typeface ever made – <a href="https://spiekermann.com/en/helvetica-sucks/"><strong>“Helvetica sucks. It really wasn’t designed for small sizes on screens. Words like milliliter can be very difficult to decipher.”</strong></a></p>



<p>To me these 6 typefaces <strong>lack features that most designers need today,</strong> I’m not saying I can put together a better list, but <strong>here is my attempt:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://fonts.google.com/specimen/EB+Garamond?query=eb+garamond"><strong>Eb Garamond</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="https://fonts.google.com/specimen/Bodoni+Moda?query=bodoni+moda"><strong>Bodoni Moda</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="https://fonts.google.com/specimen/Playfair+Display"><strong>Playfair Display</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="https://fonts.google.com/specimen/Poppins?query=poppins"><strong>Poppins</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.edenspiekermann.com/insights/mozilla-fira-fox/"><strong>Fira Sans</strong></a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.fontshare.com/fonts/switzer"><strong>Switzer</strong></a></li>
</ul>



<p>A small note if you have your own list please tell me about it in the comment section, <strong>I would love to know!</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Eb Garamond</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="1000" height="500" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/ebgaramond.png" alt="" class="wp-image-200" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/ebgaramond.png 1000w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/ebgaramond-300x150.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/ebgaramond-768x384.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure>



<p>Made as a <strong>revival of Claude Garamond’s original 1532 typeface,</strong> which is present on Vignelli’s list, this version was made for the digital age. The source for the letterforms comes from a scan of the <strong>“Berner Specimen”</strong> composed in 1592 by Conrad Berner.</p>



<p>Its letterforms are <strong>elegant and well-proportioned,</strong> striking a balance between classic aesthetics and modern legibility, making it <strong>suitable for various applications, including body text and headings.</strong></p>



<p>EB Garamond is versatile, offering different weights and styles.<strong> It&#8217;s also an open-source typeface!</strong></p>



<p>With an extensive character set, it supports various characters and diacritics, making it suitable for multilingual projects. <strong>Its attention to detail during the revival and refinement process ensures a high-quality typeface with consistent design features. </strong>EB Garamond works well in both print and digital contexts, thanks to its design that maintains its elegance and legibility in various sizes and applications.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Why is this typeface on my list?</h4>



<p>Like <strong>Vignelli</strong> it made sense to me to include Garamond although in my case a more updated version of it, <strong>it’s a perfect typeface for a variety of uses,</strong> it has a lower contrast between strokes but it exhibits a classic timeless design.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Bodoni Moda</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="1000" height="500" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/bodonimoda.png" alt="" class="wp-image-199" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/bodonimoda.png 1000w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/bodonimoda-300x150.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/bodonimoda-768x384.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure>



<p>On the same line as EB Garamond Bodoni Moda is also a <strong>revival for the digital age </strong>designed by Owen Earl. It&#8217;s a <strong>contemporary reinterpretation of the classic Bodoni typeface loved by Vignelli, </strong>originally created by the Italian typographer Giambattista Bodoni in the late 18th century. The typeface&#8217;s historical connection gives it a touch of <strong>timeless sophistication,</strong> making it a suitable choice for a range of design applications.</p>



<p>One of Bodoni Moda&#8217;s key strengths is its <strong>high contrast between thick and thin strokes,</strong> which is a hallmark of the Bodoni style. This contrast gives the typeface a <strong>distinct and striking appearance</strong> that works exceptionally well for headlines, titles, and other display text. <strong>The sharp, geometric letterforms contribute to a sense of refinement and modernity.</strong></p>



<p>Bodoni Moda is available in various weights and styles, making it versatile for different design projects. The typeface&#8217;s versatility extends to its ability to be used in both print and digital media. <strong>Its clean and precise design ensures that it remains legible and aesthetically pleasing, even at small text sizes.</strong></p>



<p>It is an excellent choice for projects that require a blend of classic elegance and modern sophistication.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Why is this typeface on my list?</h4>



<p>I love Bodoni Moda, besides being a great revival t<strong>he contrasts in each letterform gives it a sharp, refined look.</strong> It’s a perfect companion for EB Garamond and should be in your collection.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Playfair Display</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="500" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/playfairdisplay.png" alt="" class="wp-image-197" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/playfairdisplay.png 1000w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/playfairdisplay-300x150.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/playfairdisplay-768x384.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure>



<p>Playfair Display is an<strong> elegant and versatile typeface with a distinct historical charm.</strong> It was inspired by the work of John Baskerville, a renowned 18th-century typographer. This historical association imparts a <strong>timeless and classic quality </strong>to Playfair Display, making it an excellent choice for a wide range of design projects.</p>



<p>One of the key strengths of Playfair Display is like Bodoni Moda <strong>its combination of high contrast between thick and thin strokes and the graceful, well-proportioned letterforms.</strong> This balance between classic aesthetics and modern readability makes it a versatile choice suitable for both body text and headings. The typeface manages to strike a <strong>harmonious equilibrium </strong>between the two, making it a perfect option for projects that require a touch of sophistication.</p>



<p>Playfair Display comes in various styles and weights, offering flexibility for different design needs.<strong> This versatility ensures that it can be used effectively for a variety of applications,</strong> from traditional print materials to contemporary web design.</p>



<p>Playfair Display&#8217;s appeal lies in its<strong> historical lineage, elegant high-contrast design, versatility, and open-source availability. </strong>It is a typeface that seamlessly blends classic aesthetics with modern readability.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Why is this typeface on my list?</h4>



<p>Although fairly similar to the previous two options Playfair Display is<strong> unique in the smaller details,</strong> I really like specific characters like the <strong>“Q” </strong>or the <strong>“r” </strong>and also the number selection. In conjunction with the previous two typefaces, <strong>it covers most of my serif needs.</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Poppins</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="500" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/poppins.png" alt="" class="wp-image-198" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/poppins.png 1000w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/poppins-300x150.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/poppins-768x384.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure>



<p>Poppins is a contemporary and adaptable typeface that combines a <strong>clean, sans-serif design with a touch of approachability and friendliness. </strong>It was designed by type designer Ninad Kale, with a focus on <strong>modernity and readability, </strong>making it a versatile choice for a wide range of design projects.</p>



<p>One of the key strengths of Poppins is its <strong>simplicity and legibility. </strong>The typeface features <strong>well-proportioned, straightforward letterforms that are easy to read,</strong> making it suitable for both body text and headings. Its design is crisp and clear, which is particularly well-suited for digital media and screen usage.</p>



<p>Poppins offers a variety of weights and styles. <strong>This diversity allows for flexibility in design,</strong> ensuring that it can be used effectively in a multitude of contexts, from web design to branding and print materials.</p>



<p>Poppins&#8217; appeal lies in its modern and approachable design, legibility, and versatility. <strong>It&#8217;s a typeface that seamlessly blends contemporary aesthetics with readability.</strong></p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Why is this typeface on my list?</h4>



<p>I picked Poppins as an <strong>alternative to Futura, which I don’t like.</strong> To me Poppins is Futura with a more refined letterform design, it’s<strong> slightly more geometric</strong> but it <strong>shares the key qualities of Futura.</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Fira Sans</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="500" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/firasans.png" alt="" class="wp-image-196" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/firasans.png 1000w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/firasans-300x150.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/firasans-768x384.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure>



<p>Initially designed as a <strong>commission from Firefox to Edenspiekermann </strong>Fira Sans is a modern and adaptable sans-serif typeface designed by <strong>Erik Spiekermann and Ralph du Carrois.</strong> It was crafted taking as a base the well-known iconic <strong>FF Meta </strong>to provide a highly legible and functional option, making it a versatile choice for a variety of design projects.</p>



<p>One of the key strengths of Fira Sans is its <strong>exceptional legibility.</strong> The letterforms are<strong> clean, balanced, and well-proportioned,</strong> ensuring easy readability, which is crucial for body text, headings, and user interfaces. This makes Fira Sans an excellent choice for content across various mediums.</p>



<p>Fira Sans offers an extensive range of weights and styles, including regular, italic, bold, and condensed versions. This wide variety of options allows designers to tailor their typographic choices to fit the specific requirements of a project,<strong> from web design to branding and editorial layouts.</strong></p>



<p>Fira Sans&#8217;s appeal lies in its modern design, exceptional legibility, extensive weights and styles, and open-source availability.<strong> It is a versatile and reliable typeface</strong> that works well in a wide array of design applications.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Why is this typeface on my list?</h4>



<p>I really like Fira Sans, it’s one of my favorite typefaces and I still cannot believe it’s free and open-source. Designed by one of my favorite designers it’s a <strong>humanistic sans-serif typeface that fits the list really well, </strong>it’s one of the key elements I believe <strong>Vignelli’s list lacks.</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Switzer</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="500" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/switzer.png" alt="" class="wp-image-195" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/switzer.png 1000w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/switzer-300x150.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/switzer-768x384.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure>



<p>Inspired by<strong> neo-grotesk Swiss typefaces </strong>Switzer is a typeface designed by Indian Type Foundry. This modern interpretation translated to a modern geometric sans-serif that is very legible.</p>



<p>Like Fira Sans and Poppins, the key strength is its <strong>exceptional legibility and simplicity. </strong>The letterforms although geometric have a lot of character. <strong>Balanced, clean, and very straightforward </strong>Switzer is an <strong>essential typeface.</strong></p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Why is this typeface on my list?</h4>



<p>In my opinion, this typeface solves the main issues I and many designers have with Helvetica, <strong>it has character but it still shares the key qualities of Helvetica.</strong> It’s a workhorse of a typeface completely free which is also incredible.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">So, this was my list, with these 6 typefaces I believe most designers will have their needs covered. Compared to Vignelli’s list it actually is fairly similar although I’ve replaced one of the serifs for a humanistic sans-serif typeface which in my opinion, and for my work, was the missing ingredient!</h2>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What makes this list good?</h2>



<p><strong>Versatility</strong> was the key aspect when I was making this list, I wanted three serifs and three sans-serifs that <strong>were versatile but that at the same time covered the several aspects that make each category unique. </strong>When looking to<strong> Vignelli’s </strong>list and mine you can clearly see what I mean, both lists follow the same thought process.</p>



<p>I wanted to also include the most amount of <strong>variable and web-ready typefaces </strong>as I believe this type of technology is the future.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Why have I chosen only free typefaces?</h2>



<p>Mainly because they are<strong> widely available and easier to integrate, </strong>but also because <strong>I don’t like the fact that I have to pay thousands for Helvetica when better, free typefaces are available. </strong>I don’t like the types of prices most foundries ask for a single individual font, as a student it bothered me.<strong> I’m really glad we live in a time and age where free typefaces are a lot of the times good or better than paid ones.</strong></p>



<p>In the future, I hope projects like <strong>Google Fonts </strong>or <strong>Adobe Fonts </strong>continue to make proper efforts to support type designers and provide great typefaces for free. I will also always support foundries that make great typefaces open-source, free, or adequately priced. <strong>You’re awesome!</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">On a final note, let me remind you that mine or Vignelli’s list are just a basis, you can and should always expand on it and search for better alternatives.</h2>



<p>Even if you look at Vignelli’s work you will see other typefaces, for example, the Ducati logo he designed uses Univers. So<strong> be open to new horizons and support type designers and small foundries</strong> whenever you can!</p>



<p>Thank you for reading, as per usual I would love to read your opinion.</p>



<p>You can read the last article <a href="/5-must-have-items-every-designer-needs-in-their-toolkit/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/these-are-the-only-6-typefaces-you-need/">These are the only 6 typefaces you need</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Hugo&#039;s Notes</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/these-are-the-only-6-typefaces-you-need/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- plugin=object-cache-pro client=phpredis metric#hits=562 metric#misses=17 metric#hit-ratio=97.1 metric#bytes=277264 metric#prefetches=0 metric#store-reads=46 metric#store-writes=3 metric#store-hits=52 metric#store-misses=11 metric#sql-queries=10 metric#ms-total=81.81 metric#ms-cache=6.16 metric#ms-cache-avg=0.1283 metric#ms-cache-ratio=7.5 -->
